<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><xml><records><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210746</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Climate intervention: Carbon dioxide removal and reliable sequestration</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The signals are everywhere that our planet is experiencing significant climate change. It is clear that we need to reduce the emissions of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from our atmosphere if we want to avoid greatly increased risk of damage from climate change. Aggressively pursuing a program of emissions abatement or mitigation will show results over a timescale of many decades. How do we actively remove carbon dioxide from the atmosphere to make a bigger difference more quickly? As one of a two-book report, this volume of Climate Intervention discusses CDR, the carbon dioxide removal of greenhouse gas emissions from the atmosphere and sequestration of it in perpetuity. Climate Intervention: Carbon Dioxide Removal and Reliable Sequestration introduces possible CDR approaches and then discusses them in depth. Land management practices, such as low-till agriculture, reforestation and afforestation, ocean iron fertilization, and land-and-ocean-based accelerated weathering, could amplify the rates of processes that are already occurring as part of the natural carbon cycle. Other CDR approaches, such as bioenergy with carbon capture and sequestration, direct air capture and sequestration, and traditional carbon capture and sequestration, seek to capture CO2 from the atmosphere and dispose of it by pumping it underground at high pressure. This book looks at the pros and cons of these options and estimates possible rates of removal and total amounts that might be removed via these methods. With whatever portfolio of technologies the transition is achieved, eliminating the carbon dioxide emissions from the global energy and transportation systems will pose an enormous technical, economic, and social challenge that will likely take decades of concerted effort to achieve. Climate Intervention: Carbon Dioxide Removal and Reliable Sequestration will help to better understand the potential cost and performance of CDR strategies to inform debate and decision making as we work to stabilize and reduce atmospheric concentrations of carbon dioxide. © 2015 by the National Academy of Sciences. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.17226/18805</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210780</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Carbon capture via accelerated weathering of limestone: Modeling local impacts on the carbonate chemistry of the southern North Sea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Human activities are responsible for a > 45 \% rise of atmospheric CO2 since the industrial revolution started; burning of fossil fuels being the largest source. Via accelerated weathering of limestone (AWL), CO2 can be captured from effluent gas streams and stored in the marine environment primarily in the form of bicarbonate. We studied the CO2 storage capacity and how AWL-derived water impacts the carbonate chemistry of the southern North Sea. Therefor, a three-dimensional hydrodynamic model was coupled with a sub-module to model the carbonate chemistry. We studied three scenarios: 1) scrubbing effluent gas streams of a combined heat and power plant (60 kW), 2) scrubbing 10 \% or 3) 100 \% of the flue gas of a coal-fired power plant (750 MW). Whereas, impacts on seawater carbonate chemistry due to AWL discharge were imperceptible in the first scenario, a maximum change in pH(T) and calcite saturation state of 0.1 and 0.6 was found in scenario 2. In scenario 3, the decrease in pH(T) exceeded 1 around the discharge site and the calcite saturation state reached 8 in large parts of the Jade Bay, posing the possibility of significant impacts on the marine ecosystem. Abiotic precipitation of calcite might occur around the discharge site. In all three scenarios, 50 \% of the captured CO2 re-entered the atmosphere after the simulated time period of one year. This study shows that care is needed in siting, sizing and operating AWL facilities to maximize climate and ocean ecosystem benefits while minimizing negative environmental impacts.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijggc.2019.102855</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210883</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mitigating the atmospheric CO2 increase and ocean acidification by adding limestone powder to upwelling regions</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The feasibility of enhancing the absorption of CO2 from the atmosphere by adding calcium carbonate (CaCO3) powder to the ocean and of partially reversing the acidification of the ocean and the decrease in calcite supersaturation resulting from the absorption of anthropogenic CO2 is investigated. CaCO3 could be added to the surface layer in regions where the depth of the boundary between supersaturated and unsaturated water is relatively shallow (250-500 m) and where the upwelling velocity is large (30-300 m a(-1)). The CaCO3 would dissolve within a few 100 m depth below the saturation horizon, and the dissolution products would enter the mixed layer within a few years to decades, facilitating further absorption of CO2 from the atmosphere. This absorption of CO2 would largely offset the increase in mixed layer pH and carbonate supersaturation resulting from the upwelling of dissolved limestone powder. However, if done on a large scale, the reduction in atmospheric CO2 due to absorption of CO2 by the ocean would reduce the amount of CO2 that needs to be absorbed by the mixed layer, thereby allowing a larger net increase in pH and in supersaturation in the regions receiving CaCO3. At the same time, the reduction in atmospheric pCO(2) would cause outgassing of CO2 from ocean regions not subject to addition of CaCO3, thereby increasing the pH and supersaturation in these regions as well. Geographically optimal application of 4 billion t of CaCO3 a(-1) (0.48 Gt C a(-1)) could induce absorption of atmospheric CO2 at a rate of 600 Mt CO2 a(-1) after 50 years, 900 Mt CO2 a(-1) after 100 years, and 1050 Mt CO2 a(-1) after 200 years.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1029/2007JC004373</style></electronic-resource-num></record></records></xml>