<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><xml><records><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210399</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Effect of Ocean Iron Fertilization on the Phytoplankton Biological Carbon Pump</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">It has been proposed that photosynthetic plankton can be used as a biological carbon pump tp absorb and sequester carbon dioxide in the ocean. In this paper, plankton population dynamics are simulated in a single stratified water column to predict carbon dioxide sequestering due to surface iron fertilization in deep ocean. Using a predator-prey model and realistic parameter values, iron fertilization was found to only cause temporary blooms up to 5 months in duration, and relatively small increases in adsorption of atmospheric CO(2).</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.4208/aamm.10-m1023</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210475</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Iron-Marine Algal Interactions and Impacts: Decreasing Global Warming by Increasing Algal Biomass</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Iron limitation in vast water bodies has been linked to decreased algal productivity, despite different iron-acquiring mechanisms, and the presence of ferritin in many algal species that act as an iron internal reservoir. Therefore, iron fertilization has been proposed to increase algal biomass and photosynthesis. This, in turn, will reduce carbon dioxide in the atmosphere and increase oxygen, thereby decreasing global warming, and achieving ecological balance. In addition, algal proliferation will hopefully lead to enhancement in biodiversity, Biological pump, fish productivity and, subsequently marine food industry. Many climate geoengineering experiments in the form of ocean iron fertilization have been conducted globally in order to achieve such a purpose. However, reservations remain as the outcomes are not as promising as were previously expected. As the temporal and spatial scales of iron fertilization experiments are limited, the effects on fish productivity remain speculative. On the other hand, side effects were also recorded. The main purpose of iron fertilization, for carbon dioxide sequestration and global warming mitigation, still remains to be fully realized and verified. Several improvements and future modifications are suggested, and legal issues are discussed in this review.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/su141610372</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210746</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Climate intervention: Carbon dioxide removal and reliable sequestration</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The signals are everywhere that our planet is experiencing significant climate change. It is clear that we need to reduce the emissions of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from our atmosphere if we want to avoid greatly increased risk of damage from climate change. Aggressively pursuing a program of emissions abatement or mitigation will show results over a timescale of many decades. How do we actively remove carbon dioxide from the atmosphere to make a bigger difference more quickly? As one of a two-book report, this volume of Climate Intervention discusses CDR, the carbon dioxide removal of greenhouse gas emissions from the atmosphere and sequestration of it in perpetuity. Climate Intervention: Carbon Dioxide Removal and Reliable Sequestration introduces possible CDR approaches and then discusses them in depth. Land management practices, such as low-till agriculture, reforestation and afforestation, ocean iron fertilization, and land-and-ocean-based accelerated weathering, could amplify the rates of processes that are already occurring as part of the natural carbon cycle. Other CDR approaches, such as bioenergy with carbon capture and sequestration, direct air capture and sequestration, and traditional carbon capture and sequestration, seek to capture CO2 from the atmosphere and dispose of it by pumping it underground at high pressure. This book looks at the pros and cons of these options and estimates possible rates of removal and total amounts that might be removed via these methods. With whatever portfolio of technologies the transition is achieved, eliminating the carbon dioxide emissions from the global energy and transportation systems will pose an enormous technical, economic, and social challenge that will likely take decades of concerted effort to achieve. Climate Intervention: Carbon Dioxide Removal and Reliable Sequestration will help to better understand the potential cost and performance of CDR strategies to inform debate and decision making as we work to stabilize and reduce atmospheric concentrations of carbon dioxide. © 2015 by the National Academy of Sciences. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.17226/18805</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210804</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Migration and transformation of marine carbon and related chemical driving factors</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The study showed that the migration and transformation of marine carbon had a close relation with the biogeochemical processes driven by various chemical factors. The growth and decline of nutrient concentration, pH, dissolved oxygen (DO), redox potential (Eh), SO4 2-, and sulfur potential (Es) could change marine chemical environment, and thus, affect the migration and transformation of marine carbon. When the nutrient supply was adequate to the nutritional demand of phytoplankton, CO2 was conveyed to deep sea through photosynthesis and organic matter oxidation, which caused the decrease of sea water PCO2 and the increase of sea-air CO2 flux and organic carbon output, making the sea area as a CO2 sink. But, the increasing acidification of marine environment caused by CO2 dissolution and organic matter degradation brought about the solubility augmentation of carbonate in seawater. Moreover, the mineralization of organic carbon was coupled with the changes of DO, Eh, SO42- and Es, and the deposition and burial process of carbon in sediments. In sea water body, high DO and high Eh accelerated the transformation from inorganic carbon to organic carbon, while in sediment, high SO42- was adverse to the burial of organism with low DO and low Eh.</style></abstract><urls/></record></records></xml>