<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><xml><records><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210099</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The intra-annual variability in the performance of wave energy converters: A comparative study in N Galicia (Spain)</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents the analysis of the intra-annual power performance of different WECs (wave energy converters) at two locations of interest in the northern coastal region of Galicia (NW Spain). With this aim, the wave resource at the locations of interest is characterised by considering a procedure whose implementation on a coastal region produces the required wave spectral information for reconstructing the coastal resource in terms of monthly characterisation matrices with the adequate resolution for conducting accurate performance computations of WECs. Next, the monthly performance of different WECs at these locations is estimated through the combination of the characterisation matrices obtained and the efficiency of the technologies analysed. The results show that the analysis of the intra-annual performance of different technologies at different locations is a key aspect so as to define the most appropriate WEC-site combination for harnessing the wave energy resource in a coastal region. Finally, the information produced by implementing the methodology considered in this work allows the reconstruction of the wave resource at any coastal site (not only at the selected locations), in the form of monthly high resolution characterisation matrices, and thus, the monthly performance of any WEC-site combination can be computed. Â© 2015 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.energy.2015.01.020</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210113</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Experimental investigation of mooring configurations for wave energy converters</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mooring systems are required to keep floating wave energy converters (WECs) on station. The mooring concept might impact the performance of the WEC, its cost and its integrity. With the aim of clarifying the pros and cons of different mooring designs, we present the results from physical model experiments of three different mooring concepts in regular and irregular waves, including operational and survival conditions. The parameters investigated are the tension in the cables, the motions of the device in the different degrees of freedom and the seabed footprint in each case. We can see that the mooring system affects the performance of the wave energy converter, but the magnitude of the impact depends on the parameter analysed, on the mode of motion studied and on the conditions of the sea. Moreover, different configurations have similar performances in some situations and the choice of one over another might come down to factors such as the type of soil of the seabed, the spacing desired between devices, or environmental impacts. The results of our experiments provide information for a better selection of the mooring system for a wave energy converter when several constraints are taken into account (power production, maximum displacements, extreme tensions, etc). Â© 2016 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijome.2016.04.009</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210127</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A Novel Configuration of a Hybrid Offshore Wind-Wave Energy Conversion System and Its Controls for a Remote Area Power Supply</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This article aims to develop a novel hybrid offshore wind-wave energy conversion system (HOW-WECS) configuration which can successfully feed a stable power to the customers of remote communities in near-shore areas or remote islands. The proposed configuration uses a minimum number of converters for the integration of the doubly-fed induction generator (DFIG) based wind energy system with the direct-drive linear permanent magnet generator (DDLPMG) based wave energy system. Advanced control schemes for the DFIG and the DDLPMG are presented to enhance the power extraction from the implemented HOW-WECS. The dynamic and the transient performance of the proposed system and the associated control schemes are tested under various operating scenarios and electrical fault conditions. The dynamic performance was acceptable as the implemented control strategies were able to keep the stator voltage and the stator current of the DFIG sinusoidal and balanced, the frequency excursions are within the acceptable band, and the common ac-bus voltage of the distribution network stable under all operating scenarios. The results prove the effectiveness of the proposed system under transient conditions and the ability of the proposed HOW-WECS to recover quickly to gain its pre-fault conditions once the fault was cleared.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TIA.2022.3197099</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210128</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Research on an All-Flow Velocity Control Strategy for a 120 kW Variable-Pitch Horizontal Axis Tidal Current Turbine</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Horizontal-axis tidal current turbines have considerable potential to harvest renewable energy from ocean tides. The pitch control system is a critical part of variable-pitch tidal turbines. Existing control strategies for tidal turbines mainly rely on flow measurement devices to obtain tidal velocities, which are costly and subject to many limitations in practical applications, making them unsuitable for small off-grid tidal turbines. In this paper, we propose a pitch control strategy for a 120 kW horizontal-axis tidal current turbine based on the output power of the generator. The torque of the turbine was calculated based on the blade element momentum theory, and a dynamic model of the tidal turbine was established. The dynamic characteristics of the turbine and generator were studied under various flow rates and pitch angles. On the basis of the characteristic analysis, the generating efficiency of the unit was improved under a low flow rate, and the output power was limited to a rated value under high-current velocity by regulating the pitch angle. Furthermore, a novel protection and start up strategy is proposed to protect the unit and make full use of the tidal energy when the tidal current velocity exceeds the limit value. We performed simulations, the obtained results of which demonstrate the effectiveness and advantages of the designed control strategies.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/jmse10111578</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210132</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modelling a Tidal Turbine in Unsteady Flow</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A brief review of the literature is provided on the characteristics of marine currents and the approaches used for simulating tidal turbines. The feasibility of using CFD models to simulate time-dependent turbulent flow around a tidal turbine is then explored. Two different approaches for specifying the structure of the turbulent inflow conditions in CFD models are compared: the von Karman spectral approach and the Synthetic Eddy Method (SEM) of Jarrin et al. (2006). The former model is commonly employed in the wind industry and is coded into Garrad Hassan's Tidal Bladed and NREL's TurbSim. Different approaches are also tested for decomposing the turbulence at the inlet into resolved and modelled components. The results from these tests indicate that the turbulence produced using the SEM inlet conditions is slightly less susceptible to decay with downstream distance than the von Karman approach provided that the modelled turbulent kinetic energy accounts for only a small fraction of the total turbulence energy. Simulations of the unsteady flow around a tidal turbine, represented here as a simple porous disc, provide some insight into the effect of large-scale flow oscillations on the wake of the turbine. The wake structures obtained from unsteady CFD simulations are compared to those obtained using a steady approach. The results indicate that the presence of large coherent turbulent structures in the incident flow field produces a shorter wake than predicted by steady flow simulations. This work represents the first stage in the development of a unified model which will couple meta-scale simulations of flow in an estuary or complete channel to detailed small-scale simulations of the flow around tidal turbine devices.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210136</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The investigation of a segment multi-chamber oscillating water column in physical scale model</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave Energy Converters (WECs) are being developed as a viable green energy solution to meet power needs for coastal communities. This paper presents the initial work on a fixed multi-chamber OWC (MCOWC) concept. The paper reports theoretical and experimental modeling. It begins with initial tests to verify the simple idealized model of a fixed OWC multi-chamber concept. These take place under small-amplitude regular-wave wave tank conditions. The analysis is carried through to assess the effect of the Capture Width (Hydrodynamic efficiency). Experimental data is put forward from the mounting of level sensors and anemometers to test the hydrodynamic performance of a fixed MCOWC at different wave periods. The orifice effects of the chamber on the relative amplitudes of the inner free water surface and air flow rate in the duct are investigated. The experimental results will be used as real case data in order to optimize the orifice area and to maximize the chamber power according to the air flow velocity above the water surface inside the chambers. Â© 2016 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/ICRERA.2016.7884534</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210155</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Hybrid Triboelectric-Electromagnetic Nanogenerator with a Double-Sided Fluff and Double Halbach Array for Wave Energy Harvesting</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Harvesting wave energy is challenging due to the waves' direction, randomization, and ultra-low vibration frequency limitations. Here, a double-sided fluff and double Halbach array structured hybrid triboelectric-electromagnetic nanogenerator (FH-HG) for harvesting ultra-low frequency wave energy is reported. The double-sided fluff fabricates three triboelectric nanogenerators (TENGs), which significantly enhance space utilization and volume power density. Meanwhile, the double Halbach array electromagnetic generator (H-EMG) provides the optimum counterweight in the double-sided fluff TENG (F-TENG) and transforms the mechanical energy into electrical energy. The optimal linkages of TENGs and EMGs are both specified as parallel, according to a series of theoretical analyses and experimental comparisons. As the result, the maximum volume power density of F-TENG and H-EMG is achieved at 2.02 and 16.96 W m(-3), respectively. The design of the double-sided fluff and the double Halbach array ensures the device's superior output at low frequencies while also increasing its endurance. Furthermore, the outputs of the FH-HG can power some small electronic devices and the Bluetooth transmission system to achieve the purpose of real time marine environmental monitoring. Overall, benefiting from the excellent structural design and distinctive operational mechanism, the FH-HG provides a remarkable candidate for harvesting wave energy on a large scale.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/adfm.202205011</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210156</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Analytical estimates of the energy yield potential from the Alderney Race (Channel Islands) using marine current energy converters</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Energy from marine currents offers the promise of regular and predictable electrical generation at higher power densities than other renewables. The marine current resource is potentially large but mainly concentrated in a number of sites around the world. The power density for a horizontal axis turbine operating in such currents has a similar form to that of a wind turbine and is dependent on the cube of the velocity and the fluid density which for water is about 1000 times that of air. These two factors imply that the power density for marine current energy converters will be appreciably higher than that of wind generators resulting in smaller and hence more manageable size turbines. In the UK, for example, tidal races which exist in the waters around the Channel Islands and the 'Sounds' off the Scottish west coast are well known. The energy density at such sites is high due land mass constrictions which result in large current velocities at depths which are suitable for the installation of multiple arrays of turbines. This study was undertaken for the purpose of quantifying the potential of generating electricity from the Alderney Race in the Channel Islands. The work quantifies the resource, identifies fluid currents that could be used for the establishment of various size arrays in the race and constructs some logical course of action and direction for the installation of marine current turbines in arrays in the Race. The analytically predicted results for the selected site of the Alderney race showed that such installations can realise energy yields in excess of 7.4 TWh which is equivalent to 2% of the UK requirements for the year 2000. However, despite the totally predictable resource the energy yield of the site followed an uneven power production which could be used in a planned mixed power production structure. The analysis, although based on data from Admiralty Charts, has shown that there is a large potential for energy generation from such sites. Furthermore, and by virtue of the topography of the site, it is feasible to envisage a modular approach to the installation of size-dependent marine energy conversion devices or turbines to be deployed in phases taking into account technology progression and developments. Â© 2004 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2004.02.013</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210162</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">ON THE TIDAL STREAM RESOURCE OF TWO HEADLAND SITES IN THE ENGLISH CHANNEL: PORTLAND BILL AND ISLE OF WIGHT</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">There are various candidate sites for tidal stream energy extraction in the English Channel. In this paper we examine the tidal stream resource at Portland Bill and the south coast of the Isle of Wight. A depth-averaged numerical model is developed and compared to field measurements. The presence of rows of tidal turbines is simulated using a line-discontinuity to represent the head loss across the turbines. The head loss is given by linear momentum actuator disc theory. At each site the length of the turbine rows, the local blockage ratio, and the location of the turbines are varied. For Portland Bill the presence of an array with multiple rows of turbines is also considered. We find that it is likely that (based purely on the hydrodynamics) power could viably be extracted at each site, with the mean power produced by each site being in the order of 10s MW</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210163</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Application of a new OpenFOAM tool to design a pilot floating wind farm offshore mazara del vallo (Italy)</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A new Computational Fluid Dynamic tool, based on OpenFOAM, was implemented to reproduce a physical wave tank for offshore applications. The code has new boundary conditions for deep water wave generation, a new turbulent model and a new numerical restraint to represent realistic mooring lines in OpenFOAM. A real study case application of this tool is shown hereby: a preliminary analysis of a floating wind turbine offshore Mazara del Vallo, (Italy). The application demonstrated the usefulness and capability of the model. Moreover, with active absorption, the dimension of the numerical domain, computational costs and time of the simulations are reduced. Copyright Â© 2018 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE)</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210166</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">ANALYSIS OF WAVE ENERGY CONVERSION PROCESS</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Since wave energy conversion technologies are developing due to the depletion of fossil fuels and due to their hazardous effects on the environment, an important and unexploited source of energy is wave energy. The paper proposes to compare theoretical data obtained using specialized software and data obtained via laboratory measurements using a scale model, regarding the mechanical torque generated at the axis of the electric motor. The data collected represent the kinetic and potential energy, simulating Black Sea waves using an installation proposed to be patented, an installation that converts off-shore wave energy.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210172</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Levelized Cost of Energy (LCOE) of wave energy using GIS based analysis: The case study of Portugal</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The main objective of this paper is to establish an economic modelling of wave energy through a Geographical Information System (GIS). Furthermore, this method has been tested for the particular case of the Portuguese coast. It determines the best sea areas to install wave energy converters in this region, using spatial analysis of the Levelized Cost of Energy (LCOE). Several economic parameters, as capital or O\&amp;M costs, have been considered. In addition, a sensitivity analysis has been performed by varying the discount rate in three different scenarios. Several types of physical restrictions have been taken into account: bathymetry, submarine electrical cables, seabed geology, environmental conditions, protected areas in terms of heritage, navigation areas, seismic fault lines, etc. Spatial operations have been carried out to complete the procedure, using Model Builder of GIS software. Results indicate the most suitable areas in economic terms in Portugal to install wave energy devices. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijepes.2014.09.022</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210180</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Power and thrust measurements of marine current turbines under various hydrodynamic flow conditions in a cavitation tunnel and a towing tank</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The results of cavitation tunnel and tank tests on an 800 mm diameter model of a marine current turbine (MCT) are presented. The tests were carried out in a 2.4 mÃ—1.2 m cavitation tunnel and the 60 m towing tank. Results for power and thrust coefficients are presented for a range of tip speed ratio and pitch settings for various conditions. The results of this investigation provided an insight into the operation of a singe turbine in straight or yawed flow, the effect on performance of changes in the tip immersion of the rotor, the interference between twin rotors and the likely areas of cavitation inception. In addition, the analysed results presented provide useful information for the hydrodynamic design of MCTs and detailed data for the validation of numerical models. Â© 2006 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2006.01.012</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210181</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave energy converter platform stabilisation and mooring load reduction through power take-off control</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mooring systems are a significant capital cost of a floating wave energy converter and their premature failure negatively impacts operational costs. Excessive peak loads and accumulated fatigue damage can lead to failure, so these factors are cost drivers in wave energy converter design. Here, the potential to reduce platform motion and mooring loads through modification of the power take-off (PTO) control are investigated. An approximate velocity tracking control strategy is implemented with a linear quadratic regulator design method using differential weighting of system states. It is demonstrated that the controller can be tuned to capture similar mean power to an optimally tuned, passively damped system while significantly reducing mooring line cyclic loading. The relative accumulated fatigue damage in the mooring lines in a high energy sea-state is found to be reduced by between 43% and 92% as a result of using the approximate velocity tracking control strategy. Â© 2021 The Authors. IET Renewable Power Generation published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Institution of Engineering and Technology</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/rpg2.12242</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210186</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An alongshore wave energy power generation device and its numerical calculation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Described was an alongshore wave energy power generation device, of which the special dual-channel structure could convert the flow of sea water in dual directions into the rotation of the impeller in a single direction. A two-dimensional numerical calculation of the structure of the dual-channel was performed by utilizing the MRF (moving reference frame) model in the software Fluent 6.3. The velocity and pressure distribution of the fluid inside the channel were analyzed when the number of blades was 4 and the fluid turned various angles. The water flow rate through the power generation equipment item and its output power were also studied. Furthermore, the influence of the angle that the blades on the impeller turn on the utilization efficiency of the wave energy was investigated. The calculation results show that when the turning angle of the impeller is relatively small, the pressure difference between any two zones of the impeller is conspicuous, thus the flow rate passing through the equipment item is relatively small. With an increase of the turning angle of the impeller, the pressure difference between any two zones of the impeller will first decrease and then increase. Corresponding with this, the flow rate passing through and the output power of the equipment item will first increase and then decrease gradually.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210197</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Operations and maintenance issues in the offshore wind energy sector An explorative study</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Purpose - There is increasing research interest in the expansion of the offshore wind energy sector. Recent research shows that operations and maintenance (O\&amp;M) account for around 20-35 per cent of the total energy costs in this sector. The purpose of this paper is to provide an overview of O\&amp;M issues in the offshore wind energy sector to propose initiatives that can help reduce the cost of energy used by offshore wind farms. Design/methodology/approach - The paper is based on an in-depth literature review and a Delphi study of a panel of 16 experts on O\&amp;M. Findings - Consisting primarily of conceptual papers and/or modelling papers, the extant literature identifies several challenges for O\&amp;M in the offshore wind energy sector. These challenges can be grouped into four categories: issues related with industry immatureness; distance/water depth; weather window; and policy issues. The Delphi study identified three other major issues that lead to increased O\&amp;M costs: too many predefined rules that limit development; lack of coordinated planning of the different services offered at the wind farms; and lack of a common approach on how O\&amp;M should be managed strategically. Research limitations/implications - The present study is based only on Danish respondents. Future research needs to include various respondents from different countries to identify country-specific contingencies. Practical implications - The paper provides an overview of the O\&amp;M issues in the offshore wind energy sector to prioritize where future resources should be invested and, thus, reduce O\&amp;M costs. Originality/value - This is the first paper on O\&amp;M issues that bridges both literature studies and industry expert opinions.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1108/IJESM-04-2015-0012</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210202</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Development of a novel point absorber in heave for wave energy conversion</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents an advanced design methodology for electric power generation from the vast ocean wave energy. A novel single-buoy heaving device called wave energy converter (WEC) based on hydrostatic transmission (HST), or can be shortened as HSTWEC, is proposed to convert mechanical energy generated by ocean waves into electric energy. Modeling and simulations with both regular and irregular waves were then carried out to investigate working performances of the designed HSTWEC. The results showed that more than 78% of wave energy can be absorbed. In addition, an adaptive controller was designed to improve the performance of the suggested device. Effectiveness of the overall HSTWEC control system was finally proved by simulations. Â© 2013 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2013.08.028</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210208</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A climate-dependent sustainability index for wave energy resources in Northeast Asia</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this study, five decades of simulated wave climate in Northeast Asia were used to investigate the intra-annual variation and long-term change of wave energy potential. The results show that in general, the nearshore areas of the eastern Pacific side of Japan have the highest annual mean wave power while Japan and Taiwan function as natural barriers to prevent oceanic waves to propagate from the Pacific Ocean towards Korea and eastern China. The wave energy hotspots vary, seasonally mainly from the east of Japan during the spring to Ryukyu Islands and Taiwan during the autumn, with the highest values in nearshore areas reach around 40 kW/m in September. The results indicate that the intra-annual stability of wave energy resources is the lowest in the western coasts of Japan, whereas this area has contained the least change of wave energy during five decades. On the contrary, southern areas of Japan despite having higher monthly stability show the highest reduction of wave power in the long-term. Hence, a novel index was proposed and applied in nearshore areas in order to specify the most suitable areas for wave energy exploitation considering the sustainability of the resources in both short and long-term. Â© 2020 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.energy.2020.118466</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210214</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Status and potentials of tidal in-stream energy resources in the southern coasts of Iran: A case study</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Interest in renewable energy in Iran has increased continually over the past decade. Iran has an excellent hydro power energy resource and the use of this resource will assist in the development of a sustainable energy future. Iran - with its many narrow channels and significant tidal range - might be expected to have considerable potential for tidal current power generation. The Khowr-e Musa Bay is a large coastal embayment on the south-western coast of Iran in which the peak tidal currents exceed 2 m/s. It is therefore a promising site for tidal stream power. The assessment employed a statistical method, for estimating tidal current energy resource at the selected site, during one lunar month (since 6 November 1996 to 7 December 1996). With the introduction of constraints and limitations, the technical, practical, accessible and viable tidal current energy resources were obtained. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.rser.2012.08.010</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210221</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The influence of channel geometry on tidal energy extraction in estuaries</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A significant number of estuaries in the UK not only have a high tidal range but also exhibit strong tidal currents, where tidal farms could be used for energy extraction. The purpose of this study is to examine the influence that the geometry of the channel has on the impact of a tidal farm deployed in an estuary. A hydrodynamic model (Mike21) has been used to model several idealised estuaries with dimensions based on a group of locations suitable for tidal energy extraction in the UK. The maximum changes in low and high water levels with the tidal farm have been identified for each case and located within the estuary. The changes in the time for the low and high tides in a point inside the estuary have also been analysed. It is noted that the maximum changes in water levels due to the farm range from the order of mm to a few dm and the locations of these changes are strongly dependent on the geometry of each case. In addition, the effect is generally more noticeable in the increase of low water levels and the decrease of high water levels than vice-versa. This would be associated with the loss of intertidal areas and the reduction of flood risk levels. In terms of the changes in the time of low and high water levels, the effects of the farm are negligible in all cases. Â© 2016 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2016.09.009</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210225</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Efficiency properties of a wave energy converter placed in front of a vertical breakwater</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The present paper aims at investigating the efficiency properties of a cylindrical WEC placed in front of a vertical, surface piercing, breakwater of infinite length. A theoretical model is presented based on the linearized velocity potential, the image theory and the matched axisymmetric eigenfunction expansion formulations. The WECs under examination are the heaving absorber and the oscillating water column device. From the present analysis it is demonstrated that the absorbed wave power by the examined WECs in front of a vertical wall is strongly affected by the geometrical parameters of the converters and their mechanical components, and these should be considered when designing the WEC-breakwater system so as to increase its wave power efficiency. Â© 2021 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210241</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Optimal phasing of the European tidal stream resource using the greedy algorithm with penalty function</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The regular periodicity of astronomical tides allows their accurate prediction, and so it should be possible to determine how best to optimise the future distribution of arrays of tidal energy devices for any shelf sea region. By considering together the magnitude and phase of tidal currents over a shelf sea region, maximum aggregated power generation, with minimal periods of low generation, can be deduced. Here, we make use of the greedy algorithm to optimise future exploitation of the tidal stream resource over the northwest European shelf seas, a region which contains a world-leading tidal energy resource. We also apply a penalty function to the greedy algorithm, favouring the selection of future hypothetical sites where power generation would be out-of-phase with previously developed sites. Our results demonstrate that the Pentland Firth and Channel Islands would be optimal sites for parallel development for relatively low numbers of arrays, with important contributions from the Irish Sea for larger scale exploitation. Although there is minimal phase diversity between European tidal stream sites to deliver firm power generation, it is possible that tidal range could contribute to such baseload through the parallel development of lagoons or impoundments. Â© 2015 Taylor &amp; Francis Group, London.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1201/b18973-27</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210243</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical analysis and performance optimization of a submerged wave energy point absorber</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A submerged wave energy point absorber, TWED (Torres Wave Energy Device), has been studied under regular and irregular wave conditions. A partial non-linear time domain model of the TWED has been implemented in Simulink. The numerical model was exploited to test the sensibility of the TWED performance to changes in some variables under regular waves: generator damping constant, floater diameter, depth, frictions and drag coefficients. In this paper, the TWED was also optimized for maximum energy production under a real wave climate. To obtain the average wave performance of the converter, a 44 year series of data record has been employed. The objective functions have been the Average Absorbed Power (AAP) and the sea-state generator damping constant (K). After the optimization, AAP full time series have been obtained. Then several statistics analysis for AAP has been carried out for different time intervals; in order to study the variability of AAP. In addition, an evaluation of the TWED behaviour in a sea state in the Operation Limit has been studied. It has been found that the instantaneous absorbed power in a sea state could be as much as 20 times higher than the mean absorbed power. Â© 2012 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2012.10.016</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210245</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Study on the potential of oscillating water column-Ocean wave power plant in 3T (Underdeveloped, Frontmost, and Outermost) regions in Indonesia as a new renewable energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">As the largest archipelagic country globally, Indonesia holds great energy potential to be used as electric energy, one of which is ocean wave energy. Energy from ocean waves that never run out and can reach many remote islands, becomes the optimal option to be used as a power plant in supplying electricity in Indonesia's 3T (Underdeveloped, Frontmost, and Outermost). By utilizing the movement of waves in oscillating columns, ocean wave power plants-oscillating water column (PLTGL-OWC) become one of the simplest types of power plants, and easy to apply in various locations. This study aims to see the potential of the electric power generated by PLTGL-OWC. The data used is a hindcast of wave height, wavelength and the period from Badan Meteorologi, Klimatologi, dan Geofisika (BMKG) during 2013-2018. Electrical power is obtained after calculating the power of ocean waves and then multiplied by the efficiency of the OWC system in this study, which is 11.917% in units of kW. It was found that the condition of sea wave height in the 3T region in this study peaked in the JJA period when the Australian monsoon was active. The area with the tremendous potential for generating power is located in West Coast Regency, Lampung with an average electrical power of 25.85 kW per year, while the lowest power potential is in Nias Regency, which is 0.12 kW per year. Â© 2022 Author(s).</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1063/5.0106091</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210249</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A decision support model to optimise the operation and maintenance strategies of an offshore renewable energy farm</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In order to accelerate the access into the energy market for ocean renewables, the operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) costs for these technologies must be reduced. In this paper a reliability-based simulation tool for the optimization of the management of an offshore renewable energy (ORE) farm is presented. The proposed tool takes into account the reliability data of the simulated devices and estimations on the energy produced to create a series of results in terms of availability and maintainability of the farm. The information produced supports operational and strategic decision making regarding the O&amp;M for offshore farms. A case study simulating a conceptual tidal energy project, consisting of an array of two tidal turbines located off the north coast of Scotland, is presented to show some of the results achievable with this model. The proposed methodology, although adopted for a tidal farm here, is generally applicable to other kinds of ORE farms. Â© 2017 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2017.08.019</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210254</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Experimental Research of a New Wave Energy Conversion Device</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">With the increasing tension of contemporary social energy, the development and utilization of renewable energy has become an important development direction. As an important part of renewable energy, wave energy has the characteristics of green environmental protection and abundant reserves, attracting more investment and research. For small marine equipment energy supply problem, this paper puts forward a micro wave energy conversion device as the basic of heaving motion of waves in the ocean. This paper designed a new type of power output device can solve the micro wave energy conversion problem. Â© Published under licence by IOP Publishing Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1088/1755-1315/111/1/012008</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210259</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Sustainable co-generation from the tides: A review</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The article discusses the sustainable co-generation from the tides. The tide-generating forces encompass the gravitational pull of principally sun and moon and the rotational force of the earth. The gravitational attraction exerted by the moon upon the earth and an inertial effect are the primary causes of the tides.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/S1364-0321(02)00011-4</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210262</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Could environmental concerns kill of an environmentally friendly industry?</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Marine renewable energy attracts a depth of scrutiny from environmental regulators and statutory nature conservation bodies that more established marine industries have managed to escape. The marine energy industry has seen remarkable development since the first attempt in the UK to generate electricity from tidal stream power, by the lifelong exponent of renewable energy, Peter Fraenkel. SeaGen continues to operate in Strangford Narrows and to date has delivered more than 8GWh to the national grid. Several other tidal energy generators have been successfully tested at the European Marine Energy Center (EMEC) in Orkney, Scotland, including devices owned by OpenHydro, Ireland, Alstom, France, Scotrenewables, UK, Andritz Hydro Hammerfest, Norway, Atlantis Resources Corporation, Singapore, and Voith, Germany. The Marine Current Turbines, UK, development in Strangford Lough, which is an SAC for harbor seals, provides a concrete example of disproportionate costs.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210265</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">AC fault ride through of modular multilevel converter VSC-HVDC transmission systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper discusses the AC fault ride through of two terminal modular multilevel converter (MMC) VSC based HVDC integration of combined offshore wind and wave farms. The combined offshore wind and wave farms are modelled as a controllable three phase voltage source connected to a 600MVA, 460kV/370kV transformer. A 31- level MMC has been selected because of acceptable harmonic attributes. Two 300kV DC submarine cables with length of 100km have been employed in this study. A voltage source has been connected in series with an inductive resistive circuit to give a short circuit ratio of 3.5. This paper finally presents a comparative simulation analysis of hysteresis based and PI based DC voltage controller for fault ride through (FRT) capability. The analysis showed that the PI method resulted in smaller overshoots and dips. A high switching frequency PWM based electromagnetic transient (EMT) model in MATLAB/Simulink was developed for the analysis. Â© 2015 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/UPEC.2015.7339823</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210269</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Advantages of plate-type heat exchanger over tube-type heat exchanger for OTEC power plant</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The optimization for closed-cycle 100-MW Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion (OTEC) power plant was carried out between the plate-type heat exchanger and the double-fluted tube-type one using ammonia as the working fluid by the method of the steepest descent. The performance of both heat exchangers were compared. In terms of cost, the plate-type heat exchanger was found to be more desirable than the double-fluted tube-type for an OTEC application.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210271</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Measurement system for evaluating wanted and unwanted forces on a point absorbing wave energy converter during offshore operation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A force measurement system has been developed and installed in a wave energy converter at Uppsala University. The force in the connection line as well as the vertical and horizontal strain in the generator hull is measured. With these measurements the forces acting on the generator during offshore operation can be monitored and analyzed. This paper presented the principle, implementation and test results of the measurement system. A brief discussion of error sources and possible improvements is also given. Copyright Â© 2015 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210274</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">2nd International Conference on Renewable Energies Offshore, RENEW 2016</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The proceedings contain 103 papers. The special focus in this conference is on Renewable Energies Offshore. The topics include: Assessing the utility and effectiveness of the IEC standards for wave energy resource characterisation; wave energy potential assessment along the west coast of Fuerteventura; trends in the available wave power at the Portuguese pilot zone; development of a numerical modelling tool for combined near field and far field wave transformations using a coupling of potential flow solvers; assessing the importance of including waves in simulations of tidal stream turbine impacts; tidal energy resource characterisation in the Dover strait by using VHF radar and ADCP measurements; assessing climate change effect in offshore wind power in the north of Portugal; regional frequency analysis of wind speed on the coast of Portugal; a methodology for the power performance assessment of floating offshore wind turbines; application of reanalysis data for offshore wind power potential assessment off the west coast of India; development of an autonomous offshore monitoring system; evaluation of offshore wind power potential of India by combining satellite and moored buoy data; high resolution monitoring for marine renewable energy; additional attenuation detection and correction of radar wave within the interior region of offshore wind farm; energy capture optimization for an adaptive wave energy converter; systems engineering applied to the development of a wave energy farm and revenue optimization for the ocean grazer wave energy converter through storage utilization.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210275</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Optimizing power generation of a bottomraised oscillating surge wave energy converter using a theoretical model</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Preliminary sizing of an oscillating surge wave energy converter (OSWEC) is an iterative process that relies on knowledge of the relevant hydrodynamic coefficients for a given geometry. Often, the complex definition of the device geometry requires coefficients to be obtained through experiments or numerical boundary element solvers such as WAMIT. These techniques demand significant user and computational effort, therefore inhibiting the fine-scale parametrization of object dimensions. In this study, a theoretical model, originally presented in Michele et al. (2016), is developed and demonstrated to efficiently optimize the power production for an OSWEC device (subjected to certain environmental conditions) with variations in device widths, heights, and distances from the seabed. Assuming negligible device thickness, the OSWEC motions are modeled as a bottomraised two-dimensional flap in regular waves using potential flow theory formulated in elliptical coordinates. The solutions to this diffraction-radiation problem are obtained using Mathieu functions with appropriate boundary conditions. The resulting potentials are then used to derive frequency-dependent expressions for the added mass and radiation-damping coefficients, along with waveexcitation magnitude in surge, pitch, and coupled surgepitch motions. Good agreement in hydrodynamic coefficient curves is shown between the theoretical model and the numerical results obtained from the boundary element-based program WAMIT. The theoretical model is then employed to maximize the time-averaged output power while maintaining or reducing the hinge reaction force, with variations in device dimensions, wave frequency, and amplitude. Â© European Wave and Tidal Energy Conference 2021.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210280</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Socio-economic, legal, and political context of offshore renewable energies</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore renewable energies have been identified as important clean sources of energy in line with sustainable development goals. However, their use can generate conflicts with other maritime activities, as well as the protection of biodiversity and the marine environment. This article analyses the influence of regulatory frameworks and ocean governance in the implementation of such devices, from a legalâ€“political point of view. In this sense, it studies how the law of the sea addresses potential international conflicts between ocean energy installations and other activities (e.g., navigation) developed by other states. It also studies the importance of preventive legal toolsâ€”marine spatial planning, strategic environmental assessment, and environmental impact assessmentâ€”to anticipate and reduce clashes with other sea users as well as environmental damages that may be caused by these structures. Likewise, this research analyses different national consent procedures and legalâ€“economic supporting schemes, to identify those that boost the implementation of such projects more quickly. Finally, the relevance of enhancing the involvement of affected coastal communities and local stakeholders in the decision-making processes, as well as in the socio-economic benefits of offshore renewable energy projects to increase their social acceptance, is also emphasized. This article is categorized under: Policy and Economics > Governance and Regulation Policy and Economics > Energy Transitions Policy and Economics > Regional and International Strategies. Â© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/wene.462</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210283</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Laboratory Characterization of a Liquid Metal MHD Generator for Ocean Wave Energy Conversion</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Harnessing ocean wave energy is an old challenge that has gained momentum in recent years. In this paper, we present the flow and electrical characterization of a prototype of an alternate liquid metal magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) generator at a laboratory scale which has the potential to make use of the energy of marine waves for its conversion into electrical energy. The eutectic alloy Galinstan, used as a working fluid, was driven in oscillatory motion in a duct of a rectangular cross-section exposed to a transverse magnetic field generated by permanent neodymium magnets. The electric current induced by the motion of the liquid metal in the magnetic field was collected through copper electrodes and delivered to the load. The oscillatory axial velocity component along the duct was measured using ultrasonic Doppler velocimetry for different oscillation frequencies. In turn, the output currents and voltages were measured for different operation conditions and the electric power and efficiency were estimated from experimental measurements. The coupling of this generator to a wave energy converter (WEC) is discussed.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/su13094641</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210288</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Analysis of a single point tensioned mooring system for station keeping of a contra-rotating marine current turbine</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Energy Systems Research Unit within the Department of Mechanical Engineering at the University of Strathclyde has developed a novel contra-rotating tidal turbine (CoRMaT). Novel aspects of this turbine include two contra-rotating sets of rotor blades directly driving an open-to-sea permanent magnet generator (PMG). The balancing of reactive forces by the use of contra-rotation enables the use of a single-point compliant mooring system for station keeping. A series of tank and sea tests have led to the deployment and demonstration of a small stand-alone next generation tidal turbine. The stability of a single-point mooring system is examined and power quality from the direct drive generator is evaluated. It is noted that good stability from a single-point mooring can be achieved within a real tidal stream; however from sea testing of the turbine off the west coast of Scotland in the Sound of Islay, it is shown that some instabilities in device station keeping may have an effect on the output electrical power quality. Finally, the scaling up of the power take-off and delivery options for a 250 kW production prototype are described and assessed. It was concluded that the most promising option was an enlarged version of the system already tested, namely a direct-drive contra-rotating PMG. Â© 2010 Â© The Institution of Engineering and Technology.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/iet-rpg.2009.0209</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210289</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design of compensation battery for tidal power-photovoltaics-SOFC microgrids in Ternate and Pulau-Tidore Islands</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Solid oxide fuel cell (SOFC) can supply backup power for a remote island microgrid that generates power from tidal energy, photovoltaics (PV), and wind turbines. Since SOFCs need high temperature operation, though, the possible output adjustments are relatively slow. Therefore, SOFC with renewable energy requires the electricity compensation by a storage battery. This paper reports the analysis results using MATLAB/Simulink 2016b simulations of a microgrid with tidal energy, photovoltaics, and SOFC generators. The dynamic characteristics of the modeled SOFC are estimated from experimental tests of a product in Japan, and the suitable battery capacity for such a microgrid is determined. Furthermore, proposed system stores surplus electricity using a hydrogen energy carrier, energy supply can be carried out only in renewable energy. The remote tropical islands of Ternate and Pulau-Tidore served as a case study area for the proposed microgrid. Proposed microgrid for a remote island was modeled using MATLAB/Simulink 2016b. The simulations clarified the suitable combination of tidal power generation, PV, and SOFC capacity assuming a maximum load. The required capacity of a Li-ion storage battery in the example case of Indonesia's remote Ternate and Pulau-Tidore Island needs to be 3.2% of the maximum hourly load if the maximum load on the microgrid is 1200 kW. Â© 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/er.5904</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210301</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design by optimization and flume test of ducted horizontal axis marine current turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this study, an optimization method which couples a Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) method and lifting line model interaction method is presented, and applied to design, for highest power output, horizontal axis marine current turbines in uniform inflow for different duct shapes. The flow around duct is solved by the RANS method, where the turbine blades are represented by a pressure drop as a function of radius, based on the lifting line model. An automated tool is developed to generate high-quality meshes for given duct shape and domain size. The present method is first applied to design unbounded ducted turbines and the effect of duct shapes (angle of attack, camber, chord length and thickness) on the power coefficient is studied. Then, ducted turbines placed in a cylindrical channel are designed by this method, built by a 3D printer and tested in a water flume. Â© 2019 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210312</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical Simulation of Wave Flow Over the Overtopping Breakwater for Energy Conversion (OBREC) Device</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A number of Wave Energy Converters (WEC) have been proposed by many researchers, but most of them are not economically competitive as a contender in the energy market. This article intends to contribute to the development of very viable concept, which called as Overtopping Breakwater for Energy Conversion (OBREC) aims to fully utilize traditional breakwaters and capturing wave energy. The OBREC and its concept have been physically modeled and tested in Aalborg University since 2012 until 2014 and showed the promising results. In present work, the most-recent CFD of FLOW 3D technology is used to provide a more reliable approach in analyzing wave flow over the structure, in particular, OBREC device. Thus, the numerical simulations are carried out for validating overtopping discharge performance from the previous experimental and prediction methods. The result shows a good agreement with the experimental data. Hence, FLOW 3D is highly capable in handling coastal issues, especially for evaluating overtopping wave parameters. (C) 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/). Peer-review under responsibility of the organizing committee of the 10th International Conference on Marine Technology.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.proeng.2017.08.131</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210317</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Air turbines for wave energy conversion</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper describes the present status of the art on air turbines, which could be used for wave energy conversion. The air turbines included in the paper are as follows: Wells type turbines, impulse turbines, radial turbines, cross-flow turbine, and Savonius turbine. The overall performances of the turbines under irregular wave conditions, which typically occur in the sea, have been compared by numerical simulation and sea trial. As a result, under irregular wave conditions it is found that the running and starting characteristics of the impulse type turbines could be superior to those of the Wells turbine. Moreover, as the current challenge on turbine technology, the authors explain a twin-impulse turbine topology for wave energy conversion. Copyright Â© 2012 Manabu Takao and Toshiaki Setoguchi.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1155/2012/717398</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210334</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Performance evaluation and optimization of a hinged-typed wave energy converter</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents the numerical analysis and optimization of the wave energy converter, Sea Wave Energy Extraction Device (SeaWEED), which is considered an improved attenuator consisting of four modules connected by rigid truss structures. A potential-flow based frequency-domain program based on the Lagrange multiplier method was developed to simulate the hinged motions and predict the power take-off (PTO) of SeaWEED. The numerical method was validated using experimental data. Optimization studies were further carried out by considering various parameters, including damping coefficients of the PTO systems, lengths of truss structures and draft of the device. The uniform design method was used for sampling, and the response surface method was employed for surrogate construction. An optimal combination of parameters was determined for an intended operation site. Â© 2019 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210343</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Size optimization of new hybrid stand-alone renewable energy system considering a reliability index</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Over last two decades, solar and wind energies have become an alternative to traditional energy sources. These alternative energy sources are non-polluting, free in their availability and are renewable. Another alternative is tidal energy, which is related to falling and rising ocean water levels. Tidal behavior can be predicted easily and this means that if it is enabling to harness tidal energy, it can be produced power for specific periods of time. In this paper, a new hybrid combination of renewable energy sources is considered. The combination of wind, photovoltaic and tidal is taken into account as a primary and battery as an auxiliary source. The aim of design is to minimize the annualized cost of the generation system over its 20 years of operation. Determining the capacity of hybrid wind, photovoltaic, tidal and battery is formulated as an optimization problem. The objective function is the minimization of the cost with the constrain having specific reliability index. To evaluate the system reliability level, the Equivalent Loss Factor (ELF) has been used as an index. Comparison between hybrid wind, solar and battery and new combination of renewable energy is done and it is shown that the combination of wind, solar, tidal and battery is more economical. Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) is used for optimal sizing the system. Simulation results are carried out by MATLAB software. It is shown that hybrid system is the best configuration that has minimum cost and can satisfy all constrains. Â© 2012 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/EEEIC.2012.6221521</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210348</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Towards wave energy utilization for oil and gas assets and wave farms development: The adriatic sea demonstration case</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Among the renewable sources, the energy stored in waves is more concentrated than others such wind or solar energy sources. The wave energy sectors are at the cutting edge of engineering design and several technologies sound technical solutions, with positive steps towards commercial viability, however, the cost of energy projection is still too high to allow direct access to mass electricity market in the short term. Meanwhile, the extension of O&amp;G Companies presence in offshore and deep water frontier regions has been one of the main causes of the increasing interest in ocean wave energy in upstream operations. Consideration is directed to the increasing offshore power demand which triggers a challenge of maintain environmentally responsible operations while maximizing returns on O&amp;G production investment. Accelerated development of ocean energy technologies by O&amp;G offshore experience and investments could offer a wide range of long-term benefits, such as new routes to decarbonisation, creation of a new generation portfolio and potential economic opportunities for the development of wave farms and multi-megawatt projects. This paper aims at giving an overview of the first worldwide open water demonstration project of a wave energy converter connected to a refitted gas platform off the coast of Ravenna in Adriatic Sea, an open-sea facility to support research, technical testing and commercial demonstration of prototypes and offshore stand-alone renewable multi-source grid. It will address the deployment, the sea prototype testing and offshore power export of ISWEC, a Wave Energy Converter able to transform the wave-induced motion of a vessel into electrical power, by gyroscopic effects produced from a spinning flywheel carried inside it. Â© 2019 Offshore Mediterranean Conference (OMC). All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210371</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modelling the effect of large arrays of tidal turbines with depth-averaged Actuator Disks</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Actuator Disk concept is suitable to simulate the flow interactions between tidal turbines. As the computational expense of AD simulations is too large for applications at regional scale, the â€œbed frictionâ€&#x9d; method is generally preferred. It consists in applying an enhanced drag over the tidal farm area. The main drawback is that the flow around each turbine is not resolved and that the flow interactions between the turbinesâ€™ wakes are neglected. The extent to which this simplification affects the accuracy of the large scale flow is not well understood. Here, we propose a methodology for representing large arrays of tidal turbines in Shallow Water Equations solvers. It consists in representing individual turbines as small areas where a sink momentum term is applied. The sink term is calculated from the vertical integration of the force exerted on an AD. After validating the model, we apply the methodology to simulate the effect of 45 turbines placed in the Alderney Race. The results are compared to the results obtained with the â€œbed frictionâ€&#x9d; method. The two approaches give similar results because the hydrodynamics conditions of the Alderney Race favor the mixing of the wakes which prevents the flow interactions between the turbines. Â© 2016 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2016.09.021</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210380</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Evaluation of entropy generation methods in wells turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Entropy generation analyses have been applied, in recent years, to a variety of systems, including Wells turbines. This can be a very powerful method, as it can provide important insights into the irreversibilities of the system, as well as a methodology for identifying, and possibly minimizing, the main sources of loss. However, some of the simplifications used in recent studies raise more than a concern on the validity of the approach. This work proposes a method based on RANS equations to evaluate the en-tropy production in Wells turbines. An estimation of the second-law efficiency of different Wells turbine rotors is also presented, under conditions representative of the air flow inside an OWC device. The main sources of entropy generation are highlighted and compared for the different geometries. Â© 2019 American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME). All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210401</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Study on wake effect of horizontal axis marine current turbine based on single pile support structure [å&#x8d;•æ¡©ç»“æž„çš„æ½®æµ&#x81;èƒ½æ°´è½®æœºå°¾æµ&#x81;æµ&#x81;åœºåˆ†æž&#x90;]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In order to reduce the influence of the tidal current flow field on the unit spacing, the position of the turbine and the utilization of the marine space resources, the research is studied based on the numerical simulation and the tank test method. On this basis of the flow field of the turbine with a single pile support structure and different installation heights is analyzed. The results show that the numerical simulation is consistent with the results of the tank test. The structure of single pile has obvious influence on the wake flow field. The recovery law of the wake flow in different installation height is different. Â© 2019, Editorial Board of Acta Energiae Solaris Sinica. All right reserved.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210405</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">MARINE RENEWABLE ENERGY IN THE UNITED KINGDOM AND THE ROLE OF THE UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Serious research into wave energy in the UK started in the 1970s and, from the beginning, the University of Edinburgh has played a significant role. The UK is now in the process of developing a new marine renewable energy industry and full scale commercial prototypes are already being tested at sea. A full scale testing centre, EMEC, has been established in Orkney and is proving crucial in the evolution of the industry. Research is still ongoing, however, and, once again, Edinburgh is playing a significant role. The University is involved in public and private funded research, much of it in direct association with industry.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210406</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Analyzing the performance ofwave-energy generator systems (SSG) for the Southern Coasts of Iran, in the Persian Gulf and Oman Sea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Sea-wave Slot-cone Generator (SSG) wave-energy device is a type of electric energy converting structure that converts energy from sea waves, and which is designed and installed based on wave-overtopping in areas. Most of the previous studies have evaluated SSG systems based on hypothetical waves, considering the system geometry variations. However, it is important to consider the real wave conditions. This paper presents the results of a numerical study to investigate the performances of an SSG system in the context of the Persian Gulf and Oman Sea, where there is a strong need for renewable energies. The computational fluid dynamic (CFD) code Flow-3D was applied. First of all, available experimental data were applied to calibrate and evaluate the accuracy of the numerical model. Then, the real wave conditions on the coasts of the Persian Gulf and Oman Sea were imposed on the JONSWAP spectrum for the numerical modeling. Results of the study demonstrated that the hydraulic efficiency of the SSG system in the Persian Gulf and Oman Sea was low for wave heights lower than 0.5 m. The nominal efficiency of the system was relatively more than 60% for wave heights higher than 1 m; thus, the performance of the SSG system was suitably evaluated. Finally, the numerical results demonstrated that the most optimal conditions, with a nominal efficiency of 97%, were obtained for incident waves that had a height of 2 m and a period of 5.6 s. In this case, the hydraulic performance of the system was maximum. Â© 2018 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en11113209</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210410</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A review on front end conversion in ocean wave energy converters</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Harvesting the energy from ocean waves is one of the greatest attractions for energy engineers and scientists. Till date, plenty of methods have been adopted to harvest the energy from the ocean waves. However, due to technological and economical complexity, it is intricate to involve the majority of these energy harvesters in the real ocean environment. Effective utilization and sustainability of any wave energy harvester depend upon its adaptability in the irregular seasonal waves, situation capability in maximum energy extraction and finally fulfilling the economic barriers. In this paper, the front end energy conversions are reviewed in detail which is positioned in the first stage of the wave energy converter among other stages such as power take off (PTO) and electrical energy conversion. If the recent development of these front end energy conversion is well known then developing wave energy converter with economic and commercial viability is possible. The aim of this review is to provide information on front end energy conversion of a point absorber and emphasize the strategies and calamity to be considered in designing such kinds of devices to improve the energy harvesting competence. This will be useful to the engineers for speeding up the development of a matured point absorbing type wave energy converter.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1007/s11708-015-0370-x</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210442</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An Improvement on Slot Configuration Structure for a Low-speed Surface-mounted Permanent Magnet Synchronous Generator with a Wound Cable Winding</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper concentrates on low-speed surface-mounted permanent magnet synchronous generator (LS-SMPMSG) electromagnetic design using finite-element (FEM)-based method. The introduced LS-SMPMSG is utilized in marine energy conversion (MEC) and tidal energy conversion (TEC) systems. The main feature of the designed LS-SMPMSG is its ability to generate electrical power in MEC and TEC systems at a low speed of approximately 100 rpm. In the second part, a new slot structure for LS-YYSMPMSG has been proposed to enhance the LS-SMPMSG performance. The FEM analysis shows that the new slot structure led to reducing the torque ripple and the cogging torque equal to 19.54\% and 87.5\% respectively. Also, it influenced the LS-SMPMSG Joule losses by 16.1\% reduction. Another advantage of the new slot structure of LS-SMPMSG is its easy construction and assembly. The FEM analysis validates the advantages of the proposed structure.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.5829/ije.2021.34.09c.01</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210463</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Molecular profiling of an oleaginous trebouxiophycean alga Parachlorella kessleri subjected to nutrient deprivation for enhanced biofuel production</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Background: Decreasing fossil fuels and its impact on global warming have led to an increasing demand for its replacement by sustainable renewable biofuels. Microalgae may offer a potential feedstock for renewable biofuels capable of converting atmospheric CO2 to substantial biomass and valuable biofuels, which is of great importance for the food and energy industries. Parachlorella kessleri, a marine unicellular green alga belonging to class Trebouxiophyceae, accumulates large amount of lipids under nutrient-deprived conditions. The present study aims to understand the metabolic imprints in order to elucidate the physiological mechanisms of lipid accumulations in this microalga under nutrient deprivation. Results: Molecular profiles were obtained using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) of P. kessleri subjected to nutrient deprivation. Relative quantities of more than 60 metabolites were systematically compared in all the three starvation conditions. Our results demonstrate that in lipid metabolism, the quantities of neutral lipids increased significantly followed by the decrease in other metabolites involved in photosynthesis, and nitrogen assimilation. Nitrogen starvation seems to trigger the triacylglycerol (TAG) accumulation rapidly, while the microalga seems to tolerate phosphorous limitation, hence increasing both biomass and lipid content. The metabolomic and lipidomic profiles have identified a few common metabolites such as citric acid and 2-ketoglutaric acid which play significant role in diverting flux towards acetyl-CoA leading to accumulation of neutral lipids, whereas other molecules such as trehalose involve in cell growth regulation, when subjected to nutrient deprivation. Conclusions: Understanding the entire system through qualitative (untargeted) metabolome approach in P. kessleri has led to identification of relevant metabolites involved in the biosynthesis and degradation of precursor molecules that may have potential for biofuel production, aiming towards the vision of tomorrow's bioenergy needs. Â© 2019 The Author(s).</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1186/s13068-019-1521-9</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210464</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Introduction of an innovative wave energy converter: SPA-OWC</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A new type of the wave energy converter called a submergible point absorber using oscillating water column (SPA-OWC) is presented. SPA-OWC is an axisymmetric device consisting basically of a submerged vertical tail tube open at both ends, fixed to a lid having an open bottom to the sea. It seems to be quite similar to the spar-buoy. However, the air chamber of the SPA-OWC is not exposed to the atmosphere so there is no restriction of the installation location. That is, this device can be floating or submerged. Furthermore, the body of SPA-OWC is not necessary to move essentially in heave. Therefore, easy access for maintenance is guaranteed, and it may be free to choose an installation method among the tight-mooring, slack-mooring, or standing on a sea-bed. The dynamics of SPA-OWC is analyzed in the frequency domain and the theoretical performance is computed using ANSYS AQWA to prove its feasibility. Copyright Â© 2014 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210479</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A rule-based phase control methodology for a slider-crank wave energy converter power take-off system</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The slider crank is a proven mechanical linkage system with a long history of successful applications, and the slider-crank ocean wave energy converter (WEC) is a type of WEC that converts linear motion into rotation. This paper presents a control algorithm for a slider-crank WEC. In this study, a time-domain hydrodynamic analysis is adopted, and an AC synchronous machine is used in the power take-off system to achieve relatively high system performance. Also, a rule-based phase control strategy is applied to maximize energy extraction, making the system suitable for not only regular sinusoidal waves but also irregular waves. Simulations are carried out under regular sinusoidal wave and synthetically produced irregular wave conditions; performance validations are also presented with high-precision, real ocean wave surface elevation data. The influences of significant wave height, and peak period upon energy extraction of the system are studied. Energy extraction results using the proposed method are compared to those of the passive loading and complex conjugate control strategies; results show that the level of energy extraction is between those of the passive loading and complex conjugate control strategies, and the suboptimal nature of this control strategy is verified. Â© 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijome.2017.07.001</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210480</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A self-regulating heat pump to utilize wind and wave energy sources</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wind and wave energy devices produce their outpw in the form of shafr work, with a power ourput which varies over a wide range as the input energy intensity changes. For mypr ocesses (desalination, thermochemical processes, steam raising, space heating) energy is required in the form of heat. The conversion of shfi work directly to heat is thermodynamically very ineficient. This eficiency may be greatly improved by using the shafr work to drive a heat pump which abstracts thermal energy from the environment (the sea or airstream) and upgrades it to the requisite remperature level. In this regard, wind and wave energy are iakal sources, since the thermal energy contained in the airstream or sea exceeds by several orders of magnitude the mechanical energy that can be abstracted. Heatpwnps have hitherto been designed to utilize a constant work input and a source of heat at variable temperature. But in order to harness renewable energy effectively, a heat pump is required rhat will utilize variable shafr work to upgrade heal from a source at mar-conrtant temperamre. A prototype heat pump is described that enables heat from an ambient source at âˆ¼20Â°C to be delivered to a load at âˆ¼100Â°C by a vapor compression system working with variable power input, such as that deriving from wind or wave energy. The design incorporates features that enable power inputs from 0.3-3 kW to be harnessed, corresponding to the wave energy in a0.1-m width of usable wavefront, or the wind energy abstracted by a rotor of 2.5-m diameter in windspeeds of 7-15 m/s. A c.o.p. of âˆ¼3 may be obtained over this range of power input. Thus the heat output is equivalent to that obtainable directly from an energy conversion device of three times the size. The combination of a renewable energy device with a self-regulating heat pump exhibits significant economies of scale up to a unit size of around 1 MW (thermal). Thus the potential uses for this device, particularly in offshore processing and in desalination, are very great. Â© 1990 Taylor and Francis Group, LLC.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1080/00908319008960180</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210484</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Shoreline wave power ,electrical generation on Islay</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A prototype oscillating water column wave energy absorber has been constructed on the island of Islay off the west coast of Scotland. The hydrodynamic and pneumatic response of the device were monitored for a two year period. A turbine generator rated at 75kW was installed in March 1991. Since then, the behaviour of the turbine generator has been monitored in all types of sea conditions. This paper gives a brief outline of the design and operation of the current system. Results from the electrical monitoring programme to date are presented. These focus on the performance of the turbine and generator in different sea conditions. The aerodynamic behaviour of the turbine is discussed with reference to the need for a well matched system. The energy transfer along the chain of power conversion from incident wave energy to electrical output will be evaluated. Comment will be made on the variability of the incident energy, and the resulting effect on the electrical output.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210497</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Detection and tracking of aircraft over wind farms using SCANTER 4002 with embedded tracker 2</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Test results of aircraft detection and tracking over large offshore wind farms show that a track can be maintained on a light manoeuvring aircraft as well as general aviation aircraft using an off-the-shelf radar solution. The optimum strategy of mitigating the deteriorating effects of closely spaced wind turbines on air surveillance is shown to depend on the characteristics of the wind farm, in particular the density of the wind turbines.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/cp.2012.1644</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210498</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The offshore floating type wave power device ``Mighty Whale{''} open sea tests - Performance of the prototype</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mighty Whale is a floating wave power device based on the Oscillating Water Column (OWC) principle. It converts wave energy into electric energy, and produces a relatively calm sea area behind. The open sea tests were begun in September 1998 in Gokasho Bay, Nansei Town, Mie Prefecture. Measurements collected since then include performance data in typhoon seasons. This paper presents the measurements of wave energy absorption, floating body motion, and wave height dissipation. It is expected that these results will be useful in the design of offshore wave power devices in the future.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210501</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave Energy in the Red Sea Region Perspectives and Analysis</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The present study aims to find the best location for installing wave energy converters (WEC) in the NEOM area, located in the Red Sea northern region, and to determine the most suitable converter system for harvesting wave energy using available data provided by KAUST. The Red Sea region represents a challenge for wave modulization and analysis due to its two distinct and opposing wave structures induced by reverse winds that converge at its middle. By incorporating wind and wave data series from 1985 to 2015 in the Advanced Research Weather and Forecasting model and WAVEWATCH III. In the present study, the highest peak period found in the selected area is 4 seconds based on the wave hindcast generated on a 1-km resolution grid, and the highest wave found was 0.79 m. A total of 8 points were selected and analyzed to test the potential of wave energy at NEOM coastlines along the Gulf of Aqaba and NEOM Bay. Based on the results, the Gulf of Aqaba, with a mean wave power of 1.98 kW/m at P\#2 is a good candidate for a WEC system. Possible installation of wave energy converters in the selected areas is discussed in this thesis, including farms of point absorbers with the integration of wave and solar sources (DEIM). Based on preliminary information regarding the NEOM region, potential environmental and social challenges were identified in this study for the viability of wave energy exploitation.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210503</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Factors that influence array layout on wave energy farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents a study of the factors that influence array layout on wave energy farms. The WEC considered is a two-body heave converter extracted from Babarit et al. (2012). Simulations were run through a time domain model from de Andres et al. (2013) with irregular waves considering different sea states. Factors analyzed in this paper are array layout, WEC separation, number of WECs and wave directionality. Results show that wave directionality is very important in order to achieve constructive interference. When looking at the number of WECs the conclusion is that as the larger the number of WECs, more interactions are possible and therefore, the higher the interaction factor is. Regarding array layout, triangle and square configurations were found to be similar and the efficiency of each one depends on the most probable peak period. Separating distance was found to be a key factor and L10/2 was set as the optimal one. Finally, wave climate was classified in different subtypes around the globe. The optimum layout in these sites was assessed. The influence of directionality was studied and the triangular configuration was found to be the most favorable for multidirectional climates while square configurations were most adequate in unidirectional climates. Â© 2014 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2014.02.027</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210505</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Challenges in the reliability and safety data collection for offshore wind turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wind energy is abundantly available in nature both on onshore and offshore. As a response to the climatic crisis the focus on wind energy is increasing due to its renewable and environment friendly energy production. Due to social and political reasons the trend has been shifted largely from onshore to offshore wind farms. Offshore wind energy production faces a wide range of new challenges in design, development, manufacturing, installing, and maintenance and operational. In this paper the challenges and issues pertaining to reliability and safety data collection of offshore wind turbines are outlined. In the offshore oil and gas industry the OREDA concept for data collection has been running for more than 25 years. We therefore briefly describe what is considered to be the state of the art within this industry when it comes to data collection. Next we discuss expected differences between the oil and gas industry, and the wind power industry which will have an impact on data collection. Finally we point at some trends that we believe will be important for future data collection especially related to availability to online condition monitoring data. The reliability and safety data will be of utmost importance when maintenance and inspection strategies are to be developed. Therefore we also give some preliminary aspects related to what type of data we really need for various types of analyses. Â© 2010 Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210511</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ocean energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ocean energy is an important and promising renewable energy for the future. Even though extensive technology development and demonstrations have occurred in the areas of ocean thermal energy, wave energy and tidal energy over the last 40 years, commercial plants based on these technologies are very slow in coming up because of the high capital costs. In recent years, due to increase in the fossil fuel costs, renewable energies such as solar photo voltaic systems and wind energy systems have become cost competitive. Ocean energy systems are likely to become cost competitive in a decade or so, especially for remote islands and coastal areas. This chapter presents the highlights of developments in the areas of ocean thermal energy, wave energy and tidal energy. Â© Printed in India.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.16943/ptinsa/2015/v81i4/48306</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210516</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design of Wave Energy Converter (WEC): A prototype installed in Sicily</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The purpose of this work is to describe a possibility of installation of a wave converter in Sicily, in the Mediterranean Sea. In this paper we present the design of buoyant electrical generator, in particular, wave linear permanent magnet generator which can make wave energy converted to electrical energy.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/OCEANS-Genova.2015.7271536</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210518</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">WEC prototype advancement with consideration of a real-time damage accumulation algorithm</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Machine maintenance and repair is not a trivial issue when it comes to renewable energy devices. It has been said that one of the most important factors in enhancing the marketability of wind energy is to cut its overall maintenance costs, which is about 10% - 20% of the overall cost of energy [1]. The average maintenance and repair costs of ocean wave energy devices are yet to be determined, but it may be higher than wind energy. The harsh ocean environment, repeated cycling of the drive train, coastal storms, environmental concerns, loss of revenue due to long periods of machine downtime, safety issues concerning technicians working on the buoy while it's still in operation, and so forth, all add to the maintenance and repair costs of a WEC (Wave Energy Converter). This study proposes a unique damage accumulation prediction algorithm that enables real-time determination of bearing fatigue life. Â© 2011 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/PTC.2011.6019378</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210519</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Sailing solar-cell raft project and weather and marine conditions in low-latitude Pacific Ocean</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Development of a huge wind-sailing solar cell raft (SCR) with dimensions of 5Ã—5 km is proposed, which can generate electricity comparable to a 1,000-MW nuclear power plant in low-latitude Pacific Ocean. Solar energy of 8 kÂ·Wh/m2/day or more is targeted because the SCR navigates in fine weather using weather satellites. The generated electricity will be transported by battery tankers loaded with a tremendous number of high-energy-density batteries. Studies based on available data indicate that there are vast open seas in the tropical Pacific Ocean, where the maximum solar energy attains 7 kÂ·Wh/m2/day annually on average and conditions of winds, waves, and sea currents are favorable for the solar energy system to operate. Three major technologies for breakthrough to realize this system are discussed from their future perspectives. Â© 2013 American Society of Civil Engineers.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1061/(ASCE)EY.1943-7897.0000088</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210531</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">London Array Offshore Wind Farm, Outer Thames Estuary, UK</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The 175-turbine London Array wind farm was built on schedule, on a scale once thought unfeasible for the emergent offshore wind sector-and despite economic headwinds of the global recession and rough weather and sea conditions. Its success has been vital for the UK, which has anchored its energy future with offshore wind power.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210550</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Efficient winds</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An expert from Westwood Global Energy Groupâ€™s provides information about the global offshore wind market. Westwood Global Energy Group has tracked the emergence and development of the offshore wind market for the last 17 years. Over this time, it has seen a niche industry supported by subsidies and delivering near-shore, small-scale projects grow into a multi-billion-dollar industry. Increasing project scale has been a major underlying trend in the industry. Capacity, water depth, and distance from shore have been increasing since the early projects. With the development of floating foundations, offshore substructures can be deployed with efficient connection in 50m-500m water depth, delivering a step change in technology innovation.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210582</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Joint evaluation of the future wave and wind energy close to Bulgaria and Romania coastlines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The importance of this study is to underline the fact that the wind energy potential in the western part of the Black Sea basin can be considered significant, while the wave energy is lower in comparison with oceans. However, in winter time when energy consumption in Bulgaria and Romania is high, the wave energy presents the highest values. The aim of this research paper is to draw a comprehensive picture regarding the wave and wind energy near Bulgaria and Romania coastlines. More precisely, six locations were studied. Regarding the geographical location, the studied points are located in the range 42Â°N to 45.2Â°N and 27Â°E to 30Â°E as follows: three points are near to the Bulgariaâ€™s coastline and the other three close to Romaniaâ€™s coastline. In this study, the wind conditions were analyzed at 10-meter height. The data for the wind analysis were provided by the Regional Climate Model (RCM) from Euro-Cordex database (EUR-11) and covers three intervals. All intervals cover 30-year of data as follows: Historical dataset (01 January 1976 to 31 December 2005), near future RCP8.5 scenario (01 January 2021 to 31 December 2050) and future RCP8.5 scenario (01 January 2071 to 31 December 2100). The wave analysis was conducted on the same intervals but using data coming from SWAN model. Finally, by analyzing the resulted coming from this joint evaluation it can be concluded that the presented analysis provides a more comprehensive picture regarding the future wind and wave energy resources in the coastal environment of Bulgaria and Romania, compared with historical period. Â© 2019, International Multidisciplinary Scientific Geoconference. All rights received.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.5593/sgem2019/4.1/S17.038</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210583</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Predicting Output Power for Nearshore Wave Energy Harvesting</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Energy harvested from a Wave Energy Converter (WEC) varies greatly with the location of its installation. Determining an optimal location that can result in maximum output power is therefore critical. In this paper, we present a novel approach to predicting the output power of a nearshore WEC by characterizing ocean waves using floating buoys. We monitored the movement of the buoys using an Arduino-based data collection module, including a gyro-accelerometer sensor and a wireless transceiver. The collected data were utilized to train and test prediction models. The models were developed using machine learning algorithms: SVM, RF and ANN. The results of the experiments showed that measurements from the data collection module can yield a reliable predictor of output power. Furthermore, we found that the predictors work better when the regressors are combined with a classifier. The accuracy of the proposed prediction model suggests that it could be extremely useful in both locating optimal placement for wave energy harvesting plants and designing the shape of the buoys used by them.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/app8040566</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210584</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical Modelling of an Air Turbine for a Hybrid System for Sea Wave Energy Utilization</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In connection with global warming and the depletion of energy production resources, new clean ways of obtaining energy are increasingly being sought. A source of renewable energy harvesting is the energy of sea and ocean waves. The present paper reports the design and modelling of an air turbine and its numerical simulation, which will be used in a hybrid system for utilization of the energy of wind waves. Â© 2022 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/CIEES55704.2022.9990674</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210591</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Recent tendency and progress of installation surroundings and technology for environment load reduction on high voltage circuit breakers</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Recent tendencies of installation surroundings and progress of technologies for environment load reduction on high voltage circuit breakers are reviewed. Damage situations of the circuit breakers on the Great East Japan Earthquake in 2011 are shown and studies of seismic design and guidelines of substation equipment are reviewed. In addition, new surroundings such as an offshore substations for wind farms are introduced. Life extension technologies with RCM (Reliability Centered Maintenance) will be more important technologies for a point of view of environment load reductions. The transition from fundamental phase to industrial phase will be made in research and development of substitute SF6 GCB (Gas Circuit Breaker). Â© 2017 The Institute of Electrical Engineers of Japan.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1541/ieejpes.137.484</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210596</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Thermal analysis of thermo-electric power generation system for the waste heat recovery from a marine diesel engine aboard a handymax-size tanker</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The waste heat recovery from marine diesel engines is important in terms of improving the energy efficiency of ships. Thermo-electric generator can be used to convert the waste heat in the ship to the electrical energy. This study investigates the effects of different thermo-electric materials and sea water temperatures on the thermal performance of the thermo-electric power generation system. The polyacetylene, Ba8Ga16Ge30, SiGe and (CuI)001Bi2Te3 are considered thermo-electric materials. The energy of the exhaust gases from the marine diesel engine on a handymax-size tanker is used as the waste heat source. The maximum electrical power of 117 kW is produced for (CuI)0.01Bi2Te3 at the sea water temperature of 5Â°C and the engine load of 100% MCR (Maximum Continuous Rating). However, the minimum electrical power of 18.74 kW is produced for the polyacetylene at 30Â°C and 75% MCR. Â© 2023 the Author(s).</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1201/9781003358961-53</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210603</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A Political, economic, social, technology, legal and environmental (PESTLE) approach for risk identification of the tidal industry in the United Kingdom</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents a comprehensive analysis of renewable and especially tidal energy through a political, economic, social, technology, legal and environmental (PESTLE) analysis approach and by reviewing the most up to date relevant literature. The study focuses on the United Kingdom given the favourable environmental resources for such technologies; the number of different design concepts that are currently under development as well as the research funding that has been invested over the last few years. Findings of the analysis identify the risks and multiple stakeholders involved at all stages of the tidal energy projects development from the conceptualization of the design, right through to decommissioning. Many of the stakeholders present benefits to the tidal developers through funding, incentives and knowledge sharing, but at the same time they also present potential risks to the future of projects. This is mostly down to different approaches of the most important aspect of tidal energy that needs to be considered, making it hard for technologists and developers to equally address all requirements. From this research it can be concluded that several of these risks can be mitigated early on providing that particular stakeholders are involved at the correct stage of a project. Â© 2013 by the authors; licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en6105023</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210608</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Experimental verification of ABS concrete design methodology applied to the design of the first commercial scale Floating offshore wind turbine in the United States</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The abundance of consistent high strength winds off the world's coastlines and the close proximity to dense population centers has led to development of innovative marine structures to support wind turbines to capture this energy resource. Off the US coast, 60% of the offshore wind lies in deep water (greater than 60m) where the development of Floating Offshore Wind Turbine (FOWT) hull technology will likely be required in lieu of fixed bottom technology such as jacket structures. The United States National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) and the offshore wind community commonly refer to 60m as the transition point between fixed bottom structures and floating structures due to economic reasons. Floating wind turbines deployed in the harsh offshore marine environment require the use of materials that are cost-effective, corrosion resistant, require little maintenance and are highly durable. This has led the University of Maine to develop a concrete hull technology called VolturnUS for full-scale 6MW FOWTs. In this work, experimental testing was conducted to verify the performance of the concrete under operational, serviceability, and extreme loading conditions as required by the American Bureau of Shipping Guide for Building and Classing Floating Offshore Wind Turbines. The testing included structural testing sub-components of the hull and served as experimental verification of American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) concrete design methodology which is currently approved and being used to design the first commercial scale FOWTs in the United States. Two 6MW wind turbines supported on VolturnUS concrete hulls will be used for the New England Aqua Ventus I project. The project is planned to be deployed and connected to the grid by 2019 in the Northeast U.S. and is funded by the US Department of Energy. Copyright Â© 2017 ASME.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/OMAE2017-62461</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210613</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Economic feasibility of wind and photovoltaic energy in Kuwait</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The worldwide environmental concern and awareness created a way towards the generation of pollution-free wind and solar renewable energies. Wind and Photovoltaic (PV) power plants of each 10 MW capacity located in the Shagaya area, west of Kuwait, were compared after one year of operation. The wind power plants recorded high capacity factors resulting in a yearly power production of 42.59 GWh, 21% higher than expected (contractual 31.160 GWh). It will reduce the emission of CO2 throughout the projected lifetime of 25 years by 118,303 tons. CAPEX (capital Expenditure) and OPEX (operation expenditure) were taken into consideration throughout the life of the plants along with investment costs resulting in a levelized cost of electricity (LCOE) for wind of 0.015 KWD/kWh or 0.046 USD/kWh, compared to 0.027 KWD/kWh or 0.082 USD/kWh for solar PV (44% lower than PV). Offshore, Boubyan Island, Northern Kuwait territorial waters, were found to be the foremost appropriate for wind energy generation, with Wind Power Density of more than 500 Watt/m2 in summer which is ideal for the high energy demanding season in Kuwait. The LCOE for offshore wind energy was 27.6 fils/kWh, compared to 39.3 fils/kWh for thermal power plants. Â© 2021 EDP Sciences. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1051/e3sconf/202128005016</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210618</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Optimization of Output Parameters of the Horizontal Tidal Turbine by Modifying Its Meridional Section</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The velocity of tidal current at the location of Haya Strait shows that the velocity of ocean currents could reach 2.54 m/s with the available power density of Pd = (0 -3670) x10-3 kW/m2. To utilise the available energy, then a prototype of bulb propeller tidal turbine in the form of Venturi canal was designed and tested using a raft platform. The dimensions of the turbine; inlet diameter D0 = 4 meter and impeller diameter D1 = 1.5 meter and outlet diameter = 2.60 meter. At the speed stated above, hydraulic force obtained reached 324 kW. Optimization of turbine output parameters is carried out through structural modification and cross-view geometrical modification. Turbine meridian cross view section is modified to be streamlined. In this case, cross view modification by adapting ducted-turbine that is carried out without changing the inlet dimension. Flow velocity was measured at three turbine sections, namely at the inlet section, the impeller housing section and the outlet section. Rate of meridian flow is measured at three meridian positions, which are Vo at the inlet, V1 at the impeller and V2 at the outlet. Output parameters are calculated based on the water velocity and the data measured at the three corresponding sections. The maximum power coefficient was found to be 0.593 that occurs at the induction factor value of a = 0.346 and the maximum thrust coefficient of CT = 1 was found at the induction factor value of a = 1. The hydraulic power is changed from 0.00 Ã· 226 kW to 0 Ã· 324 kW, or an increase of 43%. The turbine brake power is changed within the range of 0.00 Ã· 194 kW to 0 Ã· 221 kW that is equivalent to 14% of power increase. Â© 2018 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/BICAME45512.2018.1570498954</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210630</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">INFLUENCE OF INCOMING FLOW DIRECTION ON SPACING BETWEEN VERTICAL AXIS MARINE CURRENT TURBINES PLACED IN A ROW</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">From the commercial point of view it may be beneficial to install a set of marine current turbines forming a park, by analogy with wind parks. Consequently, this motivates research on park configurations. An array of ten vertical axis marine current turbines is simulated to study how the distance between the turbines affects the performance of the park for different flow directions. The simulations are performed using a two-dimensional vortex method. An array of identical turbines is created, where all turbines are on a single line. The turbines are operated at the tip speed ratio, which corresponds to the highest power coefficient for a single turbine. The distance between the turbines is varied and the total power from the array is compared to the turbine spacing for different flow directions. Additionally, flow data from a real site is used to find an optimal orientation of the line of turbines. The performance of the array is estimated for the site as a function of turbine spacing.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210635</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design and Development of a Multi-Port Converter for Marine Microgrid Applications</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this work, a multi-port converter (MPC) design is presented that works as the key building block of a marine microgrid. An emulated wave energy converter (WEC) serves as the renewable energy resource of this microgrid system. The proposed MPC is comprised or a WEC interfacing port, energy storage port, and a split-phase AC load/grid port. Stable power exchange among these dissimilar energy resources are facilitated through a 400V internal DC bus. The full MPC design along with its control and thermal model is developed and implemented in PLECS. Commercially available SiC power modules have been used to leverage its high switching frequency capability that to achieve compact system design with reduced passive component sizes. Individual controller for each energy resource interfacing converter is analyzed, developed and implemented initially. A state-machine is developed utilizing these discrete controllers for MPC operation where all three ports are active simultaneously. These discretized controllers along with voltage/current sensor models with limited bandwidth and response delay in the feedback path are implemented in PLECS to emulate practical controller deployment. Simulation results are provided to validate both the power stage and the discrete controller design. Furthermore, iterative thermal analysis is carried out to have a realistic estimation of the device junction temperature during rated condition to evaluate the efficacy of the thermal management system. Finally, a virtual prototype design of the MPC is presented.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/ECCE47101.2021.9595808</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210642</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Western Europe: France: GDF Suez...</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">GDF Suez is carrying out feasibility studies for tidal power projects at Raz Blanchard in Lower Normandy and Passage du Fromveur in Brittany. At Raz Blanchard, the firm wants to install a pilot plant of 3-6 turbines, giving a power of 3-12 Mw, by 2015. There are plans eventually for a commercial facility with 100 turbines.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210654</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind farm black start service integration: Review and outlook of ongoing research</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A review of the ongoing research on black start (BS) service integrated with offshore wind farms (OWFs) is presented in this paper. The overall goal is to firstly gain a better understanding of the BS capabilities required by modern power systems. Subsequently, the challenges faced by OWFs as novel BS service providers as well as an outlook on the ongoing research which may provide solutions to these are presented. OWFs have the potential to be a fast and environmentally friendly technology to provide BS services for power system restoration and, therefore, to ensure resiliency after blackouts. As a power electronic-based system, OWFs can be equipped with a self-starter in the system in order to perform BS. The self-start unit could be a synchronous generator (SG) or a power electronic unit such as a grid-forming (GFM) converter. Preliminary BS studies performed in PSCAD/EMTDC are presented in a simplified OWF system via an SG as the self-start unit. Consequently, technical challenges during the BS procedure in an OWF benchmark system are outlined via theoretical discussions and simulations results. This is useful to understand the threats to power electronics during BS. Finally, the most relevant GFM strategies in the state-of-the-art literature are presented and their application to OWF BS is discussed. Â© 2020 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en13236286</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210655</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Tidal turbines to mine marine megawatts</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Unlike wind turbines, marine turbines are source of a more consistent energy production because of more consistent tidal flows and wind currents. Usually, they are built of conventional materials like steel. However, three featured turbines' rotor blades are made up of composites. These include projects by OpenHydro Group Ltd., Verdant Power in collaboration with the New York Power Authority, and of the Marine Current Turbines Ltd. The first is a multimillion euro project that includes installation of a series of unique Open-Center turbines off the coast of the island of Alderney. Second is the development of a $1.5M, three-blade turbine design intended to moor a cluster of turbines off Roosevelt Island in New York city's East River. Lastly, the development of Seaflow which is the world's first "full-size" tidal turbine. It is an 11m, 36 ft. diameter propeller-like, two-blade rotor mounted on a 3.1m, 10 ft. diameter steel monopile.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210656</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Assessing the impact of introduced infrastructure at sea with cameras: A case study for spatial scale, time and statistical power</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Detecting the effects of introduced artificial structures on the marine environment relies upon research and monitoring programs that can provide baseline data and the necessary statistical power to detect biological and/or ecological change over relevant spatial and temporal scales. Here we report on, and assess the use of, Baited Remote Underwater Video (BRUV) systems as a technique to monitor diversity, abundance and assemblage composition data to evaluate the effects of marine renewable energy infrastructure on mobile epi-benthic species. The results from our five-year study at a wave energy development facility demonstrate how annual natural variation (time) and survey design (spatial scale and power) are important factors in the ability to robustly detect change in common ecological metrics of benthic and bentho-pelagic ecosystems of the northeast Atlantic. BRUV systems demonstrate their capacity for use in temperate, high energy marine environments, but also how weather, logistical and technical issues require increased sampling effort to ensure statistical power to detect relevant change is achieved. These factors require consideration within environmental impact assessments if such survey methods are to identify and contribute towards the management of potential positive or negative effects on benthic systems.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.marenvres.2019.04.007</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210657</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">PUBLIC RESPONSES TO A PROPOSED WIND FARM AND THEIR APPLICATION TO TECHNICAL COMMUNICATION METHODS</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Large-scale renewable energy projects such as wind farms are becoming increasingly common installations in and near local communities. Wind power promises to reduce our dependence on fossil fuels, but public resistance to new forms of energy poses a communication problem. This study collects the responses of local Northeast Ohio residents to a proposed offshore wind farm on Lake Erie. The findings can improve environmental communication between experts and the public. A framework for the metaphorical construction of meaning is provided as a method for improving future dissemination of environmental information. Learning objective: It is important for technical communicators to understand and use apt metaphors to describe environmental issues to increase public comprehension and engagement. Â© 2022 Taylor and Francis.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.4324/9781003266549-10</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210666</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Role of Wave Energy Converter Farms in Coastal Protection</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Many worldwide coasts are under erosion with climate projections indicating that damages will rise in future decades. Specifically, deltaic coasts are highly vulnerable systems due to their low-lying characteristics. This chapter investigates the role of wave energy converter (WEC) farms on the protection of an eroding gravel-dominated deltaic coast (Guadalfeo, southern Spain). Eight scenarios with different alongshore locations of the wave farm were defined and results were compared with the present (no farm) configuration of the coast. Assuming that storm conditions drive the main destruction to the coast, we analysed the impact of the most energetic storm conditions and quantified the effects of the location of the farm. Significant wave heights in the lee of the farm were calculated by means of a calibrated wave propagation model (Delft3D-Wave); whereas wave run-up and morphological changes in eight beach profiles were quantified by means of a calibrated morphodynamic model (XBeach-G). The farm induces average reductions in significant wave heights at 10m water depth and wave run-up on the coast down to 18.3\% and 10.6\%, respectively, in the stretch of beach most affected by erosion problems (Playa Granada). Furthermore, the erosion of the beach reduces by 44.5\% in Playa Granada and 23.3\% in the entire deltaic coast. Combining these results with previous works at the study site allowed selecting the best alternative of wave farm location based not only on coastal protection but also on energetic performance criteria. This chapter, whose methodology is feasibly extensible to other coasts worldwide, provides insights into the role of the alongshore location of WEC farms on wave propagation, run-up and morphological storm response of deltaic coasts.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1007/978-3-319-90701-7</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210673</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Estimation of the wave energy in the Italian offshore</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Vicinanza, D., Cappietti, L., Ferrante,V. and Contestabile, P., 2011. Estimation of the wave energy in the Italian offshore. Journal of Coastal Research, SI 64 (Proceedings of the 11th International Coastal Symposium), 613 - 617. Szczecin, Poland, ISSN 0749-0208 The offshore wave energy potentials of the Italian seas has been studied by analyzing the wave measurements carried out by the Italian Wave Buoys Network. The annual and monthly average offshore wave power, varies between 1,6 kW/m and 9.05 kW/m. The Adriatic sea shows an average value around 2 kW/m, the smallest value around Italian coasts as expected. The Ionian, North and Middle Tyrrhenian seas are a bit more energetic reaching a value of about 3 kW/m whereas the South Tyrrhenian is characterized by a value of 4 kW/m. A completely different behavior is highlighted for the Alghero buoy (north-west Sardinia island) where the estimated power reaches the value up to 9 kW/m.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210676</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A Resonant ZVZCS DC-DC Converter With Two Uneven Transformers for an MVDC Collection System of Offshore Wind Farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A resonant zero-voltage and zero-currentswitching (ZVZCS) dc-dc converter is proposed in this paper for a medium-voltage dc collection system of offshore wind farms. The resonant converter is composed of two full-bridge cells sharing a bridge leg, two transformers with uneven power ratings and different functions, whose secondary windings are connected in series and a voltagedoubler rectifier. The converter operates in discontinuous current mode and can achieve zero-current switching for four main power switches and rectifier diodes over the whole load range. The two auxiliary switches with small forward current can be turned on with ZVZCS, and turned off with zero-voltage switching. Hence, the switching loss can be reduced and efficiency is improved. The operation principle of the converter is analyzed and design rules of main parameters are presented. The influences of the turn ratios of auxiliary transformer and resonant capacitance on the peak and switching-off currents are discussed in detail. Furthermore, a model is built in PLECS and simulation results are given. A 150-1500 V/2 kW prototype is established and tested to verify the operation principle and design rules.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TIE.2017.2694389</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210678</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Control Strategy on Optimal Redistribution of Unbalanced Power for Offshore Wind Farms Integrated VSC-MTDC [é€‚ç”¨äºŽæµ·ä¸Šé£Žç”µæŽ¥å…¥çš„å¤šç«¯æŸ”ç›´ç½‘å†…ä¸&#x8d;å¹³è¡¡åŠŸçŽ‡ä¼˜åŒ–åˆ†é…&#x8d;æŽ§åˆ¶ç­–ç•¥]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this paper, for a voltage source converter based multi-terminal DC transmission (VSC-MTDC) system connected with offshore wind farms, a self-adaptive and hierarchical control scheme was proposed to consider the optimal allocation of imbalanced power when wind energy fluctuation occurred frequently. The equivalent extra cost function in the form of active/reactive power and voltage on the valve side was deduced firstly in details. Based on the incremental cost curve of extra generation and DC voltage at the point of common coupling (PCC), the scheme can locally make the unbalanced power be shared economically without central controller, having similar effect to the equal increment principle (EIP). Principles of control parameters setting was discussed based on control characteristic analysis and stability analysis. Finally, a 4-terminal radial system was used to verify the effectiveness in PSCAD/EMTDC simulation platform. The results show that the proposed scheme can reduce the extra generation cost effectively under normal conditions, and maintain DC voltage stability and power balance when the fault occurs. Â© 2020 Chin. Soc. for Elec. Eng.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.13334/j.0258-8013.pcsee.182565</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210681</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modelling of power fluctuations from large offshore wind farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper deals with modelling of power fluctuations from large wind farms. The modelling is supported and validated using wind speed and power measurements from the two large offshore wind farms in Denmark. The time scale in focus is from 1 min to a couple of hours, where significant power fluctuations have been observed from these wind farms. Power and wind speed are measured with 1s sampling time in all individual wind turbines in almost 1 year, which provides a substantial database for the analyses. The paper deals with diversified models representing each wind turbine individually and with aggregation of a wind farm to be represented by a single large wind turbine model. Copyright Â© 2007 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/we.246</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210682</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Floating buoy type energy collector for tidal current power generation (proposition of desirable profile and preliminary investigation)</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The authors have proposed, at ISOPE-2000, the unique machine in which two stage runners successfully counter-rotate the inner and outer rotors of the peculiar generator. This machine has remarkable advantages that not only output voltage is sufficient but also rotational moments hardly act on a mounting bed. These advantages make extremely easy to board the machine with large capacity on a floating buoy moored in the strait. In this paper, a semi-circular cylinder is proposed as the floating buoy type energy collector for giving effectively tidal current energy to the counter-rotating runners and flow conditions around its body are discussed with experimental data. Vortex behaviors shedding from its collector are also simulated numerically in comparison with visualized results.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210683</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Life cycle assessment of electricity generation from an array of subsea tidal kite prototypes</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Tidal current technologies have the potential to provide highly predictable energy, since tides are driven by lunar cycles. However, before implementing such technologies on a large scale, their environmental performance should be assessed. In this study, a prospective life cycle assessment (LCA) was performed on a 12 MW tidal energy converter array of Minesto Deep Green 500 (DG500) prototypes, closely following the Environmental Product Declaration (EPD) standards, but including scenarios to cover various design possibilities. The global warming potential (GWP) of the prototype array was in the range of 18.4â€“26.3 gCO2-eq/kWhe. This is comparable with other renewable energy systems, such as wind power. Material production processes have the largest impact, but are largely offset by recycling at the end of life. Operation and maintenance processes, including the production of replacement parts, also provide major contributions to environmental impacts. Comparisons with other technologies are limited by the lack of a standardized way of performing LCA on offshore power generation technologies. Â© 2020 by the authors.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en13020456</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210686</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An Efficient Offshore Wind-Wave Hybrid Generation System Using Direct-Drive Multitoothed Rotating and Linear Machines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents an offshore wind-wave hybrid generation (WWHG) system, which can efficiently harness the offshore wind and wave energy. The key is to use the multitoothed doubly-salient permanent-magnet (MDSPM) machines for serving the rotating generator and the linear generator. Different from the traditional wind or wave generation system, this WWHG system integrates the wind generation part and wave generation part together to directly harness the wind and wave energy without gear box. The system configuration and machine design are analyzed and discussed in detail. Also, the finite-element method is performed to verify the validity of the proposed two machine design. The results tell that the system has the high reliability and can be upgraded to the suitable size for offshore hybrid-source energy conversion in practical application.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210690</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Comprehensive feasibility assessment of a poly-generation process integrating fast pyrolysis of S. japonica and the Rankine cycle</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Marine macroalgae or seaweeds are increasingly becoming strong candidates for sustainable biofuel feedstocks of the future. This study features a large-scale process design and comprehensive analysis of an industrial-scale (400,000 tons dry feedstock per year) poly-generation pyrolysis process that utilizes 3rd generation biofuel feedstock, Saccharina japonica brown seaweed, and produces diesel-range hydrocarbon fuel, heat, and power. Process design relied predominately on published experimental data regarding fast pyrolysis of S. japonica in a fixed-bed reactor system, followed by dewatering and catalytic upgrading of the produced biocrude. The design featured acid wash pretreatment for the reduction of mineral content, and subsequently a Rankine power cycle utilizing biochar. The design also considered two distinct cases of on-site hydrogen production and hydrogen purchase. Based on the experimental data, a rigorous steady-state flowsheet model was constructed using Aspen Plus for each design case. The results of comprehensive techno-economic assessment, sensitivity, and Monte Carlo analyses provided insight into capital cost for the process, minimum product selling price, and selling price ranges. Finally, the process is compared with traditional crude oil extraction and processing in terms of significant reductions in CO2 emissions, hence providing strong evidence of its environmental sustainability. Â© 2019 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.113704</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210697</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Topology assessment for 3 + 3 terminal offshore DC grid considering DC fault management</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This study assesses four DC grid topologies where each of the terminals can exchange power with any other terminal and a DC fault on any DC cable can be isolated. The DC grids are built using the following components: hybrid DC circuit breakers (CB), mechanical DC CBs, DC/DC converters and DC hubs. The aim is to compare DC fault performance, technical feasibility/readiness, power transfer security, expansion and costs. The base case for comparison are three separate 300 km offshore HVDCs connecting 3 1 GW offshore wind farms with three onshore VSC terminals. The rating of DC CBs is limited by the state of technology and costs which introduces limitation on the length of DC cables (because of communication delays) and on the DC bus fault level (limiting the number of connecting DC lines). DC/DC converters inherently block propagation of DC faults and their rating is not sensitive to DC fault level. DC hubs have considerable cost advantages over multiple DC/DC converters in cases where multiple DC systems are connecting at the same DC station. The cost assumptions for all major components are analysed, including the offshore platform costs. The study concludes that overall DC grid costs are similar (within 8%) for all four topologies. Although power security is similar for all technologies, the expansion options are best with DC/DC converters or DC hubs. DC hubs nevertheless suffer from highest on-state losses. Â© The Institution of Engineering and Technology 2015.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/iet-gtd.2013.0838</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210698</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Reliability, maintainability and levellised cost of offshore wave energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave Energy Converters pose a unique engineering challenge, with complex and innovative technology, to be deployed in hostile locations with limited access opportunities. Reliability is a concern, given that failures may occur in sea states which give peak output, but which could delay repair interventions, leading to significant revenue losses. Reliability can be viewed as an economic question, in which the initial capital costs of a wave energy development, and the available energy yield at its deployed location, are balanced against the future operating and maintenance costs, and revenue losses from breakdowns. This paper describes a model based on real wave data, in which the interaction of the wave resource, capital, operating and maintenance costs, and different levels of reliability and maintainability is examined to determine their effect on the Levellised Cost of Energy from a wave farm. Â© 2010: The Royal Institution of Naval Architects.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210699</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Research on an innovative large-scale offshore wind power seawater desalination system</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">For high cost, hard grid connection and low failure probability for large-scale offshore wind power, an innovate seawater desalination system is proposed. It directly couples offshore wind power with high energyconsuming seawater desalination to a new and full one. The system uses 100%off-shore wind power and adopts variable condition optimal control to maintain energy consumption per unit when fresh water production changes due to wind power fluctuation. Furthermore, it changes power transmission as fresh water transmission ashore, which not only solves the difficult problem of large-scale, and super-large-scale wind power application, saves the investment of offshore wind farms and increases the utilization efficiency of wind energy, but also solves the point source pollution problems caused by on-shore largescale and super-large-scale seawater desalination. As a result, the system is of great practical and strategic significance. Â© 2010 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/WNWEC.2010.5673305</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210709</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Power of ocean: Evaluation of blue energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Blue Energy has created a new vista of renewable and sustainable energy forms with the power of ocean. This article evaluates tidal energy as a major source of blue energy. It analyzes how tidal energy has the potential to contribute enormously towards a greener future. A few real-life examples are illustrated how the blue energy research paradigm can harness the kinetic energy of the ocean, such as triboelectric nanogenerators, tidal barrage, and tidal current turbines to replace the fossil fuels with renewable energy. Â© 2018 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/UV.2018.8709306</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210715</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Structural condition assessment of offshore wind turbine monopile foundations using vibration monitoring data</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The offshore wind farm industry has substantially grown in recent years. There is a substantial number of wind farms in the waters offshore Europe with several others proposed for regions in North America and Asia. A vast majority of the existing offshore wind turbines are supported on monopile foundations. The presence of a monopile in a flowing body of water causes the water to accelerate around the monopile, which can result in seafloor scour. Scour can significantly reduce the soil support thereby reducing the monopile stability and strength. Scour can also reduce the fundamental natural frequency of the turbine structure. If the natural frequency of the support structure approaches the turbine rotor frequency, a resonant condition will develop that can damage the turbine or its support structure. To avoid this situation, a monitoring system consisting of two strategically located bidirectional accelerometers was installed on the towers of four turbines of an existing offshore wind farm. The objective of the monitoring campaign was to correlate frequency measurements with the overall structural performance of the monopile foundations. The developed approach was based on operational modal analysis and system identification techniques using acceleration response data and calibrated computer models. Identified frequencies were correlated to specific structural performance limit states including; vibrating resonance of the tower with the turbine rotor, lack of foundation stability, and yielding of the monopile foundation material. This paper presents the findings of this work, which can assist owners and operators who may benefit from similar structural health monitoring systems. Â© 2013 SPIE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1117/12.2018263</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210716</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Operational data to maintenance optimization: Closing the loop in offshore wind O&amp;M</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind assets have reached multi-GW scale and additional capacity is being installed and developed. To achieve demanding cost of energy targets, awarded by competitive auctions, the operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) of these assets has to become increasingly efficient, whilst ensuring compliance and effectiveness. Existing offshore wind farm assets generate a significant amount of inhomogeneous data related to O&amp;M processes. These data contain rich information about the condition of the assets, which is rarely fully utilized by the operators and service providers. Academic and industrial research and development efforts have led to a suite of tools trying to apply sensor data and build machine learning models to diagnose, trend and predict component failures. This study presents a decision support framework incorporating a range of different supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms. The aim is to provide guidance for asset owners on how to select the most relevant datasets, apply and choose the different machine learning algorithms and how to integrate the data stream with daily maintenance procedures. The presented methodology is tested on a real case example of an offshore wind turbine gearbox replacement at Teesside offshore wind farm. The study uses k-nearest neighbour (kNN) and support vector machine (SVM) algorithms to detect the fault using supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA) data and an autoregressive model for the vibration data of the condition monitoring system (CMS). The implementation of all the algorithms has resulted in an accuracy higher than 94%. The results of this paper will be of interest to offshore wind farm developers and operators to streamline and optimize their O&amp;M planning activities for their assets and reduce the associated costs. Copyright Â© 2018 ASME.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/IOWTC2018-1058</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210718</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Optimized design of doubly salient permanent magnet generator taking into account converter constraints</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents the operation and characteristics of a doubly salient PM generator for tidal energy turbine. The behavior and the supply strategy of this unconventional machine is described. An energy ratio criterion is introduced and combined with a torque to mass ratio one for the design of such system taking into account both the generator compactness and the converter sizing. A simple method for the calculations of these two criterions is proposed. The influences of the main geometrical parameters which define the machine geometry are firstly studied. Then a multi-objective optimization process is used to optimize the two design criterions. From the calculations of these criterions for 20,000 set of geometrical parameters a Pareto front is highlighted. Several point of this Pareto front which corresponds to typical DSPM designs are presented and analyzed. The results highlight the interest of proposed method which optimize simultaneously the generator design and the converter size. Â© 2016 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/CISTEM.2016.8066816</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210719</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Techno-economic assessment of biofuel development by anaerobic digestion of European marine cold-water seaweeds</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The techno-economic characteristics of macro-algae utilisation from European temperate zones was evaluated in a selected Anaerobic Digester (AD) using the chemical process modelling software ECLIPSE. The assessment covered the mass and energy balance of the entire process followed by the economic feasibility study, which included the total cost estimation, net present value calculation, and sensitivity analysis. The selected plant size corresponded to a community based AD of 1.6 MWth with a macro-algae feed rate of 8.64 tonnes per day (dry basis). The produced biogas was utilised in a combined heat and power plant generating 237 kWe(net) electricity and 367 kW(th) heat. The breakeven electricity-selling price in this study was estimated at around (sic)120/MWh. On the ground of different national and regional policies, this study did not account for any government incentives. However, different support mechanisms such as Feed-in-Tariffs or Renewable Obligation Certificates can significantly improve the project viability. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.biortech.2013.01.005</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210727</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Aeroelastic design of large wind turbine blades considering damage tolerance</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modern offshore turbine blades can be designed for high fatigue life and damage tolerance to avoid excessive maintenance and therefore significantly reduce the overall cost of offshore wind power. An aeroelastic design strategy for large wind turbine blades is presented and demonstrated for a 100Â m blade. High fidelity analysis techniques like 3D finite element modeling are used alongside beam models of wind turbine blades to characterize the resulting designs in terms of their aeroelastic performance as well as their ability to resist damage growth. This study considers a common damage type for wind turbine blades, the bond line failure, and explores the damage tolerance of the designs to gain insight into how to improve bond line failure through aeroelastic design. Flat-back airfoils are also explored to improve the damage tolerance performance of trailing-edge bond line failures. Copyright Â© 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Copyright Â© 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/we.1997</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210729</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical modelling of an undulating membrane tidal energy converter</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The undulating membrane tidal energy converter is a device that uses the flutter instabilities occurring from the interaction between a slender body and a fluid flow. A new numerical model has been developed using a 2D corotational finite element method to represent the structure and the unsteady point-vortex method to compute the flow. These methods as well as the interaction process are presented. Trajectory and frequency of the undulating motion, hydrodynamic forces on the structure and velocity field in the wake are presented. Comparison shows a good agreement with experimental results obtained from a 1/20th scale prototype without power take off tested in flume tank. Â© 2020, European Wave and Tidal Energy Conference. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.36688/imej.3.119-126</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210738</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ocean wave measurement and wave energy calculation using overtopping power plant scheme</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Indonesian seas have not been used as a source of electricity yet. One of the potential and abundant sources of energy from the sea is ocean waves. This study describes the measurement of the wave characteristics and calculates its spatial and temporal energy in Pari Island which can be utilized as electrical energy using overtopping ocean wave power plants scheme. The energy that can be harvested from ocean waves is calculated by wave energy converter using the Wave Dragon WEC. This converter is the terminator type. Sea waves on the Pari Island are classified as the smooth sea with 0.16-0.51 meters significant wave height and 2-4 seconds period. The calculated WEC can produce energy up to 28 Mega Joules and power up to 6 Mega Watts. Based on this calculation, Wave Dragon which is an overtopping WEC is able to meet the electricity needs on Pari Island with two options, The first one is using 35 units of WD 1 on the Pari Island Coast with a 500 m distance from the settlement, or the second one is using 6 units of WD 2 which is located in the northeast region of Pari Island waters with 18 Km distance from the settlement of Pari Island.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1088/1755-1315/429/1/012047</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210739</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind resource assessment of the Gulf of Thailand</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The Royal Thai Government recently launched its latest policy regarding the installation of 1,800 MW wind power capacity by 2025. While onshore wind power has significant limitations due notably to land use constraints and public acceptance, offshore wind energy offers good opportunities of development and is thus an interesting alternative. The main objective of this paper is to present the offshore wind resource assessment of the Gulf of Thailand, which covers an area of 320,000 km2. A coupled mesoscale-microscale model is used, along with R1 NCEP/NCAR global reanalysis database, to generate a high resolution wind resource map. Results show that interesting potential areas for offshore wind farm development have wind speeds of up to 6.5 m/s, especially in the upper part of the Gulf of Thailand, covering a surface of 2,112 km 2. With a total potential installed capacity of 5,000 MW, the annual energy production is estimated at 9.64 TWh/year. Â© 2014 Asian Institute of Technology.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210742</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Early Stage Inter-turn Faults Detection Technique for the Rotor Windings of Offshore Wind DFIGs Based on the Differential Value of Two-side Linkage's Observation [åŸºäºŽå&#x8f;Œä¾§ç£&#x81;é“¾è§‚æµ‹å·®çš„æµ·ä¸Šå&#x8f;Œé¦ˆé£ŽåŠ›å&#x8f;‘ç”µæœºè½¬å­&#x90;ç»•ç»„åŒ&#x9d;é—´çŸ­è·¯æ—©æœŸæ•…éšœè¾¨è¯†]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The offshore wind turbine generators (DFIG) are difficult to maintain caused by their low accessibility, so the accuracy of fault identification is higher than onshore DFIGs. The slip power makes the fault characteristics very weak and difficult to identify when DFIGs are close to synchronous speed operation. An identification method was proposed for early faults of inter-turn short-circuit in rotor windings of offshore DFIGs, which was characterized by the differential value of (two-side linkage's observation, TSLO). According to the mechanism of the short-circuit fault in the DFIG rotor windings, the expression of the differential value of TSLO in the inter-turn short circuit was derived. Then the robustness of the fault feature to the slip variation and the rotational speed measurement error is verified by simulation. The simulation and experimental results show that the differential value of TSLO has high sensitivity and high reliability for the early fault identification of the rotor windings in DFIGs, which provides technical support for the accurate identification of the inter-turn short circuit of the rotor windings in DFIGs. Â© 2019 Chin. Soc. for Elec. Eng.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.13334/j.0258-8013.pcsee.180587</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210749</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An artificial neural network model of coastal erosion mitigation through wave farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this work, a novel approach based on artificial intelligence (AI) to assess the efficiency of wave energy converter (WEC) farms in coastal protection isdeveloped. We consider as a case study a beach subjected to severe erosion: Playa Granada (S Spain). More specifically, we analyse the changes in the dry beach area (quantified through the Pelnard-Considere equation) with and without wave farm protection by means of an Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model. The model is selected after a thorough comparative study involving forty ANN architectures, with one and two hidden layers, and two training algorithms (Levenberg-Marquadt and Bayesian regression). The best results are obtained with a {[}5-10-1] architecture trained with the Bayesian regression algorithm. Once validated, this ANN model is applied to optimize the design and position of the wave farm. The results confirm that ANN models are a useful design tool for hybrid wave farms.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.envsoft.2019.07.010</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210751</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">How thick should tidal turbine blades be?</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Tidal turbine rotor hydrodynamic performance is affected by the blade geometry, which in turn affects the commercial performance of the project. Reductions in blade thickness generally improve performance but must be balanced against the extra cost of material required to make thinner blades strong enough. The authors have carried out a parametric study to quantify the effects of blade geometry choice and construction method on the Levelised Cost of Energy (LCOE) of the turbine, at a range of flow speeds typical for tidal power sites. Both hydrodynamic and structural analyses have been used to develop the blade design, taking into account known costs of materials and manufacture based on experience of building megawatt-scale turbine rotors. The methodology and results from this study can be used by turbine designers to determine the optimum blade thickness for a given flow condition.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210753</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave power Sustainable energy or environmentally costly? A review with special emphasis on linear wave energy converters</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Generating electricity from waves is predicted to be a new source of renewable energy conversion expanding significantly, with a global potential in the range of wind and hydropower. Several wave power techniques are on the merge of commercialisation, and thus evoke questions of environmental concern. Conservation matters are to some extent valid independent of technique but we mainly focus on point absorbing linear generators. By giving examples from the Lysekil project, run by Uppsala University and situated on the Swedish west coast, we demonstrate ongoing and future environmental studies to be performed along with technical research and development. We describe general environmental aspects generated by wave power projects; issues also likely to appear in Environmental Impact Assessment studies. Colonisation patterns and biofouling are discussed with particular reference to changes of the seabed and alterations due to new substrates. A purposeful artificial reef design to specially cater for economically important or threatened species is also discussed. Questions related to fish, fishery and marine mammals are other examples of topics where, e.g. no-take zones, marine bioacoustics and electromagnetic fields are important areas. In this review we point out areas in which studies likely will be needed, as ventures out in the oceans also will give ample opportunities for marine environmental research in general and in areas not previously studied. Marine environmental and ecological aspects appear to be unavoidable for application processes and in post-deployment studies concerning renewable energy extraction. Still, all large-scale renewable energy conversion will cause some impact mainly by being area demanding. An early incorporation of multidisciplinary and high quality research might be a key for new ocean-based techniques. (C) 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.rser.2009.11.016</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210756</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Faring well in offshore wind power siting? Trust, engagement and process fairness in the United States</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Although visual effects may be the most defining characteristic of a wind project, implementing fair, transparent and just decision-making processes may be a significant determining factor in success. To shed light on this question, we undertook a study of perceptions of mainland coastal and island residents proximate to the Block Island projectâ€”the first offshore wind project in the United States. The study included a longitudinal survey of residents prior to and after turbine installation, and semi-structured interviews with residents and key stakeholders. We assessed the extent to which respondents were engaged in the planning process, opinions of transparency and fairness, and degree to which the planning process affected their opinion. Although interviewees who held a negative view of state government indicated that it did not cause them to oppose the project, trust in state government was the primary driver of perceptions of process fairness, which in turn was the primary driver of project support. We also found individuals to withhold final judgment of the process until the final outcomeâ€”project operation. Finally, fair process was seen as having benefits distinct from its effect on the outcomeâ€”that is, local residents valued the process itself. Â© 2019 The Authors</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.erss.2019.101393</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210758</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Technical potential and abatement costs associated with the use of process emissions from sugarcane ethanol distilleries for EOR in offshore fields in Brazil</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This study evaluates the technical feasibility and the abatement costs of the use of CO2 that is generated by the fermentation of ethanol produced in the South-Central region of Brazil to perform enhanced oil recovery using CO2 (CO2-EOR) in oil fields of the Campos basin. This mitigation alternative includes the capture of CO2, its transportation to the location of use and injection. The fermentation of ethanol produces a high concentration stream of CO2 and therefore has a low cost of capture. The technical feasibility analysis demonstrates the potential to use approximately 80% of the CO2 that is emitted by the distilleries. The abatement costs vary with the costs of dehydration, compression and injection of CO2 and with the type of investor in the CO2-EOR infrastructure, which could be an oil company or a set of distilleries. When an oil company invests in the EOR infrastructure, the average abatement cost is approximately US$ 200 per tonne of CO2. When distilleries are the investors, the average abatement cost is approximately US$ 350 per tonne of CO2. This disparity is because the revenue from selling the oil that is produced by EOR is much higher than the revenue from selling the CO2 at the wellhead. Â© 2016 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijggc.2016.07.007</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210759</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Construction of the first offshore wind turbines in Setana Port in Japan</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Two 600kW wind turbines were built in the Setana Port area in summer, 2003, and started official electric generation from April 1st, 2004. They are the very first wind turbines built in the offshore area in Japan. In Hokkaido, there are many wind energy development projects on land, and of course there are many wind turbines operating in Tohoku area, northern part of Honshu Island, too. While offshore wind farms, consisting of ten to twenty wind turbines at a single offshore location, are being built and operated from 1980s and 90s in Europe, no such offshore project is realized in Japan before. But cooperating with the Setana Town government, RIOE(Research Institute for Ocean Economics) had examined the feasibility of the offshore site selection of wind turbines, thanks to the large unused sea area of the port and to the financial support from NEDO(New Energy Development Corporation). Potential of the wind energy on site is quite favorable with 7.9m/s average through a year, and good efficiency is expected. RIOE organized research committee on this project for a couple of years and executed the basic design phases. Joint Venture Construction company consisted of Kawasaki Heavy Industries and Penta-Ocean companied were engaged in construction and had unique experience. Problems faced with are not only in the technical but also in the economic field with regard to selling the produced electricity to the Hokkaido Electric Company. Those experiences are described and discussed the possibility of the offshore wind farms in Japan in this paper. Â© 2004 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210761</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Structural vibration control of Nrel 5.0 MW fowt using optimal-based MR tuned vibration absorber</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this work, a National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) 5.0 MW floating offshore wind turbine (FOWT) model equipped with nonlinear, magnetorheological (MR) tuned vibration absorber (TVA) is analysed. Several optimal-based MR damper control solutions are regarded against passive TVA configurations and the structure without the TVA system. Tower and barge/platform angular displacement amplitude frequency responses are compared, proving the efficiency and robustness of the adopted vibration reduction solutions, as well as their capability to minimise the amplitude of the vibrating structure, the demanded actuator (e.g. MR damper) force and stroke range. Copyright Â© 2020 The Authors. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ifacol.2020.12.1253</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210762</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Estimating wind energy potential offshore in Mediterranean areas</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Relatively few studies have been performed on the evaluation of offshore wind resources, and these have been conducted mostly in Northern Europe. In Mediterranean areas the lack of such studies is mainly linked to (1) the difficulty of meteorological monitoring in deeper waters, (2) the complex orography, frequently extending down to the coasts, (3) the sea breeze wind regimes and (4) local winds such as the Bora, Mistral and Sciroc. In the North Adriatic Sea, a shallow basin of the Mediterranean, the first reason is not applicable, but the others are sufficient to make the evaluation of wind speed methods challenging. In this article we estimate the wind climatology at a platform located 15 km offshore of Venice based on 7 years of data and compare it with the wind climatology obtained by five different methods using the long-term data from four coastal meteorological stations, Venezia Tessera, Venezia San Nicola, Ronchi and Rimini. We discuss the applicability of these methods and find that the WAsPÂ® model of RisÃ¸ National Laboratory is still the best tool for wind climate estimates. The results of two new methods are promising, but the methods still require some development. Copyright Â© 2003 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/we.81</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210763</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Developments in the utilization of hydraulic energy.</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Discusses the utilisation of hydraulic energy. Conventional hydropower is seen as the developing resource worldwide. In industrial nations effort is now being directed towards low head regions of the lower reaches of rivers. Various low head stations are described. The section on wave energy presents a survey of current wave energy converters and discusses the difficulties in converting and transferring the power to a useable form onshore. The final section on tidal energy discusses its advantages and modes of operation and gives details of existing tidal power stations and reports on the present status of tidal power, with particular reference to the Severn Estuary, U.K. (S.A.K.)</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210765</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind resource in the context of global climate change over a tropical area</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Understanding the future offshore wind energy is crucial for making an appropriate energy strategy. Yet how offshore wind energy will respond to the rapidly intensifying global warming remains inconclusive. Focusing on a tropical sea in Vietnam, this study assesses the climatic impact of global warming on the local offshore wind potential. Dynamically downscaled wind data obtained by an edge-cutting fine-resolution regional climate model with two greenhouse-gases Representative Concentration Pathway (RCP) scenarios 8.5 and 4.5 were biased-corrected with a quantile mapping method before using for assessment. Results revealed a changing trend of the annual-mean offshore wind speed and power potential in Vietnam under both scenarios. However, the change is seasonally asymmetric with decreases of about 2 â€“ 10% in September-October-November and slight increases of about 2 â€“ 4% in December-January-February. The turbine-based assessment showed that the cumulative annual energy obtained from the 12 MW and 8 MW turbines could reach the highest about 50.9 GWh and 30.7 GWh (2080â€“2099 average under scenario RCP8.5) but the difference in their capacity factor is much smaller, suggesting that turbine 8 MW should be considered in the sense of cost-effectiveness in some areas. Â© 2021</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.apenergy.2021.118369</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210767</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design considerations for ocean energy resource systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The ocean occupy nearly three-quarters of the earth's surface and represent an enormous source of renewable energy. While many of the world's industrialized nations have conducted exploratory research and development, the total power currently available from ocean energy systems, with the exception of the French tidal power plant, is less than one hundred megawatts (MW). An increasing number of ocean energy conversion systems are approaching an acceptable stage of development for commercial utilization. This paper considers the factors which are the most important in the design and development of ocean energy resource systems. Sources of renewable energy in the marine environment include tides, waves, currents, and thermal gradients. The challenge is to balance the energy resource potential with sources of environmental loading, which are applicable to a specific site, in the most logical and coherent manner possible, in order to make wise choices regarding site selection and system design.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210775</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">WAVE-BY-WAVE PREDICTION in NARROWLY SPREAD SEAS USING FIXED-AND DRIFTING-POINT WAVE RECORDS: VALIDATION USING PHYSICAL MEASUREMENTS</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Accurate and reliable phase-resolved prediction of ocean surface waves is crucial for many offshore operations in ocean engineering and marine science. One important application is in optimal control of a power take-off in a wave energy converter, leading to significantly higher power production. Our interest is the forecasting of wave fields based on measurements obtained from multiple upwave locations in moderate seas with small directional spreading angles, such as is prevalent along the south coast of Australia. The prediction model, based on FFTs and propagation of waves according to the linear dispersion relation, is applied to both wave groups and irregular wave fields generated in a wave basin and, additionally, to ocean waves measured with drifting wave buoys. To account for spreading, the model numerically advances linear, plane (i.e. long-crested) waves in space at an optimum offset angle equal to the underlying seastate root-mean-square spreading angle. Averaging predictions based on a few slightly separated measurement locations, each weighted according to the estimated variance of the individual prediction, is shown to be more accurate than that from any single location. We also assess in detail the effect of drifting-buoy measurements in both long-crested and short-crested seas using synthetic wave records and show that it is possible to satisfactorily reconstruct the signal at fixed points based on the Doppler shift felt by the drifting buoy. The reconstructed signals give much better predictions compared to those completely neglecting the effect of even rather slow drift. Â© 2022 American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME). All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/OMAE2022-80885</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210787</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Dynamic analysis of wave action on an OWC wave energy converter under the influence of viscosity</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Oscillating water column (OWC) device is one of the most promising wave energy converters (WECs). Besides the energy conversion efficiency, the survivability should also be considered for a design purpose in the process of wave energy exploitation. In the present study, by introducing the artificial viscous terms into the dynamic free surface boundary condition and Bernoulli equation, a fully nonlinear numerical model based on higher-order boundary element method (HOBEM) is adopted to model the wave dynamics of an OWC device. The viscosity effects on the wave force (i.e., Î”F) is investigated by comparing the predicted wave force by the numerical model with and without these viscous terms. The effects of the chamber geometry parameters, such as front wall draft, chamber width and opening ratio (i.e., air orifice width), on Î”F are investigated. The results indicate that the viscosity effect on the wave force on the seaside surface of the front wall is larger than that on its shoreside surface. The viscosity effect on the total horizontal wave force on the front wall increases with the increase of front wall draft in some extent. The influence of the viscosity on the horizontal wave force increases with opening ratio decreasing due to the increasing air pressure inside the chamber. Â© 2020 The Authors</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2020.01.007</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210791</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Strategic review of the renewable energy technologies an economic assessment. Volume II: appendices containing detailed analyses.</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Establishes whether and when economic exploitation of the various renewable energy technologies can be anticipated. Estimates the rate and extent to which they might penetrate markets. Indicates what future Government activity in their further research, development or deployment might be appropriate. Sources considered were fuel from biomass, geothermal aquifers, wind power, wave power and tidal power. -from CEGB Digest</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210798</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Expected Effects of Offshore Wind Farms on Mediterranean Marine Life</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Current climate policy and issues of energy security mean wind farms are being built at an increasing rate to meet energy demand. As wind farm development is very likely in the Mediterranean Sea, we provide an assessment of the offshore wind potential and identify expected biological effects of such developments in the region. We break new ground here by identifying potential offshore wind farm (OWF) ``hotspots{''} in the Mediterranean. Using lessons learned in Northern Europe, and small-scale experiments in the Mediterranean, we identify sensitive species and habitats that will likely be influenced by OWFs in both these hotspot areas and at a basin level. This information will be valuable to guide policy governing OWF development and will inform the industry as and when environmental impact assessments are required for the Mediterranean Sea.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/jmse4010018</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210800</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Retrofitting of monopile transition piece for offshore wind turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The monopile foundation for an offshore wind turbine (OWT) has been successfully implemented worldwide, particularly in Germany, Denmark and the United Kingdom. Numerous offshore wind farms have been operational for a large percent of their expected service lives. However, one problematic area of concern is that the transition zone of the structure (the connection between the monopile and tower) relies on a grouted connection which fails to support the axial load of the OWT when it is subjected to wind and wave loadings. This is a major implication for offshore wind farms that are installed and, thereby requires a retrofit solution that is not only adequately-effective, but also efficiently implemented. This paper analyzes a retrofit solution that involves drilling holes through the transition piece, grout, and monopile and installing pins, which would completely prevent vertical movement between the transition piece and monopile. The NREL 5MW reference wind turbine was considered for this study, atop a monopile with a 5m diameter. To adequately address the major issue presented, this study consists of three simulation parts. All three parts implemented a finite element model (FEM) analysis of the transition zone to: 1) simulate the transition zone without any additional supports types (e.g. shear keys); 2) simulate the transition zone with the support of shear keys; and 3) simulate the transition zone with the retrofit pins without the implementation of shear keys. These pins will be spaced based on a general following of the DNV guidelines for shear key design. All three of the models are local models only, and thus have simplified loading conditions applied. Each model is 25m tall and are assumed to be fixed at the base. The retrofit solution will then be compared to the other cases to determine its efficacy in transcending the grout-failure problem. From this study it is anticipated that an effective retrofit solution will be simulated for a general OWT size. Copyright Â© 2017 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210810</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The effect of control strategy on tidal stream turbine performance in laboratory and field experiments</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The first aim of the research presented here is to examine the effect of turbine control by comparing a passive open-loop control strategy with a constant rotational speed proportional-integral-derivative (PID) feedback loop control applied to the same experimental turbine. The second aim is to evaluate the effect of unsteady inflow on turbine performance by comparing results from a towing-tank, in the absence of turbulence, with results from the identical machine in a tidal test site. The results will also inform the reader of: (i) the challenges of testing tidal turbines in unsteady tidal flow conditions in comparison to the controlled laboratory environment; (ii) calibration of acoustic Doppler flow measurement instruments; (iii) characterising the inflow to a turbine and identifying the uncertainties from unsteady inflow conditions by adaptation of the International Electrotechnical Commission technical specification (IEC TS): 62600-200. The research shows that maintaining a constant rotational speed with a control strategy yields a 13.7% higher peak power performance curve in the unsteady flow environment, in comparison to an open-loop control strategy. The research also shows an 8.0% higher peak power performance in the lab compared to the field, demonstrating the effect of unsteady flow conditions on power performance. The research highlights the importance of a tidal turbines control strategy when designing experiments. Â© 2018 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en11061533</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210812</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Current Policy and Technology for Tidal Current Energy in Korea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">As global energy consumption continues to increase, the negative impact of global warming also grows. Therefore, eco-friendly energy policy is being established all over the world. Korea's energy consumption problems are further complicated by the country's high dependence on energy sourced overseas. Korean energy policy is evolving rapidly to address these problems. Korea has begun to phase out nuclear power and is focusing on developing new sources of renewable energy. So there has been substantial interest in the development of ocean energy. Of all ocean energy technologies, tidal current energy is the closest to the commercialization. Especially, the southwestern coast of Korea is the most promising candidate site for the development of tidal current energy owing to the abundant tidal current energy resource. Meanwhile, ocean energy policy is an important factor in determining the development of ocean energy. Thus, this paper presents the overview of the current status of policy and technology for the tidal current energy system in Korea. These policies explained in this paper can provide significant interest and motivation for the use of tidal current energy resources.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en12091807</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210816</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Global monitor: UK approves wave energy "hub"</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The British government has approved construction of the $56 million Wave Hub, a deep-sea electricity "socket" that will sit on the seabed 10 mi off the Cornish coast and link as many as 30 wave energy machines to the UK electricity grid. The project, to be located in waters about 150 feet deep, will enable wave energy developers to "plug in" and test the efficiency and durability of their machines, which convert the kinetic energy of waves to electricity. Plans call for the Wave Hub to be connected to the UK grid by a 15-mi undersea cable that will come ashore at a substation at Hayle, in southwest England. Wave Hub could deliver up to 20 Mw of electricity, enough power to meet 3% of Cornwall's electricity needs. The Wave Hub project will cover an area measuring 2.5 mi by 1 mi; each early developer will be given a 5-to-10-year lease for a space in that area. The British government will subsidize $9 million to the offshore Cornish project. Southwest RDA, which has already spent more than $4 million on permitting, has approved $43.4 million for Wave Hub, with 50% of that sum expected to come from the European Regional Development Fund.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210825</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Optimization design on hydrodynamic performance of counter-rotating tidal turbine using blade element momentum theory and cfd</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Counter-rotating horizontal-axis tidal turbine (HATT) based on blade element momentum (BEM) theory is designed in order to improve the condition of low energy efficiency of traditional HATT. The research found that the flow field characteristic of counter-rotating HATT is more ordered than traditional HATT. Dynamic performance, power performance and starting requirement of counter-rotating HATT is superior to that of traditional HATT. The optimal range of blade installation angle of counter-rotating HATT is from 57 degree to 65 degree. At an optimal L of near 0.225D (where L is the distance between the front and rear rotators and D is diameter of rotor), counter-rotating HATT showed best power performance among the 3 tested L. Â© 2020 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210831</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Met-ocean conditions influence on floating offshore wind farms power production</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Met-ocean conditions may affect the performance of a floating wind turbine, since a harsh climate could lead the system to exceed its operating thresholds and thus to force the machine shutdown. In this paper, it is a proposed methodology to evaluate the effect of met-ocean conditions on the long-term dynamic behaviour, and energy production, of a floating wind farm. For a sample of 500 MW farm located off the coast of Aberdeen (Scotland), 20 years of met-ocean data are generated by means of meteorological reanalysis techniques. A subset of 1000 hourly conditions is selected, by means of a maximum dissimilarity algorithm, and input to a dynamic floating wind turbine model. Numerical results are then interpolated for the whole set of met-ocean data, using radial basis functions. This approach allows to dramatically reduce the global computation time. Tower inclination and hub acceleration are chosen as relevant operating parameters: the former mainly depends on mean wind speed and direction, being largest at rated wind speed. The latter is also affected by significant wave height, and reaches its highest values when wind and waves are aligned. For each simulation, any machine exceeding the selected safety threshold is considered to be shut down. Assuming continuous operation, the average lifespan capacity factor of the farm is 50.2%; more restrictive tolerances result in a non-linear reduction of the energy production. This approach may help both at the design and the operational stage, in determining the best trade-off between energy production and safe operation. Â© 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/we.1840</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210832</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical study on overtopping performance of a multi-level breakwater for wave energy conversion</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Overtopping wave energy converter (OWEC) is capable of converting the unstable wave energy into the relatively stable potential energy in its reservoir. The small wave height and the large tidal range in China will cause a lower efficiency of the traditional single-level overtopping device especially at the lower tidal level. The design of the multi-level reservoirs may be a solution to improve the overtopping performance, which can be integrated in the sloping-ramp breakwater. In this study, a multi-level breakwater for wave energy conversion, consisting of two reservoirs with sloping walls at different levels, is proposed. A numerical wave tank based on the VOF model is established in ANSYS-Fluent (R) 12.0 for the OVVEC's performance investigation. The numerical model on predicting the overtopping process and time-averaged discharges is validated by corresponding experimental data. Effects of the opening width of the lower reservoir, sloping angles of two reservoirs and the gap height between the reservoirs on the dimensionless overtopping discharges are studied numerically. It is found that a smaller opening width, larger height ratio, and two sloping angles of 30 degrees have positive effects to improve the overtopping performance of the device.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2017.12.058</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210841</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Impact of a periodic power source on a RES microgrid</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The aim of this article is to highlight the impact of a periodic power source, such as a tidal turbine, on the operation and sizing of an autonomous hybrid microgrid with photovoltaic panels and storage. The technique of hill climbing (repeated local search) is used to find the optimum combination of Renewable Energy Sources (RES) and storage units with respect to the required capital cost for various load curves and weather conditions. To model the operation of the microgrid devices, analytical and phenomenological models, have been used, which take into account the specifications of actual commercial devices. Six different case studies are presented, with and without a tidal generator, which are based on six different sets of electrical consumption data corresponding to the Euripus campus of the National &amp; Kapodistrian University of Athens (NKUA) in Psachna, Evia, Greece, and respective meteorological and tidal current data from the region. The results show that tidal energy may be used in a RES microgrid, where applicable, to satisfy the base load requirements, leading to a reduction in installed capacities of intermittent RES and storage, accompanied with cost reduction, especially in cases where a high load factor is observed or may be achieved, through demand response mechanisms. Such a hybrid microgrid configuration may be appropriate for regions where low velocity tidal and marine currents exist along with substantial solar and/or wind energy potential, such as the Mediterranean coast line and islands. Â© 2019 by the authors.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en12101900</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210846</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Power digest (July 2013): Scotland approves world's largest wave power farm</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The government of Scotland has approved Aquamarine Power's 40-Mw wave farm, the largest in the world, off the northwest coast of Lewis, Scotland. Lewis Wave Power Ltd could begin installing its near-shore Oyster wave energy machines at the site in the next few years, once necessary grid infrastructure has been put in place. The project envisions deployment of between 40 and 50 Oyster devices along the coast at Lag na Greine, near Fivepenny Borve. Aquamarine Power is currently testing a second-scale wave machine known as the Oyster 800 at the European Marine Energy Centre in Orkney, which is now grid-connected.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210860</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Regulatory, technical and financial challenges in the grid connection of wave energy devices</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In considering the grid connection of ocean wave energy devices, and in particular, the connection of large offshore arrays, there are a number of technical and economic challenges that need to addressed by wave energy device developers As device developers approach pre-commercial operation, grid connection factors will become increasingly significant in both technical and financial terms In this study, some generally applicable, non-device specific challenges are examined The costing issues involved in procuring, building and maintaining a grid connection are reviewed The technical impacts on device design and particularly on generator system selection are also examined in detail A grid connection costing case study in the Irish context is performed as a practical indicator of these issues</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/iet-rpg.2009.0187</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210861</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Characterization of the vertical evolution of the three-dimensional turbulence for fatigue design of tidal turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A system of two coupled four-beam acoustic Doppler current profilers was used to collect turbulence measurements over a 36-h period at a highly energetic tidal energy site in Alderney Race. This system enables the evaluation of the six components of the Reynolds stress tensor throughout a large proportion of the water column. The present study provides mean vertical profiles of the velocity, the turbulence intensity and the integral lengthscale along the streamwise, spanwise and vertical direction of the tidal current. Based on our results and considering a tidal-stream energy convertor (TEC) aligned with the current main direction, the main elements of turbulence prone to affect the structure (material fatigue) and to alter power generation would likely be: (i) the streamwise turbulence intensity (I-x), (ii) the shear stress, vw ` &lt;overbar>&lt;/mml:mover>, (iii) the normal stress, u&lt;mml:mo>' 2&lt;mml:mo accent={''}false{''}>&lt;overbar>&lt;/mml:mover> and (iv) the vertical integral lengthscale (L-z). The streamwise turbulence intensity, (I-x), was found to be higher than that estimated at other tidal energy sites across the world for similar height above bottom. Along the vertical direction, the length (L-z) of the large-scale turbulence eddies was found to be equivalent to the rotor diameter of the TEC Sabella D10. It is considered that the turbulence metrics presented in this paper will be valuable for TECs designers, helping them optimize their designs as well as improve loading prediction through the lifetime of the machines. This article is part of the theme issue `New insights on tidal dynamics and tidal energy harvesting in the Alderney Race'.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1098/rsta.2019.0495</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210873</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Green energy from marine algae: Biogas production and composition from the anaerobic digestion of Irish seaweed species</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Marine algae have emerged as an alternative feedstock for the production of a number of renewable fuels, including biogas. In addition to energy potential, other characteristics make them attractive as an energy source, including their ability to absorb carbon dioxide (CO2), higher productivity rates than land-based crops and the lack of water use or land competition. For Ireland, biofuels from marine algae can play an important role by reducing imports of fossil fuels as well as providing the necessary energy in rural communities. In this study, five potential seaweed species common in Irish waters, Saccorhiza polyschides, Ulva sp., Laminaria digitata, Fucus serratus and Saccharina latissima, were co-digested individually with bovine slurry. Batch reactors of 120 ml and 1000 ml were set up and incubated at 35Â°C to investigate their suitability for production of biogas. Digesters fed with S. latissima produced the maximum methane yield (335 ml g volatile solids -1 (gVS-1)) followed by S. polyschides with 255 ml gVS-1. L. digitata produced 246 ml gVS -1 and the lowest yields were from the green seaweed Ulva sp. 191 ml gVS-1. The methane and CO2 percentages ranged between 50-72% and 10-45%, respectively. The results demonstrated that the seaweed species investigated are good feedstocks candidates for the production of biogas and methane as a source of energy. Their use on a large-scale process will require further investigation to increase yields and reduce production costs. Â© 2013 Taylor &amp;amp; Francis.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1080/09593330.2013.765922</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210877</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">ADV Preview Based Nonlinear Predictive Control for Maximizing Power Generation of a Tidal Turbine with Hydrostatic Transmission</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">As the development of tidal turbines attracts more and more attention in recent years, reliable design and efficient control of tidal turbines are becoming increasingly important. However, the majority of existing tidal turbines still utilize traditional fixed ratio geared transmissions and the associated control designs focus on simple feedback controllers that use measurements or possibly estimates of the turbine itself or current local tidal profile. Therefore, the measurement and control are inevitably affected by the inherent delay with respect to the current tidal speeds. This paper proposes a novel tidal turbine with continuously variable speed hydrostatic transmissions and a nonlinear predictive controller that uses short-Term predictions of the approaching tidal speed field to enhance the maximum tidal power generations when the tidal speed is below the rated value. The controller is designed based on an offline finite-horizon continuous time minimization of a cost function, and an integral action is incorporated into the control loop to increase the robustness against parameter variations and uncertainties. A smooth second order sliding mode observer is also designed for parameter estimations in the control loop. A 150 kW tidal turbine with hydrostatic transmission is designed and implemented. The results demonstrate that the averaged generator power increases by 6.76% with this preview based nonlinear predictive controller compared with a classical non-predictive controller. Â© 1986-2012 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TEC.2019.2938062</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210887</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ireland's tidal energy resource; An assessment of a site in the Bulls Mouth and the Shannon Estuary using measured data</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The issues associated with Ireland's over reliance on fossil fuels to meet energy demands have sparked an interest in renewable energy. Renewable energy resources typically are intermittent and vary significantly in energy intensity. Tidal energy however has the advantage of predictability over large time scales and high power densities. A study of Ireland's tidal-current-energy resource has identified several viable sites. As part of this resource assessment, Acoustic Doppler Current Profilers were installed at two locations along Ireland's west coast, at a site in the Bulls Mouth and the Shannon Estuary. The Acoustic Doppler Current Profilers measured tidal current speed and direction at 30 min intervals over a 30 day period at a range of depths through the water column. This is the first time the measured data appears in the literature as it has only recently been made public. This paper presents tidal current speed and direction, frequency of occurrence of speed, tidal roses at several depths through the water column, and a comparison of theoretical tidal-current-speed profiles with measured data for a site in the Bulls Mouth and in the Shannon Estuary. The paper compares power density at both sites over a lunar month and also proposes a best fit power law exponent with the measured data through the water column. Finally, the paper presents an energetic performance comparison for a tidal current turbine operating at both sites. The data presented in this paper can be used in the design process to estimate the hydrodynamic and structural performance of a tidal current turbine operating under real-life conditions. The data can also be used to assess different control strategies and to design a tidal current turbine to suit the site-specific characteristics. Â© 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.enconman.2014.06.089</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210891</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Three-dimensionality of vertical axis tidal stream turbine and its application to efficiency improvement with supporting circular discs</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Hydrodynamic aspects on three-dimensional effects were investigated in this study for simple and convenient conversion of tidal stream energy using a Vertical-Axis Turbine (VAT). Numerical approach was made to reveal the differences of flow physics between 2-D estimation and rigorous 3-D simulation. It was shown that the 3-D effects were dominant mainly due to the variation of tip vortices around the tip region of rotor blade, causing the loss of lift for the reduction of torque for rotating turbine blade. A VAT with supporting circular discs at both ends spanwisely was then proposed to reduce the three-dimensionality and increase the structural strength as well as the power coefficient. Copyright Â© 2013 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96212075</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave resource assessment in Oregon and southwest Washington, USA</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Detailed wave energy resource assessments are necessary for the planning and design of wave energy converters. The waves in the U.S. Pacific Northwest have been identified as very energetic making this coast potentially suitable for wave energy harvesting. Several efforts to harvest this resource are under way in this region, however no long term, high resolution description of the resource is presently available. Here, the results of a 7 year hindcast are presented at a 30 arc-second resolution using the numerical models WAVEWATCH III and SWAN. The hindcast accuracy was quantified by comparing to measured buoy data yielding linear correlation coefficients similar to 0.90 for the significant wave height. This study describes the alongshore variability of the resource over the continental shelf. The general decline of the wave power with depth is explained by considerations of wave refraction and shoaling. Further, due to wave refraction, areas off the central and southwest Oregon coast are identified that show increased wave power at 50 m of water in comparison with the 250 m value. These areas also show increased temporal variability. In addition, areas with preferentially narrower wave spectra in both frequency and direction are identified off southwest Oregon. Further, general trends in the directionality of the resource indicate a systematic switch in the wave direction with latitude. The seasonality of the resource is also assessed in terms of variability and trends relevant to the planning and deployment of wave energy converters. The continental shelf is mapped in terms of the coefficient of variability, which is greater (smaller) than unity during the summer (winter) and regardless of the season smaller in southwest Oregon. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2013.11.014</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96212078</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Power Collection from Wave Energy Farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Most Wave Energy Converters (WECs) produce highly distorted power due to the reciprocal motion induced by ocean waves. Some WEC systems have integrated energy storage that overcomes this limitation, but add significant expenses to an already costly system. As an alternative approach, this article investigates the direct export option that relies on aggregate smoothing among several WECs. By optimizing the positioning of the WEC devices with respect to the incoming waves, fluctuations may be mutually canceled out between the devices. This work is based on Fred. Olsen's WEC system Lifesaver, and a WEC farm consisting of 48 devices is designed in detail and simulated. The major cost driver for the electrical export system is the required oversize factor necessary for transfer of the average power output. Due to the low power quality, this number can be as high as 20 at the entry point of the electrical system, and it is thus crucial to quickly improve the power quality so that the downstream power system is efficiently utilized. The simulations undertaken in this work indicate that a high quality power output can be achieved at the farm level, but that a significant oversize factor will be required in the intermediate power system within the farm.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/app3020420</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210236</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Parabolised model of the turbulent wake behind marine turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The extraction of hydrokinetic energy from ocean currents or tides involves the use of marine turbines generating turbulent wakes. The prediction of the wake characteristics is essential because the velocity deficit and increased levels in turbulence intensity dictate the interaction between turbines and any environment impact. A numerical methodology combining the parabolised Navier-Stokes equations with a modified actuator-disk model is presented. The main innovation of the modified actuator-disk model is that the flow is considered to be non-uniform downstream of the turbine. The numerical method is used to reproduce the experiments of Neary et al. (2013) and Mycek et al. (2014). The computational results show that the modification in the actuator-disk model aids in the reproduction of the experimental measurements. The simulations also show that increased levels in the ambient turbulence intensity cause a faster recovery in the turbulent wake, which agrees with experiments. Â© The Institution of Engineering and Technology 2015.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/iet-rpg.2014.0169</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210251</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">From wave to jet and from jet to hydrogen: A promising hybrid system</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">One of the main challenges that our society must overcome in this century is that of finding alternative energy sources to fossil fuels. These, ideally, must be inexpensive, less polluting than current fuels and available for a substantial time. One promising alternative is hydrogen, which has the great advantage that it can be produced by coupling renewable energy devices with water electrolysis. Several projects devoted to connecting photovoltaic and wind systems with electrolysis devices have been successful; however, little research has been done into the coupling of ocean wave energy converters with water electrolysis. The work here proposes a basic system that stores the energy from waves in the form of hydrogen. The WEC considered is a novel design known as a Blow-Jet, which captures waves and converts them into a water jet. The performance of the Blow-Jet is found to depend more on wavelength than on wave height. The electrolyser results show, at 0.200 A and 1.88 V, that the electrolysis of water produces 0.082 Nl h(-1) of hydrogen and a current efficiency (eta(I)) of 90.58\%. Copyright (C) 2014, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2014.03.134</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210184</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Simulation of Offshore Wind Turbine Link to the Electric Grid through a Four-Level Converter</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper is on the modulation of offshore wind energy conversion systems with full-power converter and permanent magnet synchronous generator with an AC link. The drive train considered in this paper is a three-mass model which incorporates the resistant stiffness torque, structure and tower, in the deep water, due to the moving surface elevation. This moving surface influences the current from the converters. A four-level converter is considered with control strategies based on proportional integral controllers. Although more complex, this modulation is justified for more accurate results.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210270</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave energy conversion systems: optimal localization procedure</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wave energy is a renewable and pollution-free energy source that has a potential world-wide contribution to the electricity market estimated in the order of 2,000 TWh/year, which represents about 10\% of the world's electricity consumption with an investment cost of EUR 820 billion. Sea waves have one of the highest energy densities among the Renewable Energy Sources (RES). Today, the largest problem in harvesting wave energy is obtaining reliability of the technology and bringing the cost down. The main types of wave energy converters are: - The oscillating water column, which consists of a partially submerged, hollow structure open to the sea below the water line. - Overtopping devices that collect the water of incident waves in order to drive one or more low head turbines. - Point absorbers (floating or mounted on the sea bed), which usually provide a heave motion that is converted by mechanical, magnetic and/or hydraulic systems in linear or rotational motion for driving electrical generators. -Surging devices that exploit the horizontal particle velocity in a wave to drive a deflector or to generate the pumping effect of a flexible bag facing the wave front. Obviously the amount of available energy depends on the different distribution of the wave energy on the world coastlines. The most energetic sites are situated on the west coasts of the oceans at middle latitudes. European and Australian west coasts reach amounts of 80 kW/m of available wave energy; in fact, the first ``wave farms{''} have been installed in Portugal and Scotland where the energy due to the waves reaches these highest values. The power in a wave is proportional to the square of the amplitude and to the period of the motion. Therefore, long period (>7-10 s), large amplitude (>2 m) waves have energy fluxes commonly averaging between 40 and 70 kW per m width of oncoming wave. Situated at the end of the long, stormy fetch of the Atlantic, the wave climate along the western coast of Europe is characterized by particularly high energy. In the Mediterranean basin, the annual power level off the coasts of the European countries varies between 4 and 11 kW/m, the highest values occurring in the area of the south-western Aegean Sea. In the Thyrrenian Sea, this lowest value of 4 kW/m is acceptable as a limit for possible location of an offshore wave farm. In order to identify the best sites and to optimize the location of new wave farms offshore of the coastlines of the Campania region (South of Italy), the significant wave height data set of ISPRA has been used, on which the Italian Wave Atlas is based. The wave buoys data are useful to calibrate the wave prediction model WWIII implemented by the Department of Applied Sciences of the University Parthenope, which simulates the most significant wave storm events of the last ten years. This procedure has been used to produce in the recent past a risk assessment of the Campanian coastlines to the wave impact, so it can also be used to evaluate the potential wave energy to be converted offshore of the Campanian coasts.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.2495/CP090121</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210346</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Energy conversion characteristics on floating type pendulum wave energy converter in regular waves</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Fixed type pendulum wave energy converter is a kind of movable body type wave energy converter and it was invented by Kondo and Watabe with Muroran Institute of Technology in Japan. Some researches on this device were carried out experimentally and theoretically, and its high energy conversion efficiency was shown. However, the coast which can be constructed the devise is limitted and the cost to construct the caisson occupies about 70% of all cost on this device. And also, it is difficult to keep it safety in storm condition like a typhoon. In order to solve these problems, Watabe proposed the floating type pendulum wave energy converter (FPWEC) which is moored to the seabed with some lines and carried out some research on FPWEC, however it is not enough to say that the design method for this device was established. In this paper, a FPWEC model which consists buoyancy block, pendulum and generator was made. Some tests were conducted in a two dimensional wave tank and power outputs and motions of the floating body in regular waves were measured. Copyright Â© 2011 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210558</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Integration of wind power into the German high voltage transmission grid</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ibis paper deals with the integration of wind power into the German high voltage grid. In Germany the installed wind power capacity already exceeded 19 GW and expected to reach 50 GW by the year 2020. For the connection of large offshore wind farms to the onshore AC grid DC transmission technologies can be used for which suitable submarine cables are necessary. German utilities defined grid code requirements on wind turbines spelling out the necessary grid-conform behavior. The most important obligations on wind generation plant operators concern fault-ride through and reactive power supply in steady state and during grid faults. The authors discuss the main issues contained in the revised German Grid Code released in 2006. For incorporating wind turbines and wind farms into power system stability studies, suitable models are presented. The behavior of a typical wind farm during three phase grid fault based on simulation results is shown.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210600</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Energy potential of Euripus' gulf tidal stream</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The tidal energy potential of low current tidal and marine currents is investigated in this work. Existing data on the current velocity and sea level at the Euripus' strait in Evia, Greece, is used to compute the energy yield based on contemporary turbine designs. Requirements, limitations and opportunities concerning the exploitation of low velocity tidal streams are discussed. Â© 2015 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/IISA.2015.7388041</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210665</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Electrical generators in ocean energy converters</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This chapter provides an outline of the issues confronting the designer of an ocean energy converter (OEC) when selecting or designing the electrical generator and its associated control system. It is clear that, especially for wave energy converters (WECs), this is a complex problem due to the high variance in device power take-off (PTO) type, and indeed the functionality of the generator itself within the power chain. Specification and design of the generator system in tidal energy converters (TECs) have been reviewed and shown to be highly dependent on the device, turbine and current characteristics. Both squirrel cage induction generators (SCIGs) and permanent magnet synchronous generators (PMSGs) are promising generator technologies for application in TECs, showing individual advantages and disadvantages. As important as the choice of the generator technology are the concepts to deal with the special requirements of TEC devices like marine environment, submerged operation and extended maintenance intervals. A consistent requirement in both WEC and TEC system generators is the need for variable speed control and operation. In this context, the power converter technology and controller algorithms related to this need have been introduced. Â© The Institution of Engineering and Technology 2014.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1049/PBRN017E_ch2</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210721</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An evaluation of an offshore energy installation for the Black Sea region of Turkey and the effects on a regional decrease in greenhouse gas emissions</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind power plants (OWPPs), which are not yet installed in Turkey, are becoming a popular method of energy production around the world because of their environmentally friendly nature. Thus, the installation of OWPPs should be an important agenda item in terms of Turkey's renewable energy policies as a contribution to the global greenhouse gas emission targets. This study proposes a model for installing OWPPs in a suitable part of the Black Sea region of Turkey and simulates the results. The suitable locations for OWPP installation were evaluated according to the technical and geographical conditions of this region and site criteria. Meteorological data from these locations were analyzed in the Wind Atlas Analysis and Application Program (WAsP) to determine the best location. In this study, an OWPP model with a 204.6 MW installed power capacity was proposed for the identified location, which has a wind speed of 8.77 m sâˆ’1 and a wind power density of 348 W mâˆ’2. Then, an OWPP model and regional energy transmission system was modeled using DigSilent software. The load flow analysis was performed using this model, and the results show that 7616 tons of toxic gas and 1.527 million tons of greenhouse gas could be reduced in the region in a year if the proposed OWPP were put into operation. Thus, with the installation of OWPP, this study shows that annual CO2 emissions can be reduced by 7.63% for the entire Black Sea region. Â© 2020 Society of Chemical Industry and John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd. Â© 2020 Society of Chemical Industry and John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/ghg.1963</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210743</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mooring integrity in electrification projects - Learning from the floating production sector in early years of harsh environment operations</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">There is a growing interest in electrification of offshore production assets using renewable energy devices. Typical configurations have arrays of power generating devices, located a short distance away from the platform and linked by subsea cables. To date, floating offshore wind turbines and wave energy converters have been trialed as sources of electrical power. With hulls, moorings and cables set out in close proximity, there is a unique station keeping risk profile that needs to be managed, to ensure fitness for service through the life of the field. When developing electrification schemes, there is a body of relevant research that can be accessed to help identify and control mooring risks. In the early days of North Sea floating production, the industry encountered multiple instances of accelerated mooring line degradation. The causes and mitigations were researched through joint industry projects, leading to the publication of operating guidance through OGUK, the HSE, ISO and others. This guidance, along with a series of milestone papers, offers a valuable body of learning that is available to electrification projects. In this paper, the authors survey the integrity threats and challenges affecting moorings in electrification schemes that are based around small arrays of wind turbines or wave energy converters. Through qualitative risk assessment, comparison is made to mooring integrity issues in the floating production sector. The relevance of guidance from oil and gas is reviewed. Consideration is given to the consequences of a line failure, and how in some cases these may represent intolerable risks. It is argued that a through-life integrity risk assessment is essential for successful deployments; also, that existing OGUK guidance on mooring integrity be extended, to reflect the specifics of electrification projects. Â© 2021, Society of Petroleum Engineers</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.2118/205451-MS</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210757</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Artificial reef effect in relation to offshore renewable energy conversion: State of the art</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The rapid worldwide growth of offshore renewable energy production will provide marine organisms with new hard substrate for colonization, thus acting as artificial reefs. The artificial reef effect is important when constructing, for example, scour protections since it can generate an enhanced habitat. Specifically, artificial structures can create increased heterogeneity in the area important for species diversity and density. Offshore energy installations also have the positive side effect as they are a sanctuary area for trawled organisms. Higher survival of fish and bigger fish is an expected outcome that can contribute to a spillover to outer areas. One negative side effect is that invasive species can find new habitats in artificial reefs and thus influence the native habitats and their associated environment negatively. Different scour protections in offshore wind farms can create new habitats compensating for habitat loss by offshore energy installations. These created habitats differ from the lost habitat in species composition substantially. A positive reef effect is dependent on the nature and the location of the reef and the characteristics of the native populations. An increase in surface area of scour protections by using specially designed material can also support the reef effect and its productivity. Â© 2012 Olivia Langhamer.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1100/2012/386713</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210771</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Numerical simulation on scour mechanism of Rudong offshore turbine foundation [å¦‚ä¸œæµ·ä¸Šé£ŽåŠ›æœºç»„åŸºç¡€å†²åˆ·æœºç&#x90;†æ•°å€¼æ¨¡æ‹Ÿç ”ç©¶]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this study, coupling CFD and sediment-laden two-phase flow method, a three-dimensional scour model is proposed. The scouring mechanism of wind turbine foundation is revealed base on offshore wind farm in Rudong. Numerical results show that: 1) the model can emulate the flow field characteristics around the pile well; 2) The scouring patterns are good in agreement with the on-site monitoring results; 3) The scouring depth and shape for Rudong offshore wind farm foundation are mainly controlled by the tidal velocity and duration; 4) The scour on both sides of the pile is more serious, and the scour pit range is about 2-4 times pile diameter. Â© 2021, Solar Energy Periodical Office Co., Ltd. All right reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.19912/j.0254-0096.tynxb.2020-0068</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210778</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Novel vibration-based electrical energy generators for low and variable speed turbo-machinery</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A novel class of vibration-based electrical energy generators is presented for applications in which the input rotary speed is relatively low and varies significantly over time such as wind mills, turbo-machinery used to harvest tidal flows, and the like. Current technology uses magnet and coil based rotary generators to generate electrical energy in such machinery. However, to make the generation cycle efficient, gearing or other similar mechanisms have to be used to increase the output speed. In addition, variable speed mechanisms are usually needed to achieve high mechanical to electrical energy conversion efficiency since speed variation is usually significant in the aforementioned applications. The objective of the present work is the development of electrical energy generators that do not require the aforementioned gearing and speed control mechanisms, thereby significantly reducing complexity and cost, particularly those related to maintenance and service. This novel class of electrical energy generators operates based on repeated vibration of multiple vibrating elements that are tuned to vibrate at a fixed prescribed frequency. The mechanical energy stored in the vibration elements is transformed into electrical energy using piezoelectric elements. The present generators are very simple, can efficiently operate over a very large range of input speeds, and should require minimal service and maintenance. The project is at the early stages of its development, but the analytical modeling and computer simulation studies using realistic system and component parameters indicate the potentials of this class of piezoelectric-based generators for the indicated applications.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1117/12.715017</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210785</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design of monopile foundations in sand for offshore windfarms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wind farm structures are dynamically loaded, which must be accounted for when defining soil properties for design. Depending on the load case, the load history may imply a drained, partially drained or undrained soil response which will lead to different dimensions for a selected supporting structure. This paper presents some analyses for a large diameter monopile in dense sand evaluated with both drained and undrained parameters extracted using the methodology described in Andersen (2009). Both simple limit equilibrium analyses and more complex 3D FE models are used to evaluate the pile capacity and load-displacement response. Results from the different methods are compared and discussed with respect to general trends and recommendations for better practice. Â© 2011 Taylor &amp; Francis Group, London.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210820</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Evaluation of technologies for harvesting wave energy in Caspian Sea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Ocean is one of the renewable sources of energy that can supply part of the world's energy needs and thus reduce the rate of consumption of fossil fuels and other non-renewable resources. The wave energy can be converted to electricity or other forms of usable energy. Water waves have a relatively high power density with a total global power of approximately 1-10 TW, equivalent to a large fraction of the world's current total energy consumption. This study is aimed at evaluating the existing systems for converting the wave energy into electricity with the idea in mind that they could be used in the Caspian Sea, with average wave energy of 5-14 kW/m. To achieve this, major devices in this field along with the most important design parameters are identified and analyzed. Each existing system's main features are presented in a benchmark table, where each feature is assigned a weighting factor. The total score for each energy extraction system is then obtained. The most suitable device is chosen based on the conditions of the Caspian Sea including amplitude, wavelength and frequency of the waves, the depth of the sea as well as the seabed and shore conditions. The performance and maintenance costs of the device have also contributed to the final selection. Based on the current study, point absorber wave energy converters are the most appropriate devices for harvesting wave energy in Caspian Sea. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.rser.2014.01.036</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210827</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">WAVE ENERGY POTENTIAL IN THE LATVIAN EEZ</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The present article deals with one of the alternative forms of energy - sea wave energy potential in the Latvian Exclusice Economic Zone (EEZ). Results have been achieved using a new method - VEVPP. Calculations have been performed using the data on wave parameters over the past five years (2010-2014). We have also considered wave energy potential in the Gulf of Riga. The conclusions have been drawn on the recommended methodology for the sea wave potential and power calculations for wave-power plant pre-design stage.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1515/lpts-2016-0018</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210886</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Advancement of a tidal energy converter mount through integrated design process and risk management</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The International Energy Agency Ocean Energy Systems (IEA-OES) has identified a target installed capacity worldwide of 300 GW by 2050 [1]. Verdant Power is advancing the Marine Renewable Energy (MRE) industry towards commercial tidal energy and MW-scale array projects through the development of a scalable mount that integrates life-cycle operation and maintenance (O&amp;amp;M) with an environmentally compatible and scalable turbine. The Verdant Power Kinetic Hydropower System (KHPS) is a 5th generation water-to-wire MRE system that utilizes horizontal-axis turbines installed in fast-moving tidal and river currents to generate renewable energy. The Verdant Power TriFrameâ„¢ (TF) mount is a triangular frame mount that supports three KHPS turbines. Verdant will demonstrate this system at the 5m-rotor diameter scale at its Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)-licensed Roosevelt Island Tidal Energy (RITE) Project in New York City's East River, a highly accessible and well-characterized tidal site. The technical development of the TF mount is based on an iterated and integrated design and risk management process, all geared to the evolving suite of International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) marine energy standards and which includes third-party verification of key performance measures. This paper presents an overview of the integrated design process related to innovative mounting systems for tidal energy converters (TECs) that shows potential to reduce capital and operating costs through improved performance, reliability, and maintainability. With support from the US Department of Energy (DOE) and the New York State Energy Research and Development Authority (NYSERDA), Verdant is conducting an Integrated Design Process (IDP) to develop, build, install, and operate a TF mounting structure supporting three Verdant Power Generation 5 (Gen5) KHPS turbines at the RITE Project. This full-scale, open-water project also includes a demonstration of a periodic O&amp;amp;M cycle. Along with technical performance monitoring, capital and operational cost data will also be compiled. The IDP integrates the capital mount design with the procedures and costs of the associated on-water work (OWW) operations (deployment, installation, retrieval, replacement). The IDP utilizes a risk analysis and management framework for the key components and requires close coordination with partner structural engineers, marine contractors, as well as the system supply chain for fabrication, assembly, and deployment facilities. Numerical modeling tools, component testing, and a failure modes and effects analysis (FMEA) are utilized, following the guidance outlined in International Standards and the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) Risk Management Framework. The entire process is iterated, with updated feedback from all participants, resulting in an optimized design that addresses project metrics and risk mitigation. Using IDP, a TEC mounting system design has been achieved that minimizes the time and cost on-water while ensuring structural, environmental, and operational performance. The application of consensus-based International Standards and a clear risk management framework is highlighted throughout the design process and is critical to ensuring system performance and increasing stakeholder confidence across the industry. Beyond Verdant's RITE project, as the marine energy industry advances, most near-term deployments will likely be at sites driven by supportive national and regional energy and funding policies. The utilization of an IDP, in a standards-based environment, offers a means to develop cost-effective full-scale solutions to capture the opportunities for MRE and specifically, TECs to produce competitive renewable energy. Copyright Â© 2019, Offshore Technology Conference</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.4043/29442-ms</style></electronic-resource-num></record></records></xml>