<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><xml><records><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210107</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">CREATING AN OFFSHORE FLOATING WIND ENERGY INDUSTRY IN CALIFORNIA</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The state of California stands at a crossroads where many different enablers are now coming together to spur its leadership in a new offshore wind energy industry off the west coast of the US. This paper presents the rationale for this new industry to be built from the ground up and elaborates on the development efforts recently undertaken by Principle Power Inc. (PPI) to jumpstart this important opportunity. The paper will first focus on the unique value proposition offshore wind offers to the Golden State and discuss the path the company has taken to accelerate the development of the offshore wind industry along the coast, with the proposition of a flagship project in Humboldt County.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210112</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Life cycle assessment of the offshore wind farm alpha ventus</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Due to better wind conditions at sea, offshore wind farms have the advantage of higher electricity production compared to onshore and inland wind farms. In contrast, a greater material input, leading to increased energy consumptions and emissions during the production phase, is required to build offshore wind farms. These contrary effects are investigated for the first German offshore wind farm alpha ventus in the North Sea. In a life cycle assessment its environmental influence is compared to that of Germany's electricity mix.In comparison to the mix, alpha ventus had better indicators in nearly every investigated impact category. One kilowatt-hour electricity, generated by the wind farm, was burdened with 0.137 kWh Primary Energy-Equivalent and 32 g CO2-Equivalent, which represented only a small proportion of the accordant values for the mix. Furthermore, the offshore foundations as well as the submarine cable were the main energy intensive components. The energetic and greenhouse gas payback period was less than one year.Therefore, offshore wind power, even in deep water, is compatible with the switch to sustainable electricity production relying on renewable energies. Additional research, taking backup power plants as well as increasingly required energy storage systems into account, will allow further calculation. Â© 2011 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.energy.2011.01.036</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210124</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Integrating compressed air energy storage (CAES) in floating offshore wind turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The design of an offshore energy storage system carries unknowns which need to be studied at an early stage of the project to avoid unnecessary costs of failures. These risks have led to an increasing dependence on more sophisticated mathematical models. This paper refers specifically to energy storage in the offshore wind farming industry and has the objective of proposing an adiabatic compressed air energy (A-CAES) system which would be integrated on a semi-submersible offshore wind turbine (OWT) platform. Calculations in respect to the sizing of the main sub-components of the system are included and estimates for the overall round trip efficiency are presented. Preliminary calculations to size the various parts of the energy storage system (ESS) have been carried out based on the energy availability of an offshore 8 MW wind turbine with real wind data from the North Sea. The load data to determine the lowest 12-hour demand period was taken from the Nordpool database. The calculations of the proposed conceptual design are based on an operational scenario in which the 24-hour period of a particular day is split in a 12-hour charging and 12-hour discharging cycle. For charging, a 5-bank, 2-stage compressor train is used to pressurize a number of steel cylindrical vessels with compressed air. This is followed by a process in which the compressed air is discharged across 12 hours using a 2-bank, 2-stage expander turbine. The multiple compression banks enable a modular power delivery to the air storage vessels, with the number of compressors utilized varying subject to wind availability. The two stages allowed for the air to be cooled in between the stages using heat exchangers, transferring the heat of compression to a pressurized sea water circuit. The hot water would be stored in thermally insulated vessels at 3500C to heat the inlet expanding air in the discharge period. A 70 and 100 Bar charging scenarios, both with a cushion pressure (CP) in the air storage vessel (ASV) of 10 Bar at the end of the discharge cycle have been considered. Standard performance criteria are calculated such as compression and expansion ratios, inlet and outlet temperatures for the respective expansion and compression air streams and flow rates within the heat exchangers to come up with an indicative sizing proposal for the respective turbo machinery and storage vessels making up the system. Round trip efficiencies are also calculated. The study determined that a CAES system consisting of 9 compressed air storage vessels operating with a peak pressure of 100 Bar should meet the storage requirements. It is also estimated that the entire CAES system would require around 1082 m2 of deck area on the platform to accommodate the pressure vessels, the compressor and expander trains, the heat exchanger and the hot water storage vessel. Copyright Â© 2019 ASME</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/IOWTC2019-7533</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210209</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Pathways to low carbon energy transition through multi criteria assessment of offshore wind energy barriers</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A decrease in energy resources has motivated nations around the world to shift their focus to low carbon energy transition through renewable sources of energy. Offshore wind farms have emerged as a viable resource due to their many advantages. Wind energy boasts a positive image globally but does possess certain challenges. With this consideration, this study examines the challenges and barriers involved in the implementation of offshore wind energy through multi criteria assessment. Beginning with an examination of the common barriers identified from current literature resources, this study then consults a focus group and analyzes the barriers through a multi-criteria decision making (MCDM) approach known as DEMATEL. This study considers both technical and functional barriers and it offers a particular focus on the developing nation of India, because India's energy demands are significant. The role of employing an Indian context is primarily due to the significant decrease in non-renewable energy resources. Further, developing nations like India are often hampered by the challenges of initial installation of vital clean energy sources. Few existing studies offer empirical case studies for India. Our study finds that a lack of awareness is the most influential barrier, and if that barrier can be eradicated, offshore wind energy systems may contribute to easing India's energy burdens. Hence, this study assists offshore wind engineers in exploring the technology's barriers and limitations and in securing appropriate eradication strategies. Among five different challenge dimensions, this study finds governance (D1) is the key influential dimension and Lack of awareness (B4) is the most influential factor among 25 considered factors. With these results, this study bridges the gap between engineers and top-level management to explain the some of the core issues related to the implementation of offshore wind farms. Finally, this study presents useful insights considering future enhancements and recommendations for an effective implementation of offshore wind farms with the assistance of identified influential barriers for achieving effective low carbon energy alternatives. Â© 2022 The Author</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.techfore.2022.122131</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210235</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The 44-year Mediterranean HIPOCAS wind database: A useful tool to analyse offshore extreme wind events from a long-term regional perspective</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Nowadays, many efforts are leading to use the high potential offshore wind energy resources. A detailed assessment of the offshore wind resources arises as a first-rate requirement. Most of such assessment is based on extreme offshore wind atlas generated mainly from global reanalysis and satellite data. Both sort of data show certain shortcomings related, among others, to coarse spatial resolution and time inhomogeneity issues, respectively. This snag seems to be crucial over areas such as the Mediterranean Basin, which is characterized by a complex land-sea distribution and a significant orography. The HIPOCAS Mediterranean long-term (1958-2001) wind database comes to overcome the aforementioned reanalysis shortcoming and provides a Mediterranean wind data set useful to perform extreme wind analysis. This contribution also deals with a statistical extreme wind analysis over the whole Mediterranean offshore areas. Extreme return periods and levels are obtained from annual maxima using a number of distributions. Additionally, an alternative regional statistical method based on regional L-moment statistics is also proposed. The regional technique is applied to reduce uncertainty and allows a higher number of measurements to be included in the analysis, using data from a homogeneous region instead of from a single location. The herein performed extreme wind analysis provides a detailed assessment of high wind offshore areas over the Mediterranean and constitutes a subject of great interest for evaluation of wind resources. Â© 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.coastaleng.2008.02.008</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210242</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Synergetic use of multiple scatterometers for offshore wind energy potential assessment</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The synergetic offshore wind dataset derived from a combination of scatterometers (QuikSCAT, OSCAT and ASCAT-A, B) have been utilised and validated with available buoy data. It is observed that, the mean deviation in wind speed between the co-located buoy and synergetic scatterometer data is small of the order 2\% and the power density showed a difference of 2.5\%. The combined synergetic maps of wind speed, wind power density and practical power production from two offshore wind turbines V112 3M and G128 5M have been analysed and evaluated on a seasonal and annual basis. Further, considering the available area after exclusions, conflict regions due to shipping, visual and avian exclusions, India has a net power production of 364 GW (3190 TWh/yr) for V112 3M and 516 GW (4522 TWh/yr) for G128 5M turbines at 80 m hub height. This would reduce overall carbon emissions of 3117 and 4418 million tons respectively per year. Finally, the Levelised cost of energy is computed for two optimum sites in shallow waters off Gujarat and Tamil Nadu coasts and found to be lowest of around 106.87 (sic)/MWh in Tamil Nadu site, suggesting an optimum site for wind farm development.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2019.106745</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210247</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Cooperation of Offshore Wind Farm with Battery Storage in Multiple Electricity Markets</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wind power generation plays a critical role in meeting the energy demand in Denmark. Due to increasing penetration of renewable energy, and in particular wind power, the frequency deviation has become a national problem that needs to be solved urgently to continue the positive development of renewables. In this paper, a co-optimization method of an offshore wind farm with the battery energy storage system (BESS) is proposed which enable the wind farm to participate in both days ahead (DA) electricity market and primary frequency control reserve market. The optimization problem involves the hourly bidding energy, charging and discharging status which creates a mixed integer nonlinear programming (MINLP) problem. The bilinear term is linearized using big M method in this work and thus the facilitate the conversion from a MINLP to a MILP problem. The results show that the wind farm owner can obtain more profits if they want to provide ancillary service using the proposed bidding strategy. It is expected that such proposition could ensure market and political support for continuous wind power installations in Denmark. Â© 2018 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/UPEC.2018.8541864</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210261</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The first met-mast for offshore wind farm in Korea and its remote sensing system</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper mainly deals with the estimation procedure of offshore wind power resource around Korean peninsula and the selection criteria of optimal sites for offshore wind farm. The main criteria of site selection include wind class(wind power density), sea depth, distance from the coast and the proximity of on land substation. Wind class is restricted 3 or more and Sea depth is less than 20m for economical reason. Distance from the coast is limited to 10km or more but the distance from the on land substation is restricted less than 30km. It is also described the design criteria, construction process and remote sensing system of offshore meteorological mast, which is the first installation case in Korea. Copyright Â© 2011 by the International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210265</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">AC fault ride through of modular multilevel converter VSC-HVDC transmission systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper discusses the AC fault ride through of two terminal modular multilevel converter (MMC) VSC based HVDC integration of combined offshore wind and wave farms. The combined offshore wind and wave farms are modelled as a controllable three phase voltage source connected to a 600MVA, 460kV/370kV transformer. A 31- level MMC has been selected because of acceptable harmonic attributes. Two 300kV DC submarine cables with length of 100km have been employed in this study. A voltage source has been connected in series with an inductive resistive circuit to give a short circuit ratio of 3.5. This paper finally presents a comparative simulation analysis of hysteresis based and PI based DC voltage controller for fault ride through (FRT) capability. The analysis showed that the PI method resulted in smaller overshoots and dips. A high switching frequency PWM based electromagnetic transient (EMT) model in MATLAB/Simulink was developed for the analysis. Â© 2015 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/UPEC.2015.7339823</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210274</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">2nd International Conference on Renewable Energies Offshore, RENEW 2016</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The proceedings contain 103 papers. The special focus in this conference is on Renewable Energies Offshore. The topics include: Assessing the utility and effectiveness of the IEC standards for wave energy resource characterisation; wave energy potential assessment along the west coast of Fuerteventura; trends in the available wave power at the Portuguese pilot zone; development of a numerical modelling tool for combined near field and far field wave transformations using a coupling of potential flow solvers; assessing the importance of including waves in simulations of tidal stream turbine impacts; tidal energy resource characterisation in the Dover strait by using VHF radar and ADCP measurements; assessing climate change effect in offshore wind power in the north of Portugal; regional frequency analysis of wind speed on the coast of Portugal; a methodology for the power performance assessment of floating offshore wind turbines; application of reanalysis data for offshore wind power potential assessment off the west coast of India; development of an autonomous offshore monitoring system; evaluation of offshore wind power potential of India by combining satellite and moored buoy data; high resolution monitoring for marine renewable energy; additional attenuation detection and correction of radar wave within the interior region of offshore wind farm; energy capture optimization for an adaptive wave energy converter; systems engineering applied to the development of a wave energy farm and revenue optimization for the ocean grazer wave energy converter through storage utilization.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210280</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Socio-economic, legal, and political context of offshore renewable energies</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore renewable energies have been identified as important clean sources of energy in line with sustainable development goals. However, their use can generate conflicts with other maritime activities, as well as the protection of biodiversity and the marine environment. This article analyses the influence of regulatory frameworks and ocean governance in the implementation of such devices, from a legalâ€“political point of view. In this sense, it studies how the law of the sea addresses potential international conflicts between ocean energy installations and other activities (e.g., navigation) developed by other states. It also studies the importance of preventive legal toolsâ€”marine spatial planning, strategic environmental assessment, and environmental impact assessmentâ€”to anticipate and reduce clashes with other sea users as well as environmental damages that may be caused by these structures. Likewise, this research analyses different national consent procedures and legalâ€“economic supporting schemes, to identify those that boost the implementation of such projects more quickly. Finally, the relevance of enhancing the involvement of affected coastal communities and local stakeholders in the decision-making processes, as well as in the socio-economic benefits of offshore renewable energy projects to increase their social acceptance, is also emphasized. This article is categorized under: Policy and Economics > Governance and Regulation Policy and Economics > Energy Transitions Policy and Economics > Regional and International Strategies. Â© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/wene.462</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210332</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Observer-based power forecast of individual and aggregated offshore wind turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Due to the increasing share of wind energy in the power system, minute-scale wind power forecasts have gained importance. Remote-sensing-based approaches have proven to be a promising alternative to statistical methods and thus need to be further developed towards an operational use, aiming to increase their forecast availability and skill. Therefore, the contribution of this paper is to extend lidar-based forecasts to a methodology for observer-based probabilistic power forecasts of individual wind turbines and aggregated wind farm power. To do so, lidar-based forecasts are combined with supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA)-based forecasts that advect wind vectors derived from wind turbine operational data. After a calibration, forecasts of individual turbines are aggregated to a probabilistic power forecast of turbine subsets by means of a copula approach. We found that combining the lidar- and SCADA-based forecasts significantly improved both forecast skill and forecast availability of a 5 min ahead probabilistic power forecast at an offshore wind farm. Calibration further increased the forecast skill. Calibrated observer-based forecasts outperformed the benchmark persistence for unstable atmospheric conditions. The aggregation of probabilistic forecasts of turbine subsets revealed the potential of the copula approach. We discuss the skill, robustness and dependency on atmospheric conditions of the individual forecasts, the value of the observer-based forecast, its calibration and aggregation, and more generally the value of minute-scale power forecasts of offshore wind. In conclusion, combining different data sources to an observer-based forecast is beneficial in all regarded cases. For an operational use one should distinguish between and adapt to atmospheric stability.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.5194/wes-7-2099-2022</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210340</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Grid-Connected Wind Power Plants: A Survey on the Integration Requirements in Modern Grid Codes</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In recent years, the integration of wind power generation facilities, and especially offshore wind power generation facilities, into power grids has increased rapidly. Therefore, the grid codes concerning wind power integration have become a major factor in ensuring power system reliability. This work compares grid codes about wind power integration around the world. The grid codes of Denmark, Ireland, the U.K., Germany, Spain, China, the U.S., Canada, and other countries are considered. The most important of these grid codes concern reactive power, frequency regulation, fault ride through, and power quality. Several grid codes also address communication, ramp rate, and offshore wind power plants. This work provides information on the future of grid code requirements for offshore wind power integration, which helps the system operators ensure the safe operation of a power system with a high penetration of wind power generation. Â© 1972-2012 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TIA.2019.2934081</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210342</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modelling of a controlled doubly fed induction machine for the use in offshore wind power plants</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">After a brief overview of the actual state of wind energy and planned offshore projects in Germany, state of the art wind power generators are described. It is explained, that a favourite generator system for such offshore applications is the Doubly-Fed Induction Machine (DFIM), due to its advantages in weight and operation. Furthermore, a State-Space-Equation-Model of the DFIM in field oriented coordinates is derived and discussed. This coordinate system offers the possibility of decoupled control of active and reactive power. The structures of the control loops are presented. To enable an effective simulation of large wind farms, two reduction steps can be performed: 1) The differential equation of the rotor is reduced by compensating the transient rotor time constant with the rotor current control. 2) Furthermore, the differential equation of the stator is reduced by means of the Singular Perturbation Method. The derived first order model can appropriately describe the dynamics of controlled DFIM in multi machine installations.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210353</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Small-Signal Stability Analysis of Offshore AC Network Having Multiple VSC-HVDC Systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents a methodology to perform small-signal analysis of an offshore ac network, which is formed by interconnecting several offshore wind power plants. The off-shore ac network is connected with different onshore ac grids using point-to-point voltage-source-converter high-voltage direct current (VSC-HVDC) transmission links. In such a network, each offshore VSC-HVDC converter operates in grid-forming mode. In this paper, the offshore VSC grid-forming control is enhanced by using a frequency and voltage droop scheme in order to establish a coordinated grid control among the offshore converters. A small signal model of the offshore ac network is developed that includes the high-voltage alternating current cables' model, the converters' current, and voltage-control model, the frequency droop scheme, and the voltage droop scheme. Based on this model, an eigenvalue analysis is performed in order to study the influence of the frequency and voltage droop gains on overall offshore ac network stability. Finally, theoretical analysis is validated by performing nonlinear dynamic simulation.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TPWRD.2017.2725982</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210355</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Adaptive Droop Control Strategy Participating in Power Grid Frequency Regulation for VSC-MTDC Transmission System</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In view of the voltage source converter based multi-terminal direct current (VSC-MTDC) transmission system connected with large-scale offshore wind farms, the power distribution mechanism of the conventional DC voltage droop control is derived, and the impacts of the control strategy on the frequency of receiving grid are analyzed. The DC capacitor of the VSC-MTDC system is used for energy storage, and the frequency of receiving grid is coupled with the DC voltage of VSC-MTDC system. Then an adaptive droop control strategy participating in the primary frequency regulation is proposed. The strategy can adjust the DC voltage droop coefficient in real time according to the AC system frequency deviation, which makes each converter station rapidly adjust its own power output without communication. Thus the AC system frequency can be stabilized in a reasonable range. Finally, a five-terminal VSC-MTDC system is formed in the DigSILENT/PowerFactory simulation software, and the effectiveness of the proposed method is verified by results of three simulation examples. Â© 2017 Automation of Electric Power Systems Press.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.7500/AEPS20160729004</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210359</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Study on Static Pressure Sedimentation for Thick-Walled Bucket Foundation in Silty Clay [ç²‰è´¨é»&#x8f;åœŸä¸­åŽšå£&#x81;ç­’åž‹åŸºç¡€é&#x9d;™åŽ‹æ²‰æ”¾é˜»åŠ›ç ”ç©¶]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Bucket foundation, as an emerging type of supporting structure for offshore wind turbines, has attracted much attention in the field of offshore wind power in China owing to its superior bearing capacity and efficient construction method. Thin-walled bucket foundations have been successfully installed in Jiangsu maritime space and achieved good economic benefits. In this study, considering the upsizing of wind turbines and the far-reaching of wind fields, a thick-walled bucket foundation is proposed. Using a concrete skirt instead of a steel skirt, the thick-walled bucket foundation can effectively reduce the cost and prevent the buckling problem of the steel skirt during construction, transportation, and installation. However, the increase in the skirt's thickness leads to greater sinking resistance. An accurate calculation of the penetration resistance is the key to the successful installation of the thick-walled bucket foundation. Therefore, static pressure tests of thin- and thick-walled models were conducted to measure the subsidence resistance and soil pressure at the sidewalls and ends. By comparing the similarities and differences of the sinking resistance of the two models, the coefficients of the thin-walled sinking resistance calculation formula were optimized, and the calculation method of the thick-walled sinking resistance was proposed. The arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian method was verified and used to simulate the dynamic continuous sinking process of the thick-walled test. Results show that the growth of the skirt's thickness compacts the end soil and causes the end soil pressure to increase while the side soil is disturbed. Thus, the lateral soil pressure decreases. The cone penetration test(CPT)is recommended to calculate the sinking resistance of the thick-walled bucket foundation when the end resistance coefficient is 0.7, and the skin friction coefficient is 0.03. For the thin-walled bucket foundation, the end resistance and skin friction coefficients are 0.5 and 0.04, respectively. Â© 2022, Editorial Board of Journal of Tianjin University(Science and Technology). All right reserved.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.11784/tdxbz202109005</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210370</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A framework for hurricane risk assessment of offshore wind farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">We present a framework aimed at estimating the potential damage to an offshore wind farm from hurricanes. Our approach is related to assessing risks that are assumed to be fundamentally related to the estimation of wind speed exceedance probabilities at selected hub heights of wind turbines in the farm and of associated wind turbine loads. As part of this preliminary framework for risk assessment, synthetic storm tracks are first simulated over the ocean using available historical tropical storm data; then, a hurricane intensity evolution model based on thermodynamic and atmospheric environmental variables is developed for each of the tracks as they get to regions within the proximity of the chosen wind farm site. Based on this intensity model, a turbulent wind field can be simulated at locations of interest along the hurricane track. The simulated turbulent wind field may then be used to estimate wind speed exceedance probability distributions and, when combined with correlated waves, it can also be used in analysis of the response of individual turbines in a wind farm. The framework for the overall risk assessment is presented; the individual components that comprise such an assessment are described briefly in illustrative applications. Copyright Â© 2012 by ASME.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/OMAE2012-84147</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210377</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore Wind Energy - Potential for India</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper attempts to analyze energy demand scenario, especially that of almost unlimited wind energy and highlight vast potential of offshore wind energy for India in territorial water along its long coastline. Challenges to exploit this potential, financial viability of such offshore energy projects, social, environmental, and other related issues are discussed in Indian context to serve as a useful tool for policymakers to allocate resources for detailed studies for estimation and its ultimate utilization to add to growing pool of renewable energy.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210384</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Opportunities and risks of steel fibres in grouted joints</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Grouted Joints are typical means of connecting the supporting structure with the foundation piles of Offshore Wind Energy Converters (OWECs). The resulting gap of two steel pipes with different diameters is filled using a mineral-bound, high strength grout. Because of the special offshore conditions the grout material needs a high reliability and robustness against segregation for the pumping process. Up to now high performance concrete can be used with compressive strength exceeding 100 N/mm2. Because of the brittleness and risk of cracking in case of high performance grout material, discussions have come up in Germany whether to use steel fibres due to their crack-bridging effects. In this paper the opportunities and risks of steel fibres in Grouted Joints are described regarding to their effects on the fresh and hardenend concrete properties as well as the load-deformation behaviour of the construction. It is necessary to balance needs for the controllability of the filling process and the risk of cracking of hardened grout materials with and without fibre reinforcement. To determine the influence of steel fibres on the workability, slump flow tests with and without blocking effects were made. Currently, it is not recommended to use steel fibres for structural purposes. High doses of steel fibres, which produce an identifiable improvement of the load bearing behaviour result in critical problems for the filling process.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210390</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Corrosion protection design according to DNV GL standards and recommended practices - Possibilities and boundaries</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">DNV GL has harmonised the different standards, recommended practiced and guidelines providing holistic guidance for the design and erection of offshore wind farms. Our world-wide experience leads to profound information on cathodic protection systems design for typical foundation structures of wind farms, on the inside and outside of monopiles and jacket types. Recommendation will be given on choice of coating systems, corrosion allowance, the necessity of pre-qualification, and the effects of durability of these. Also, the danger of microbiologically induced corrosion or the effects of high (tidal) currents will be presented. Guidance and justifications for the recommended approaches is given. We will present the possibilities and freedom of the designer finding site specific solutions while following these standards and recommendations to find the optimised site specific approach. Our standards and recommendations shall not be used as cookbooks, but engineering knowledge is needed applying the information contained. Merely following the text is not sufficient. We will provide guidance on the issue of optimizing the corrosion protection system in the area of conflict between OPEX and CAPEX. We will present the possibilities for the choice of corrosion protection strategies for installation phase with possible times without the final corrosion protection system (ICCP or GACP) being in place. We will provide emphasise the interaction of design and corrosion protection with special respect to the fatigue design, since the design of wind turbine structures fatigue driven in large areas. The audience will be able to learn about the latest standardisation processed within DNV GL for offshore wind with an emphasis on corrosion protection. They will learn about our experience gained with certifying offshore projects around the world. They will learn about the progress being made and the lessons learnt from the past for their own projects. Â© 2017 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210415</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Public estimates of support for offshore wind energy: False consensus, pluralistic ignorance, and partisan effects</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Meeting future energy demands will require large-scale implementation of renewable energy projects. If one of these energy sources offshore wind becomes a common sight off coastlines, consideration of local public opinion and action will be critical. Previous research from the social sciences has lacked depth in examining the underlying factors that shape public opinion towards offshore wind development. The current research brings a new perspective to the literature by showing that how members of the public perceive support among others relates to their own opinions of offshore wind energy. We report results from two surveys. The first focused on opinion formation relating to offshore wind in general among New England residents, while the second focused on a specific offshore wind project in Rhode Island. We find evidence that both supporters and opponents of offshore wind underestimate levels of support among others, indicating a pluralistic ignorance effect and false consensus effect, respectively. We also find distinct patterns of perceived support among self-identified Republicans and Democrats. The findings hold important implications for policymakers and developers in understanding the nature of public support and opposition for offshore wind energy, particularly with respect to individuals' willingness to publicly engage with offshore wind projects.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.enpol.2017.10.005</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210421</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">GMS develops underwater ROV</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The creators of a new underwater remotely operated vehicle (ROV) claim almost any problem with the device can be repaired in less than 20 minutes. Global Marine Systems (GMS), an underwater cable company, built the Predator to help with operations on offshore wind farms. In order to make the Predator easier to maintain, GMS increased the number of components to make them easier to replace. For example, certain cables are held in place with two connectors rather than one so they can be removed without having to take the device apart further. The Predator is specifically designed to work in the difficult conditions associated with offshore wind farms. It has a high power-to-weight ratio to allow it to navigate strong currents and a number of integrated sensors to deal with low visibility. GMS is building five units to assist with the installation and repair of its cable laying and plans to use them on the planned London Array wind farm in the Thames Estuary and on a project in Asia. The unit is expected to sell for around Â£64,000.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210431</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design forces for offshore nuclear power plant construction.</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore nuclear plants, or other major offshore construction requires understanding the effects of environmental forces of a nature and magnitude markedly different from conventional onshore construction. Once these forces are understood, the facilities are amenable to design by essentially state-of-the-art analyses (sophisticated though they may be). However, without an understanding of the type, magnitude, and frequency of the environmental conditions one cannot define suitable design loads. (A)</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210433</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Reliability analysis of offshore wind turbine support structures under extreme ocean environmental loads</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Reliability analysis of jacket type offshore wind turbine (OWT) support structure under extreme ocean environmental loads was performed. Limit state function (LSF) of OWT support structure is defined by using structural dynamic response at mud-line. Then, the dynamic response is expressed as the static response multiplied by peak response factor (PRF). Probabilistic distribution of PRF is found from response time history under design significant wave load. Band limited beta distribution is used for internal friction angle of ground soil. Wind load is obtained in the form of thrust force from commercial code called Bladed and then, applied to tower hub as random load. In numerical example, response surface method (RSM) is used to express LSF of jacket type support structure for 5 MW OWT. Reliability index is found using first order reliability method (FORM). Â© 2014 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.renene.2014.11.052</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210445</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The potential of wind power generation at Gozo North-Offshore</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The potential power generation at Gozo North-Offshore was estimated for a hypothetical wind farm composed of 21 x 2MW wind turbines that can be accommodated within the site constraints. Wind from directions that are not influenced by the landmass - 270Â° (due west) through 0Â° (north) to 120Â° (east south-east) would generate 100 GWh annually, or 4.3% of power station generation. The particular direction - north-westerly - contributes 71.5 GWh emphasising the particular local wind regime. Wind from directions that may be affected by the landmass, i.e. 120Â° (east south-east) to 270Â° (due west), would have a potential of 48 GWh. It is recommended that the potential be confirmed through wind measurements at a representative point such as the seaward edge of il-Qortin tan-Nadur on the north Gozo shoreline.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210446</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Prospects for generating electricity by large onshore and offshore wind farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The decarbonisation of energy sources requires additional investments in renewable technologies, including the installation of onshore and offshore wind farms. For wind energy to remain competitive, wind farms must continue to provide low-cost power even when covering larger areas. Inside very large wind farms, winds can decrease considerably from their free-stream values to a point where an equilibrium wind speed is reached. The magnitude of this equilibrium wind speed is primarily dependent on the balance between turbine drag force and the downward momentum influx from above the wind farm. We have simulated for neutral atmospheric conditions, the wind speed field inside different wind farms that range from small (25 km2) to very large (105 km2) in three regions with distinct wind speed and roughness conditions. Our results show that the power density of very large wind farms depends on the local free-stream wind speed, the surface characteristics, and the turbine density. In onshore regions with moderate winds the power density of very large wind farms reaches 1 W m-2, whereas in offshore regions with very strong winds it exceeds 3 W m-2. Despite a relatively low power density, onshore regions with moderate winds offer potential locations for very large wind farms. In offshore regions, clusters of smaller wind farms are generally preferable; under very strong winds also very large offshore wind farms become efficient. Â© 2017 IOP Publishing Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1088/1748-9326/aa5d86</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210447</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Large-scale offshore wind energy installation in northwest India: Assessment of wind resource using Weather Research and Forecasting and levelized cost of energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In India, there are plans for 5 GW of installed capacity of wind power by 2022. This study establishes that the wind resource along the west coast of Gujarat is sufficient for offshore wind farms of between 500 MW to 2 GW rated power to be operated with capacity factors of 40% to 54%. For the majority of sites, a levelized cost of energy (LCOE) in the range 68 to 86 Â£/MWh can be achieved with installation on floating support structures. The LCOE is up to 3.2 Â£/MWh greater for installation on bed-fixed structures closer to shore. The wind resource and energy yield are predicted using Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF). Wind speed occurrence is predicted to within 1.3% for multiple sites simultaneously, and this provides wind turbine energy yield to within 3.4%. Wind speeds occurring due to sea breeze are accurately predicted and contribute 6.2% of annual energy generation at the nearshore locations and 3.8% at the deeper water offshore sites. While these events improve the viability of nearshore locations, floating installations offer lower LCOE for most locations along the Gujarat coast. Â© 2020 The Authors. Wind Energy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1002/we.2566</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210455</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Fault Transient Study of a Meshed DC Grid With High-Temperature Superconducting DC Cables</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents the DC fault transient study of a meshed DC grid with high-temperature superconducting (HTS) HVDC cables to integrate offshore wind power. A four-terminal meshed DC grid model with a Â±100 kV DC voltage rating is developed. DC circuit breakers (DCCBs) are implemented in the DC grid to deal with DC cable faults. To conduct the fault transient study, the fault scenarios with different fault locations and protection delays are studied. The sensitivity study versus different DC fault locations reveals that the faults on the faulted cable will not cause the quenching of healthy cables. The sensitivity study considering different DC fault protection delays demonstrates that the HTS cables have a current-limiting effect and the long delay of DC fault protection does not result in large fault current and the quenching of healthy cables. Extensive simulations in PSCAD/EMTDC validate the founding. Â© 1986-2012 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/TPWRD.2022.3177406</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210504</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">On motion analysis and elastic response of floating offshore wind turbines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Wind energy industry is expanded to offshore and deep water sites, primarily due to the stronger and more consistent wind fields. Floating offshore wind turbine (FOWT) concepts involve new engineering and scientific challenges. A combination of waves, current, and wind loads impact the structures. Often under extreme cases, and sometimes in operational conditions, magnitudes of these loads are comparable with each other. The loads and responses may be large, and simultaneous consideration of the combined environmental loads on the response of the structure is essential. Moreover, FOWTs are often large structures and the load frequencies are comparable to the structural frequencies. This requires a fluidâ€“structureâ€“fluid elastic analysis which adds to the complexity of the problem. Here, we present a critical review of the existing approaches that are used to (i) estimate the hydrodynamic and aerodynamic loads on FOWTs, and (ii) to determine the structuresâ€™ motion and elastic responses due to the combined loads. Particular attention is given to the coupling of the loads and responses, assumptions made under each of the existing solution approaches, their limitations, and restrictions, where possible, suggestions are provided on areas where further studies are required. Â© 2020, The Author(s).</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1007/s40722-019-00159-2</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210538</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Food safety during seaweed cultivation at offshore wind farms: An exploratory study in the North Sea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Multi-use in ocean space, and seas, entails the co-location of different industries or technologies and their corresponding activities that take place at the same time in a specific location. This concept focuses on finding solutions to tackle global challenges in food security. However, the effects that seaweed cultivation at offshore wind farms may have on food and feed safety are less readily addressed. This study examined whether currently available food and feed safety standards for seaweed can be applied to multi-use activities at sea. The focus was on the combined use of seaweed cultivation at an offshore wind farm in the North Sea. Literature regarding hazards in seaweed was screened, and standards were evaluated. Expert elicitation on seaweed cultivation was retrieved via in-depth interviews and a workshop. Results showed that although some food safety hazards may be more apparent for seaweed cultivation such as toxic metals (e.g., arsenic, cadmium) and iodine, others may become relevant when considering multi-use (e.g., allergens, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons, toxic metabolites). Key factors for food safety include the location of seaweed cultivation, handling and processing of seaweed, and seaweed testing. Public standards, the Food Safety System Certification 22000 standard, and the Marine Stewardship Council/Aquaculture Stewardship Council standard are recommended for the food and marine sectors to consider when determining standards to implement. This case study provides an example of how to address seaweed food and feed safety in a multi-use scenario in the North Sea. We recommend additional case studies for other multi-use at sea scenarios. Â© 2020 The Authors</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.marpol.2020.104082</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210573</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modeling of twin-turbine systems with vertical axis tidal current turbine: Part IItorque fluctuation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">We recently showed the advantage of using a numerical system to extract energy from tidal currents by developing a new twin-turbine model (Li and Calisal, 2010a). Encouraged by this result, we decided to use this model to study another important characteristic of the turbine system, torque fluctuation. This effort is summarized in this paper. The torque fluctuation is expected to reduce the fatigue life of tidal current turbines, though potentially it also may deteriorate the power quality of tidal current turbines. In this paper, after reviewing the twin-turbine model, we use it to predict the torque fluctuation of the system with the same configurations as we used to study the power output in Li and Calisal (2010a). Specifically, we investigate the torque fluctuation of twin-turbine systems with various turbine parameters (e.g.; relative distance between two turbines and incoming flow angle) and operational condition (e.g.; tip speed ratio). The results suggest that the torque of an optimally configured twin-turbine system fluctuates much less than that of the corresponding stand-alone turbine, under the same operating conditions. We then extensively compare the hydrodynamic interaction's impact on the torque fluctuation and the power output of the system. We conclude that the hydrodynamic interactions pose more constructive impacts on the torque fluctuation than on the power output. The findings indicate that the optimally configured counter-rotating system should be a side-by-side system, and that the optimally configured co-rotating system should have the downstream turbine partially in the wake of the upstream turbine depending on the detailed configuration of the turbines. Furthermore, one must balance the optimal torque fluctuation against the optimal power output. Â© 2011 Published by Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2010.11.025</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210575</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Frequency response tuning for a two-body heaving wave energy converter</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This study investigates frequency response tuning for a two-body heaving wave energy converter. The wave energy converter presented is a scale model "spar-float" configuration to be tested at the National Research Council Institute for Ocean Technology, St. Johns, Newfoundland. The purpose of these tests is to validate a novel tuning mechanism which affords active adjustment of the spar natural frequency. In this work, a systematic optimization procedure is used to demonstrate the utility of this tuning mechanism. The spar geometry is parameterized so that the reference depth can be input to a simplified heaving dynamics model which utilizes the long-wavelength approximation. Closed form solutions to the linear heaving dynamics model are used to establish objective functions. For a range of wave frequencies corresponding to the wave tank capabilities, optimal natural frequencies for the spar are computed. The results show that an ability to vary the spar's natural heaving frequency is indeed beneficial, and that significant power absorption benefits can be attained at low wave frequencies using the suggested tuning mechanism to produce these frequency adjustments. Copyright Â© 2008 by The International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210578</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Efficiency of HVAC power transmission from offshore-windmills to the grid</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">For large offshore windparks far away from the coast, not only the investment costs of the transmission system but, moreover, the costs of the transmission tosses play a decisive role for the economy of the total power system. In this paper some basic problems in determining the losses of HVAC transmission systems are discussed, taking into account the longitudinal distributions of current and temperature as well as the time-dependence of the power flow. Â© 2003 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/PTC.2003.1304285</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210581</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Simplified fatigue assessment of offshore wind support structures accounting for variations in a farm</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The optimal design and preliminary strength assessment of offshore wind support structures gains growing interest given the potential to drive the costs further down. This study develops a framework for Fatigue Limit State (FLS) estimations of monopiles in a simple and quick manner so as to address site variations in an offshore wind farm (OWF). Additionally, it serves the need for optimisation of all structures in the farm in the early design phase. The framework consists of two elements: (i) a stand-alone model that predicts in a simplified way the damage caused by the varying loading and (ii) correction factors that increase its accuracy. The concept of the model relies on the analytical approximation of the dynamic response, thus by-passing time consuming numerical processes. The above step renders it a simplified version of the conventional frequency-domain. Its benchmarking against the time-domain aeroelastic code DNV-GL Bladed shows fair accuracy but also certain systematic errors. These are tackled by correction factors that are generated at a reference wind turbine, where time-domain detailed assessment is necessary. Once calculated, they are transferred to the positions of interest in the farm. The method works well for lower parts of the support structure, making it suitable for monopile analysis and design.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210582</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Joint evaluation of the future wave and wind energy close to Bulgaria and Romania coastlines</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The importance of this study is to underline the fact that the wind energy potential in the western part of the Black Sea basin can be considered significant, while the wave energy is lower in comparison with oceans. However, in winter time when energy consumption in Bulgaria and Romania is high, the wave energy presents the highest values. The aim of this research paper is to draw a comprehensive picture regarding the wave and wind energy near Bulgaria and Romania coastlines. More precisely, six locations were studied. Regarding the geographical location, the studied points are located in the range 42Â°N to 45.2Â°N and 27Â°E to 30Â°E as follows: three points are near to the Bulgariaâ€™s coastline and the other three close to Romaniaâ€™s coastline. In this study, the wind conditions were analyzed at 10-meter height. The data for the wind analysis were provided by the Regional Climate Model (RCM) from Euro-Cordex database (EUR-11) and covers three intervals. All intervals cover 30-year of data as follows: Historical dataset (01 January 1976 to 31 December 2005), near future RCP8.5 scenario (01 January 2021 to 31 December 2050) and future RCP8.5 scenario (01 January 2071 to 31 December 2100). The wave analysis was conducted on the same intervals but using data coming from SWAN model. Finally, by analyzing the resulted coming from this joint evaluation it can be concluded that the presented analysis provides a more comprehensive picture regarding the future wind and wave energy resources in the coastal environment of Bulgaria and Romania, compared with historical period. Â© 2019, International Multidisciplinary Scientific Geoconference. All rights received.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.5593/sgem2019/4.1/S17.038</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210587</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The effects of mean wind speed uncertainty on project finance debt sizing for offshore wind farms</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Financing costs for offshore projects depend, among many other variables, on the quality of mean wind speed predictions. Financial institutions determine the amount of debt that can be reasonably supported by the project, based on probabilistic cash flow metrics derived from estimated mean wind speeds. Within the offshore wind industry, it is widely believed that longer wind resource campaigns or more precise wind measurement devices that decrease mean wind speed uncertainty lead to lower LCOE values. This paper shows that this is not always true, while a decrease in mean wind speed uncertainty may result in better financing conditions, it typically requires higher development expenditure. We build a theoretical cost modelling framework, which includes detailed project financing constraints, and then apply this to an industrial case study to analyse project financing of different types of offshore wind farms. We show that developers need to find the right balance between a decrease in financing costs and an increase in development expenditure. For projects limited by the maximum gearing or with an unfavourable trade-off between the development expenditure and the increased P90 annual energy production, more precise resource estimation can result in higher LCOE values. This paper suggests a new way of understanding the effects of wind resource assessment campaigns by integrating project finance constraints into cost calculations and highlighting the importance of detailed cost modelling for optimal design of offshore wind farms. Â© 2019 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.113419</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210611</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Risk Averse Optimal Operation of Coastal Energy Hub Considering Seawater Desalination and Energy Storage Systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An optimal day-ahead operation of a microgrid based on coastal energy hub is presented in this paper. The proposed CEH included wind turbine, photovoltaic unit, combined cooling, heat and power, and seawater desalination. The purpose of the optimization is minimization of the operational and environmental costs considering several technical limitations. The CEH includes an ice storage conditioner together with an energy storage system, i.e. thermal energy storage system. Particularly, the impacts of an innovative rechargeable and emerging ESS that is solar-powered compressed air energy storage is scrutinized, on the efficiency and operational and pollution costs of the CEH. It is clear that there is an intrinsic deviation between predicted and actual uncertainty variables in MG. This paper presents a bi-level stochastic optimal operation model based on risk averse strategy of information gap decision theory to overcome this information gap and to help Microgrid operator. To reduce the complexity of the proposed model, Karush-Kuhn-Tucker method is used for converting the bi-level problem into a single level. The Augmented Epsilon Constraint method is used to deals with multi objective optimization problem to harvest the maximum horizon of the uncertainties of the parameters. The proposed model implemented the Time of Use program as a price-based demand response program. Finally, the efficacy of the SPCAES for minimizing the operational cost and pollutions in the dayahead operation is depicted by implementation of the presented model on the typical CEH. Â© 2022 University of Mohaghegh Ardabili.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.22098/joape.2022.8777.1614</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210640</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Giant wind power sockets installed in the north sea</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">An offshore wind capacity of 100-13,000 Mw is expected to play a major role in Germany's transition to sourcing 80% of its power from renewables by 2050. ABB has installed the DolWind1 offshore wind connector platform, which is claimed as the world's highest-voltage offshore converter station in the North Sea. The 320 kv station has an 800-Mw power transmission capacity and will convert alternating current from three wind farms off the coast of Germany into high-voltage direct current for transmission to the mainland. At the same time, Siemens Energy finished installing the 576-Mw HVDC HelWin1 offshore platform, also in the North Sea, to link two offshore wind farms (Nordsee Ost and Meerwind) to the mainland. Both projects are now expected to be fully commissioned in 2014.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210643</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Explainable AI-driven net-zero carbon roadmap for petrochemical industry considering stochastic scenarios of remotely sensed offshore wind energy</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Recently, several countries have focused on industrial decarbonization to ensure that the net emissions of carbon dioxide reach zero and contribute to decreasing the global mean temperature. This study aims to investigate the feasibility of a net-zero carbon roadmap for the petrochemical industry by 1) developing an explainable artificial intelligence (XAI)-based generative model to produce stochastic scenarios for offshore wind power in an elec-trical grid, and 2) conducting techno-economic and environmental assessments for forecasting models that define offshore wind power networks. Firstly, data processing techniques were utilized on remotely sensed offshore wind speed datasets and energy data obtained from petrochemical industrial parks. Second, a generative model was designed using a variational autoencoder (VAE) to produce different forecast scenarios of offshore wind power. Third, stochastic scenarios were developed by considering behavioral characteristics of offshore wind power with stochastic scenario uncertainties. Finally, we investigated the techno-economic and environmental assessments of the proposed renewable energy networks. Comparing to the case of offshore wind power in 2022, The proposed XAI-driven net-zero carbon roadmap indicated that the total cost of electricity generation and fossil fuel cost with carbon capture and storage (CCS) can be reduced by 4\% and 42\% with 41\% reduction of CO2 emission. Ultimately, this may be implemented in industrial parks to aid in efforts towards carbon neutrality.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134793</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210646</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Review of VSC HVDC connection for offshore wind power integration</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Voltage Source Converter (VSC) High Voltage Direct Current (HVDC) connection has become a new trend for long distance offshore wind power transmission. It has been confirmed by a lot of research that the maximum distance of a High Voltage Alternative Current (HVAC) sub-marine cable transmission system is limited due to surplus charging current of the cables. The VSC HVDC transmission system has the ability to overcome the limitation and offers other advantages over the HVAC transmission system. This paper is to review the VSC HVDC transmission technology and its application for offshore wind power integration. Firstly, the main components, configuration and topology of the VSC HVDC transmission system are described. Secondly, the converter control system and control strategies are presented. Following that, the capabilities of the VSC HVDC technology are described. Finally, the focus is given on the control methods of the VSC HVDC transmission system for fulfilling grid code requirements concerning Low Voltage Ride-Through (LVRT) and frequency regulation. Â© 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All Rights Reserver.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.rser.2016.01.064</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210648</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Current status and future trends in the operation and maintenance of offshore wind turbines: A review</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Operation and maintenance constitute a substantial share of the lifecycle expenditures of an offshore renewable energy farm. A noteworthy number of methods and techniques have been developed to provide decision-making support in strategic planning and asset management. Condition monitoring instrumentation is commonly used, especially in offshore wind farms, due to the benefits it provides in terms of fault identification and performance evaluation and improvement. Incorporating technology advancements, a shift towards automation and digitalisation is taking place in the offshore maintenance sector. This paper reviews the existing literature and novel approaches in the operation and maintenance planning and the condition monitoring of offshore renewable energy farms, with an emphasis on the offshore wind sector, discussing their benefits and limitations. The state-of-the-art in industrial condition-based maintenance is reviewed, together with deterioration models and fault diagnosis and prognosis techniques. Future scenarios in robotics, artificial intelligence and data processing are investigated. The application challenges of these strategies and Industry 4.0 concepts in the offshore renewables sector are scrutinised, together with the potential implications of early-stage project integration. The identified technologies are ranked against a series of indicators, providing a reference for a range of industry stakeholders. Â© 2021 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en14092484</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210650</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Underwater noise due to pile driving: A challenge both for the installation of offshore wind energy farms and for numerical simulation [Unterwasser-Rammschall: Eine Herausforderung bei der Errichtung von Offshore-Windparks und fÃ¼r die numerische Simulation]</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind energy is a key technology towards the extension of renewable energy. State of the art foundations for wind turbines are based on pile driving, where steel piles are driven deeply into the seafloor by a hydraulic hammer. As a result of this pile driving, significant sound emissions into the surrounding water column occur that can have harmful effects on marine life, like e.g. the harbor porpoise. At present, various sound mitigation measures are being developed and tested under offshore conditions. Within the scope of the research project "BORA - Berechnung von Offshore-Rammschall", a profound model to predict near and far field sound levels with respect to varying foundation structures as well as different sound mitigation measures is being developed. Extensive offshore tests serve as model validation. This article provides insight into the pile driving noise problematic and the current state of research of the BORA project.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210714</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Integrating Modular Hydrogen Fuel Cell Drives for Ship Propulsion: Prospectus and Challenges</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper proposes a new drive system for the ship propulsion. The drive power for propelling ship varies from few MW in a small cruise ship to hundreds of MW for large cargo ships. A typical cruise ship has a 6 MW drive whereas a cargo ship has 80 MW drive. Combustion drives are not sustainable and environment friendly. An idea of electric drive system using hydrogen fuel cell and necessary storage has been proposed. The hydrogen reformer develops hydrogen fuel cell using off-shore renewables like Wind, Wave and Solar power but the power handling capability of this fuel cell system (100 kW) restricts the application to the propulsion drives of several MW. The detail drive scheme describing; how multiple modular hydrogen fuel cell drives are integrated to develop variable power. The different options available for the propulsion system and factors affecting the choice are discussed in detail. Also, how such modular drives are helpful in controlling torque and power requirements is discussed. Replacement of electric drive reduces volume and weight of the ship and the available volume can be utilized for the storage and reform systems. The proposed paper will give a remarkable concept to overcome the challenges of utilizing hydrogen fuel cell to the larger scale and in future it can be extended to all other applications.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210776</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A road map for renewable energy integration with subsea processing systems</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper proposes a road map for the integration of renewable energy supply to power subsea processing systems. To replace the traditional power supply, like fossil fuel-based generators or grid power, a wind turbine generator (WTG) operating on a islanded mode has been introduced and discussed. A review of the state of the art of WTGs is performed, primarily focused on power and controls aspects, with identification of the main technological gaps left to achieve wind-powered subsea processing. To fully assess the renewable energy integration and current gaps, a study case is proposed which addresses a subsea compression train powered by offshore wind. A thorough analysis is conducted, with meteorological conditions based on the NCS (Norwegian Continental Shelf), where gas line packing is proposed as an innovative means of energy storage. Finally, an economic analysis as well as a CO2 emission estimate is presented to demonstrate the benefits of the proposed road map. Some further discussions and conclusions are presented as well as some propositions for future works. Â© 2021, Society of Petroleum Engineers</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.2118/205433-MS</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210803</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Cluster-based DC grid control strategies applied to a European offshore grid scenario</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents a novel cluster-based approach for operation and control of multiterminal offshore high-voltage dc (HVDC) grids equipped with voltage source converter (VSC) technology. While conventional optimal power flow algorithms for ac transmission systems focus on minimizing generation costs, wind forecast uncertainties and future bulk power transfers preset by contracts between Transmission System Operators require new concepts for control of future offshore multiterminal dc (MTDC) grids. Based on already installed and future planned offshore wind farms in the North Sea, power generation of a wind farm for one time step using specific wind power curves including limited availability, wake effects and dynamic shut off as well as a method to allocate wind power plants to HVDC offshore converter stations are outlined. A sequential Newton Raphson acdc power flow algorithm was developed to cluster MTDC grids into different zones assuring an export of power from wind farm clusters to different control or market areas. The two main control objectives for MTDC grid operation are minimum grid transmission losses and fulfilment of guaranteed power transfers to specific market areas. To provide proof of the overall applicability, acdc power flow simulations were carried out on a specially developed future European Offshore Grid Scenario using real forecasted offshore wind speed data. Â© 2017 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/UPEC.2017.8232033</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210811</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">LiDAR Measurements of Wind Shear Exponents and Turbulence Intensity Offshore the Northeast United States</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This paper presents wind speed shear exponents and turbulence intensity (TI) measurements collected from light imaging, detection, and ranging instruments (LiDARs) measuring wind speeds from 40 m to 200 m above sea level and provides comparisons to industry design guidelines. The high-altitude wind speed data are unique and represent some of the first measurements made offshore in this part of the country, which is actively being developed for offshore wind. The data are used to support the New England Aqua Ventus I Floating Offshore Wind Farm to be located 17 km offshore the Northeast United States. Multiple LiDAR measurements were made using a DeepCLiDAR floating buoy and LiDARs located on a nearby island. The measured wind speed shear exponents are compared against industry standard mesoscale model outputs and offshore design codes including the American Bureau of Shipping, American Petroleum Institute, and Det Norske Veritas-Germanischer Lloyd guides. Significant variation in the vertical wind speed profile occurs throughout the year which is not addressed in design standards. Additionally, TI measurements made from the LiDAR, although not widely accepted in the scientific community, are presented and compared against industry guidelines.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1115/1.4053583</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210815</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Intermittent Fingerprints in Wind-Turbine Interactions</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">We show that the turbulent wind observed at an offshore wind farm is non-Gaussian through analysis of velocity increments, extended self-similarity and intermittency in the energy flux. We then modify Gaussian turbulence using multi-fractal fields and reproduce most of the observed non-Gaussianity. By using cubed velocities as a simplistic wind-turbine interaction model, we demonstrate how the turbulence intensity, integral length, and the intermittency seen in non-Gaussian turbulence make fingerprints on the turbine power. These fingerprints are to some extend verified by comparing measured power with simulated power using a wind-turbine interaction simulator. Â© Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg 2012.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1007/978-3-642-28968-2_52</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210822</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Revision and application of the P-Y curves to monopile foundations in cohesionless soil</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Monopiles are used as foundation for offshore wind turbines, and are open-ended steel pipe piles with large diameters. For the offshore wind energy converters of 5 MW and higher, the pile diameter may be greater than 5 m. The p-y curve method has been used extensively for the design of pile foundation design and the p-y curves for piles in cohesionless soil are determined based on field test results with a pile diameter of less than 2 m, and less than 200 cycles under cyclic loading conditions. Therefore, some modifications of p-y curves need to be considered for the monopile foundation designing of offshore wind turbine. The suitability of p-y curves for designing monopile foundation is reviewed in this study. The reduction of the subgrade reaction modulus due to pile diameter, the effect of high-cycle of cyclic lateral load and scour around the monopile are considered in the modifications of p-y curves. The deformations calculated with unmodified p-y curves seem to be under estimated.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210823</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Feasibility of offshore wind turbines for linkage with onshore green hydrogen demands: A comparative economic analysis</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Imprudent fossil fuel use for getting energy caused serious environmental problems making us necessary to seeking for alternative energy sources which are renewable and sustainable. Using wind energy is currently considered as one of feasible renewable energy sources, however, the problem of noise pollution from the sweep of turbine blades should be solved. As a feasible solution for the noise pollution problem, the construction of wind farms offshore is currently considered. In addition, many factors can change the onshore wind speed, while offshore wind has a higher wind speed and consistency, which leads to higher energy efficiency. However, the remained intermittency of wind energy makes storage media such as H2 necessary, thus, the construction of an offshore wind base H2 production system can be required for protecting the energy security. In this study, a comparative economic analysis is conducted to verify feasible equipment placements of offshore wind-based H2 production systems in various possible cases with different electrolyzer types, wind speeds, and offshore distances. An optimization study for 4 case scenarios with different regions, offshore lengths, and kinds of electrolyzers, was preliminarily conducted to find several placements that are economically optimal in common. For the optimization, a mixed-integer programming tool in Python was used, and as a result, three absolutely economical placements were selected. Then, the comparative economic analysis with considering the selected three cases was conducted indicating the most feasible placement according to the considered offshore length and wind speed, and costs ranged from 1.64 to 4.46 $ kgH2âˆ’1. From the optimal cases for considered regions (Ulsan, Magallanes), the system using alkaline electrolyzer can achieve the feasible prices for both regions, while using other types stay in ranges of the current green H2 produced by electrolysis. Â© 2023 Elsevier Ltd</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.enconman.2023.116662</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210826</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A three dimensional numerical method to study aerodynamic performance of horizontal axis wind turbine</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">It is significant to study the aerodynamic characteristics for operational capability of Horizontal Axis Wind Turbine (HAWT), as HAWT have been widely used in offshore wind energy exploitation in recent years. A 3-D numerical method was developed for the aerodynamic performance of HAWT, which combined panel method with lift line method. Flow phenomena of different blade angles of attack were researched by different tip-speed ratio parts. A 3-D panel method based on the velocity potential was introduced when tip-speed ratio is high, and blade span flow and blade interaction were all considered. Numerical calculation based on lift line method was established for the case of low tip-speed ration, which pays more attention to aspect ratio and viscosity in the high blade angle of attack. Numerical results of NREL PHASE VI wind turbine by use of the present method show good agreement with experimental results, especially for the prediction of the maximum output power of wind turbine. The method can be applied to optimize turbine configurations and characterize aerodynamic loads which act on the offshore wind turbine foundation. Copyright Â© 2010 by The International Society of Offshore and Polar Engineers (ISOPE).</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210829</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Asset modelling challenges in the wind energy sector</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The research area of asset management and cost reduction for wind energy is increasing in importance as over 100,000 turbine assets are currently installed worldwide. Such large numbers of turbine assets, with a growing offshore component, drive demand for research into improved decision support for wind farm planners and operators - as the operational risk for the assets is removed from OEMs (while under warranty) and is transferred to the power utility owners (post-warranty). The current and future demand for research in this field has thus been driven by the needs of owner/operators and central government policy formulation. The huge potential energy available from offshore wind in particular, is well known. The most crucial aspect of future deployment levels is the economic recovery of this potential energy. The long-term viability of the offshore wind power as a large scale energy solution hinges on reduction of the cost of energy, as a purely cost-based energy market would currently produce a gas- and coal-based system. Operational expenditure (OPEX) accounts for roughly 1/3 of the total cost of energy from an offshore wind farm. Crucially, the number of practical decisions and options available to an operator to reduce OPEX are limited and need to be clearly stated and understood before opportunities for cost reduction can be taken. The areas of research identified by the authors to aid in this process can be summarised into 3 key themes: 1) Asset and meteo-ocean modelling to support offshore operations and maintenance, 2) Analysis of wind farm maintenance data for asset life cycle optimization, and 3) Role of condition monitoring in decreasing OPEX. Â© 2014 CIGRE. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210850</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Policies and exploitative and exploratory innovations of the wind power industry in China: The role of technological path dependence</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Exploitative innovation emphasizes the refinement of technologies. For example, the super long and super flexible blade is an improvement on the traditional blade. Exploratory innovation emphasizes the breakthrough of technological trajectories. The floating offshore wind turbine represents a revolutionary innovation. For survival and prosperity, wind power enterprises need to excel simultaneously at both exploitative and exploratory innovations. The Chinese government has issued a series of wind power innovation policies, but their impact on exploitative and exploratory innovations is not clear. Moreover, technological path dependence describes the connection between intertemporal innovations. The prevalence of QWERTY keyboard is the best case. While the effect of technological path dependence on the impact of innovation policies is also unknown. Using micro-data from listed Chinese wind power enterprises from 2006 to 2019, this study clarifies the effects of innovation policies on exploitative and exploratory innovations, and assesses the moderating effect of technological path dependence. Our results indicate that the effects of wind power innovation policies are significant, yet ambiguous. All categories of policies improve exploitative innovation, but negatively impact exploratory innovation. Besides, technological path dependence positively moderates the positive relationship between policy and exploitative innovation and the negative relationship between policy and exploratory innovation. Â© 2022</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1016/j.techfore.2022.121519</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210876</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">First offshore US wind farm installs turbine foundation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A joint venture of contractors Weeks Marine and Manson Construction completed the first installation for the five-turbine demonstration project that is set to generate power by late 2016. Abigail Ross Hopper, director of the US Interior Department's Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, termed the $290-million Block Island pilot project as the country's first offshore wind farm and a major achievement in a sustainable offshore wind program for the Atlantic Coast. The project is expected to reduce electricity usage by 40%.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210892</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Development of Wind Energy and the Installed Wind Power Plants in Turkey</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">This article analyses the development of wind energy in Turkey-the number and capacity of installed wind generators, as well as the generated electricity. It was established that the number of wind power plants is 99 with a total installed capacity of 3933 MW, and the amount of electricity produced by wind power plants is 17909.3 GWh/year. Turkey has been shown to have great potential for developing electricity generation from offshore wind farms. The increase in the number of offshore wind turbines in the coming years is expected to increase the relative share of renewable sources in the country's energy mix, to contribute to the technological and industrial development of the regions, to produce electricity from renewable and environmentally friendly sources and to reduce the country's energy dependence. It has been established that there are appropriate conditions in Turkey for the development of wind energy and preconditions have been created for achieving the target for promoting the use of renewable energy sources by 2023. Â© 2020 The Authors, published by EDP Sciences.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1051/e3sconf/202020702013</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210203</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore risks in the spotlight</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The development of different software simulation tools by British Maritime Technology Ltd (BMT) to assess the risks associated with the rapid development of offshore wind farm sites is discussed. The strategic objective is to apply practical methodologies for wind farm planning, the evaluation of risks to shipping and the implementation of risk control measures. To address such concerns, the main procedures to be developed by the projects include the risks presented by a wind farm development in close proximity to existing navigation and scenarios of possible marine traffic growth. BMT has already developed a coastal zone marine traffic risk simulation tool DYMITRI which has been used in several large and complex assesments.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210218</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Overview strategy of wind farm in VSC-HVDC power transmission</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The VSC-HVDC system performance has the most competitive and new feasible solution for integration of high wind penetration at offshore sites for efficient power transmission. This paper presents an overview of various control strategy for power converters and the plan of services in VSC-HVDC transmission. For long distance transmission line, reactance limits the transfer capability of high voltage alternating current (HVAC) system. With the advancement of VSC-HVDC technology reactance can be smoothly controlled, hence transfer capability can be enhanced. VSC-HVDC (voltage source converter- high voltage direct current) technology also meets the challenges that are faced by 2-level and multilevel converters. Rapid developments in IGBT open new gate for controlled strategy in converters. Due to this there is a paradigms shift in interfacing renewable energy with electric power system. The real and reactive power can be controlled indepedently by using VSC-HVDC system and black start capability is restored by an AC grid. This paper lays focus on VSC-HVDC transmission technology with integration offshore wind power. It will help operating engineers, designers, and research scholars to focus on this work and decision making. VSC-HVDC transmissions are giving ease of belongingness to energy transition. Â© 2016 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/POWERI.2016.8077331</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210258</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Strengthening Methods of Power Grid Fed with Large-Scale Offshore Wind Power</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In the near future, offshore wind farms will become the most important local power sources in China's coastal provinces. In this context, this paper first summarizes the main problems faced by the power grid fed by large-scale offshore wind power. These problems include commutation failure of DC system, limitation of wind power absorption, insufficient voltage stability, continuous weakening of frequency stability, insufficient power angle stability and overtop short-circuit current in AC system. Therefore, this paper puts forward a series of strengthening methods, including adding equipment, changing grid structure and applying flexible HVDC transmission technology. Meanwhile, we also explain the applicable scenarios of different measures. Finally, a case study is carried out in Jiangsu power grid, and a scheme of building a three-terminal flexible HVDC transmission system across the Yangtze River is proposed. This scheme can strengthen the voltage stability and eliminate the undesirable limitation of wind power absorption in Suzhou. Â© 2021 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/POWERCON53785.2021.9697899</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210373</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A Crew Scheduling Model to Incrementally Optimize Workforce Assignments for Offshore Wind Farm Constructions</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In the literature, different authors attribute between 15\% to 30\% of a wind farm's costs to logistics during the installation, e.g., for vessels or personnel. Currently, there exist only a few approaches for crew scheduling in the offshore area. However, current approaches only satisfy subsets of the offshore construction area's specific terms and conditions. This article first presents a literature review to identify different constraints imposed on crew scheduling for offshore installations. Afterward, it presents a new Mixed-Integer Linear Model that satisfies these crew scheduling constraints and couples it with a scheduling approach using a Model Predictive Control scheme to include weather dynamics. The evaluation of this model shows reliable scheduling of persons/teams given weather-dependent operations. Compared to a conventionally assumed full staffing of vessels and the port, the model decreases the required crews by approximately 50\%. Moreover, the proposed model shows good runtime behavior, obtaining optimal solutions for realistic scenarios in under an hour.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en14216963</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210382</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Mooring system for atlantic generating station</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Public Service Electric and Gas Company of New Jersey Central Power and Light and Atlantic City Electric Company in joint ownership will construct the world's first major commercial floating nuclear generating station at a location approximately 3 miles east of Little Egg Inlet on the coast of New Jersey. The floating nuclear plant named Atlantic Generating Station, will consist of two units each capable of producing 1150 MW electric net and will be built by Offshore Power Systems at Jacksonville, Florida. (Figure 1). Â© Proceedings of the Annual Offshore Technology Conference 1974.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210400</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Resource use of wind farms in the german north sea-the example of alpha ventus and bard offshore i</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The German government aims to obtain at least 40 percent of its electricity from renewable sources by 2030. One of the central steps to reach this target is the construction of deep sea offshore wind farms. The paper presents a material intensity analysis of the offshore wind farms "Alpha Ventus" and "Bard Offshore I" under consideration of the grid connection. An additional onshore scenario is considered for comparison. The results show that offshore wind farms have higher resource consumption than onshore farms. In general, and in respect to the resource use of other energy systems, both can be tagged as resource efficient. Â© 2013 by the authors; licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/resources2040504</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210444</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Modeling the tetraspar floating offshore wind turbine foundation as a flexible structure in orcaflex and openfast</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Floating offshore wind turbine technology has seen an increasing and continuous development in recent years. When designing the floating platforms, both experimental and numerical tools are applied, with the latter often using time-domain solvers based on hydro-load estimation from a Morison approach or a boundary element method. Commercial software packages such as OrcaFlex, or open-source software such as OpenFAST, are often used where the floater is modeled as a rigid six degree-of-freedom body with loads applied at the center of gravity. However, for final structural design, it is necessary to have information on the distribution of loads over the entire body and to know local internal loads in each component. This paper uses the TetraSpar floating offshore wind turbine design as a case study to examine new modeling approaches in OrcaFlex and OpenFAST that provide this information. The study proves the possibility of applying the approach and the extraction of internal loads, while also presenting an initial code-to-code verification between OrcaFlex and OpenFAST. As can be expected, comparing the flexible model to a rigid-body model proves how motion and loads are affected by the flexibility of the structure. OrcaFlex and OpenFAST generally agree, but there are some differences in results due to different modeling approaches. Since no experimental data are available in the study, this paper only forms a baseline for future studies but still proves and describes the possibilities of the approach and codes. Â© 2021 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en14237866</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210451</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">VC4OWT: MATLAB interface for vibration control of offshore wind turbine</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In this study, a new graphical user interface (GUI), VC4OWT, is developed to evaluate the structural response of National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) 5-MW offshore wind turbine (OWT) subjected to seismic excitations. Finite element model of OWT has been modelled and analyzed using the Opensees simulation platform. Performances of structure with and without friction damper considering soil-structure interaction (SSI) have been studied to reduce the effects of seismic load. The diagonal-bracing friction damper system is added at platform for the vibration purpose. The obtained outputs demonstrate that VC4OWT is a functional and efficient software to simulate and study the vibration control of OWT. Â© Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd. 2019.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1007/978-981-13-2306-5_75</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210579</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Data-driven Wake Modelling for Reduced Uncertainties in short-term Possible Power Estimation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">One of the ancillary services the wind farms are required to provide to the system operators is reserve power, which is achieved by down-regulating the wind farm from its possible power. In order to estimate the reserves, the possible power needs to be calculated by correcting the reduced wake effects behind the down-regulated turbines. The most recent grid codes dictate the quality of the possible power at the wind farm level to be assessed within 1-min intervals for offshore wind power plants. Therefore, the necessity of a fast and reliable wake model is more prominent than ever. Here we investigate the performance of two engineering wake models with 1-sec resolution SCADA data on three different offshore wind farms, given the quantified input uncertainty. The preliminary results show that, even wind farm specific training of the model parameters might fail to comply with the strict criteria stated in the grid codes, especially for the layouts with significant wake losses. In order to tackle the inadequacy of the engineering wake models to capture some of the dynamics in the wind farm flow due to the embedded assumptions, purely data-driven techniques are evaluated. The flexibility of such an on-line model enables 'site-turbine-time-specific' modelling, in which the parameters are defined per turbine and updated with each time-step in a specific wind farm. Â© Published under licence by IOP Publishing Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1088/1742-6596/1037/7/072002</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210806</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Study on Operation Strategy of System Connected to Large Scale Offshore Wind Power</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">With the development of China's offshore wind power, the peak shaving and operation of the power system in the eastern region, which are in a high proportion of power receiving and huge peak shaving demand for local power supply, face greater challenges. In the paper, on the basis of the quantitative analysis of the regulation characteristics of "source-grid-load", a "source-grid-load" coordinated operation strategy that takes into account environmental costs is proposed. It can improve the system's absorptive capacity and at the same time, it can cut the total operating cost of the system and improve the utilization of offshore wind power. In this way, the use of traditional fossil energy and its impact on the environment can be reduced. Taking the grid, as is scheduled in 2030, of a regional power grid as an example, the production and operation simulation and comparative analysis were carried out on the statistics before and after the coordinated operation of "source-grid-load". The results verified the effectiveness of the proposed control strategy. Â© 2019 IEEE.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1109/ICPEA.2019.8818508</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210844</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Analysis of Ice Induced Vibration Fatigue Life of Single-Pile Offshore Wind Turbine Foundation</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">In order to analyze the impact of the anti-icing cone on the wind turbine foundation, based on the safe life design theory, the evaluation method of the ice-induced fatigue life of wind turbine foundation is clarified, and the content and process of the ice vibration fatigue analysis of offshore wind turbine foundation are established. Using ANSYS numerical simulation, the ice vibration fatigue damage and life of the vertical and ice-breaking cone wind turbine foundation structures are calculated and analyzed. The results show that the cone can effectively improve the ice vibration fatigue life of the single-pile wind turbine foundation. Â© 2022 by Aussino Academic Publishing House.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210852</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Potential commercial leasing for wind power on the outer continental shelf (OCS) Offshore Maine; Request for interest</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The purpose of this public notice is to describe the proposal submitted to BOEM by Statoil North America (Statoil NA) to acquire an OCS wind lease; solicit public input regarding the proposal, its potential environmental consequences, and the use of the area in which the proposed project would be located; and solicit submissions of indications of competitive interest for a commercial lease for wind energy development on the OCS off the coast of Maine for the area identified in this notice. On 10/12/2011, BOEM received an unsolicited request from Statoil NA for a commercial wind lease on the OCS offshore Maine. Statoil NA's proposed project, Hywind Maine, would consist of four 3-Mw wind turbine generators configured for a total of 12-Mw in water depths > 100 m off the coast of Maine. The objective of the proposed Hywind Maine Project is to demonstrate the commercial potential of the existing floating offshore Hywind technology, while responding to a corresponding Request for Proposals issued by the Maine Public Utilities Commission.</style></abstract><urls/></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210847</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Design and Implementation of the Instrumentation and Sensor System for testing of a sub modelled 10 MW offshore superconducting wind turbine.</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">The large head mass of an offshore wind turbine can be reduced by using superconducting technology. As a proof of concept, a superconducting 10 MW wind turbine for offshore application is investigated under the SUPRAPOWER project funded by EU-FP7. SC coils were developed using MgB2 tapes and cooled to 20 K by a two stage Gifford McMahon cryocooler in a modular rotating cryostat. To study the coil performance and to measure and control the sub model, a LABVIEW based instrumentation system is developed. To measure the temperature distribution in a rotating cryostat, an optical based sensing system is designed and introduced. The effect of rotation on an optical based sensing system is studied. In this paper, the instrumentation along with the thermal characteristics and validation of the optical sensing system for rotating machines and its installation techniques will be reported. Â© 2019 Published under licence by IOP Publishing Ltd.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.1088/1757-899X/502/1/012169</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="Articles_137584_20240910.enl">Articles_137584_20240910.enl</database><source-app version="17.7" name="EndNote">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96210726</rec-number><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors/><titles><title><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">A New Framework for Assessment of Offshore Wind Farm Location</style></title></titles><abstract><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">Offshore wind energy has become a hot spot in new-energy development due to its abundant reserves, long power generation time, high unit capacity and low land occupation. In response to the current situation whereby wind energy, and natural and human factors have not been taken into account in the selection of sites for offshore wind-energy-resource development in the traditional ``21st Century Maritime Silk Road{'' region, this paper intends to establish a new risk assessment framework that comprehensively considers the influence of wind resources, the natural environment, and the geopolitical and humanistic environment. The rationality of the new index system and weight determination methods are separately investigated. Some interesting results are obtained by comparing the new framework with traditional frameworks. The results show that the Persian Gulf, the Timor Sea in northern Australia, and the northern part of Sri Lanka in southern India are rich in wind-energy resources and have a low overall risk, making them recommended sites. In addition, unlike the results of previous studies, this paper does not recommend the Somali Sea as a priority area for wind-energy siting due to its high geographic humanity risks.</style></abstract><urls/><electronic-resource-num><style size="100%" font="default" face="normal">10.3390/en15186758</style></electronic-resource-num></record></records></xml>